<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:10:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>you don&#39;t know squat if you don&#39;t squat</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:10:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article 2 of the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series is brought to you by legs day. You don&amp;rsquo;t know squat, if you don&amp;rsquo;t squat! This article takes a step into my day, my workout, and my nutrition. Click to read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rise-and-grind-it-s-legs-day-dec-6&#34;&gt;rise and grind, it&amp;rsquo;s legs day! - Dec 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, today was an early start. I woke up at about 5:10am for a 6am shift start. I arrived into the office and was able to grind out a lot of logistics for various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on. And, it turns out I will be heading to Las Vegas in a MONTH for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ces.tech/&#34;&gt;Consumer Electronics Show (CES)&lt;/a&gt;! Tonight, I have a squat workout scheduled and as you may or may not know, I have a love-hate relationship with squats. While I think squats are key to having a solid and functional fitness foundation, form is critical to being able to move a lot of weight. I am still trying to perfect my squat form, and it&amp;rsquo;s been challenging returning to a &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; squat from a lower-back injury. Ever since sustaining the initial injury, my squats have taken a toll in terms of how much weight I can actually tollerate. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that 5/3/1 will help me take a few steps back, adjust my form, my breathing, and my technique, and ultimately allow me to get stronger. I thing the higher-volume nature of &amp;ldquo;Boring but Big&amp;rdquo; is just what I need to get confident and comfortable with performing the squatting movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trying-so-hard-to-hit-those-macros&#34;&gt;trying so hard to hit those macros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk nutrition for a little bit. I mentioned yesterday how difficult it&amp;rsquo;s been for me to hit my macros (155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats), lately. If you had asked me a year ago, I&amp;rsquo;d be able to hit those numbers at 3PM if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t careful. So I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s up. My appetite has disappeared! Tracking my food has seemed to help, because no matter what I want to eat, it fits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gluten-free diet has been really great so far in terms of how I feel and how I&amp;rsquo;ve been digesting. I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed too many changes with my skin, but it&amp;rsquo;s only been a few days, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure it takes time. The downfall with being gluten-free is that I feel so limited with what I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; eat. It&amp;rsquo;s a choice to eat this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m doing it because I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have a greater health benefit long-term. I just think I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to find other carbohydrates that are gluten-free and low in sugar (&lt;em&gt;good luck&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some foods that are becoming staples to my diet right now are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chex/GF cereal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweet Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean ground beef (90-96% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whey Protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corn tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60% dark chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; salad mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pickles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to mix it up and have a bit more variety, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be limited when it comes to staying gluten-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-and-feeling-under-the-weather-dec-7-and-8&#34;&gt;health and feeling &amp;ldquo;under the weather&amp;rdquo; - Dec 7 and 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last article I spoke a lot about how &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; this routine was going to be. Unfortunately, that was before I got sick. So these past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling off a headcold, therefore, I didn&amp;rsquo;t train on Wednesday or Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I will get back to the gym on Friday for Bench Press, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to depend on how I feel and how much food I&amp;rsquo;m eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=Life always throws a monkey-wrench. Just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans. @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;Life always throws a monkey-wrench, and just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to just go with it, and make the most of what you set out to do. I want to nip this cold in the bud, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing everything I can to take care of myself and make a 80-90% recovery before going back to the gym. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about being &amp;ldquo;tough&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo; or whatever when it comes to training while sick. I personally think that it&amp;rsquo;s dumb to train when you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling well. Your mind will be focused on how terrible you feel rather than focusing on perfecting your form. Rest up, get over the cold or illness, and the gym will be there when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return.
The other part of training while sick is that your body is already trying to &amp;ldquo;fight&amp;rdquo; off the illness. When you throw in additional stressors, such as lack of sleep, lifting, etc., it makes it difficult for your body to get rid of it. I think this is why people end up with these &amp;ldquo;lingering&amp;rdquo; colds for weeks and months. They don&amp;rsquo;t give their bodies&amp;rsquo; the breaks they need in order to see full recovery. So, do yourself a favor and sleep!
For me, I notice the onset of an illness when I don&amp;rsquo;t get 7-8 hours of sleep consistently, and I am working 10+ hour days, and working out, and doing too much. So the illness is an alarm telling me &amp;ldquo;hey! you need to take a break!&amp;rdquo; So tonight&amp;rsquo;s chest workout is still tentative. It&amp;rsquo;s about 9:30am here, and I have many hours to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m going to train tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut this article off here, but thank you, if you have read this far, and I will be back with another article on Day 3 of 5/3/1, whether that is tonight or this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question or comment? Find me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a 10-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:54:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we overlook the cool-down routine as much as our warm-up routine. I think it has something to do with wanting to get to the exciting part of the workout and both warm-ups and cool-downs are &amp;ldquo;boring.&amp;rdquo; I used to think that these routines were a waste of time, but that was before I knew just how much benefit they provide the body. This article explains a quick, ten-minute recovery routine that you can do practically anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you will need the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopwatch or Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair or something about 2-feet off the ground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a circuit of four different exercises that are best performed post-workout or at a time when you want to &amp;ldquo;relax.&amp;rdquo; They are taken from the exercises recommended by Maraynn Berry&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/video/5-simple-exercises-to-eliminate-neck-pain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Simple Exercises to Eliminate Neck Pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be experiencing neck pain in order to do these exercises! I find that this condensed version allows my body to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;relax&amp;rdquo; especially after a heavy lifting session. This routine is especially beneficial for desk jockies because it promotes proper posture from the neck, through the shoulders, down to the hips and adductors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each exercise in this routine, you will hold the position for two minutes. There are five exercises total, therefore, ten-minutes of &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; time for this routine. I recommend you read through the exercise, and then give them a try! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-1-u-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 1:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Back:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay on the floor with your legs propped up on a chair or object 2-feet tall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your legs should be at a 90-degree angle to your hips. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-2-u-static-scapular-extension&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 2:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Scapular Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start on all fours, ensuring that your wrists are directly under your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk your hands about 6-inches in front of the starting position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift your hips forward so that your weight and shoulders are over your wrists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your elbows straight and allow your shoulder blades to sink down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your head hang. Release any tension in your neck and mouth. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;It will be challenging, but try to hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; While it seems counter-intuitive to hold this position, since we spend most of our day in a slouched over position, this exercise moves the scapula into extension, promoting realignment to the shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-3-u-repeat-exercise-1-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 3:&lt;/u&gt;  Repeat Exercise 1, Static Back.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-4-u-wall-hold&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 4:&lt;/u&gt;  Wall Hold:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit on the floor with your back and head against a wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull your shoulder blades together and down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest your legs straight out in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flex your quads. Flex your feet towards your body. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-5-u-static-adductor-frog&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 5:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Adductor (Frog):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start in a seated position with the bottoms of your feet touching each other (a.k.a. butterfly position). Make sure that your feet are aligned with the center of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lie back and relax every muscle in your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your arms at a 45-degree angle to your sides with your palms facing up. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this routine a try after your next workout or before bed. After a week of doing this routine, it&amp;rsquo;ll become second-nature and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it helps with recovery and &amp;ldquo;resets&amp;rdquo; your posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does your cool-down routine look like? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Recover with this easy, 10-minute routine www.queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; with your tips and tricks for improving recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources-for-prehab-rehab-and-recovery&#34;&gt;Additional Resources for Prehab, Rehab, and Recovery:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/au/learn/banish-pain-permanently-basic-drills-to-repair-your-posture?page=0,0&#34;&gt;Banish Pain Permanently by Maryann Berry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uprightposturefitness.com/sitting-floor-exercise/&#34;&gt;Sitting Floor Exercise by Upright Posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/egoscue-method/&#34;&gt;Egoscue Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McKenzie Method / MDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My brain is a continuum of fitnessesque thoughts; I tend to think a lot about how to improve my life through fitness, nutrition, recovery, and lifestyle changes. In the queenflex blog you will find all the random and insightful fitness ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to jot down. This collection of articles is based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve read and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned through trial-and-error. So go ahead, read some articles, drop a comment (or two), and work with me to become the person you&amp;rsquo;ve dreamt of being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-fun-facts-about-this-blog&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some fun facts about this blog:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Born in Fall 2015 with the aim to promote fitness, motivation, and healthy lifestyles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coded and maintained in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sublimetext.com/2&#34;&gt;sublime text 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the articles are written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesigned multiple times using various blogger templates before migrating to Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fit links</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This page serves as a repertoir of the top-knotch fitness and health websites approved by the queen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Add my favorite fitness site to queenflex.com&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; to have your favorite fitness site added to the queen&amp;rsquo;s list. Shoutout to those who made the cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strength-standards&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how your lifts stack up others at the same height, weight, and gender? Well Strength Standards has all this figured out! Just type in your currrent stats, your best &lt;em&gt;weight x reps&lt;/em&gt; for the big 4 (bench, squat, deadlift, press), and Strength Standards will tell you how you compare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website can also be used to generate progressions. If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck in a plateau with any of your lifts, you can generate progressions for popular lifting programs (5/3/1, Stronglifts, Cube Method, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Strength Standards is a great tool for benchmarking your current strength relative to your current size. The only downfall is you cannot &amp;ldquo;log&amp;rdquo; your progress with Strength Standards. Because of this, I recommend taking a look at the Strong App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;www.strengthstandards.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strong-app-for-ios&#34;&gt;Strong (App for iOS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Track your progress on any lift with this app for iOS. I have been using this app since Jan 2016, and let me tell you, it beats out the pencil-paper method by a million. (And I was an avid user of notebooks and training templates throughout the years.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an iDevice, switching to Strong provides you the simplicity of a notebook without the complexity and hassle of determining how much weight, how many sets/reps, and what you need to do in order to achieve progressive overload. You can see the exact weight and reps you did previously for each exercise, and that&amp;rsquo;s something that you cannot do with a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong allows you to create custom workout routines and exercises and also provides a built-in set timer, warm-up calculator, and plate calculator. You can mark sets as &amp;ldquo;warm-up&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;drop-set&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;failure&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s also easy to see progress over time, because each completed routine is added to the master calendar and PR&amp;rsquo;s are recorded into charts for each exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong stores all your data in the cloud and has the option to integrate with Facebook. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s provided me with a great value for the price. Note, I am not endorsed to say anything positive about Strong. I have had such a great experience with the app, and it&amp;rsquo;s constantly receiving updates (buy the full version with upgrades in perpetuity!) by their development team. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit @strongapp I just visited http://strongapp.io via queenflex.com. What an awesome fitness tracking app!&#34;&gt;Have a look at it, and let me know what you think!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strongapp.io&#34;&gt;strongapp.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;muscle-for-life-michael-matthews&#34;&gt;Muscle For Life / Michael Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Matthews has written multiple books and articles around fitness, bodybuilding, and strength training. Notorious for his best-selling books, &amp;ldquo;Bigger Leaner Stronger&amp;rdquo; (for men) and &amp;ldquo;Thinner Leaner Stronger&amp;rdquo; (for women), Matthews provides scientific evidence alongside his recommendations while explaining the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; of nutrition and training in language anyone can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about him, his training philosophies, and programs on his website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muscleforlife.com&#34;&gt;www.muscleforlife.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;last updated 2016-11-25&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-rm progression calculator</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 15:20:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/calculator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever struggle to figure out how much weight you should use per set during a 1-rep-max test?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, look no further! Here&amp;rsquo;s a calculator that you can use to determine how much weight you should use for each of your warm-up and working sets in order to reach your target 1RM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input your target 1RM weight into the &amp;ldquo;target 1RM weight&amp;rdquo; field as well as the set number. The calculator will output the number of reps and respective weight you should hit for the given set. All calculations are based on the recommendations from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/training/how-to-warm-up-for-a-one-rep-max&#34;&gt;this T-Nation article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tool courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.com&#34;&gt;queenflex.com&lt;/a&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://jscalc.io&#34;&gt;jscalc.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://jscalc.io/embed/aQMGRFvVJOGJW6Iq?autofocus=1&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; overflow:&#34;hidden&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>charlie mike: continue mission</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/charlie-mike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 17:54:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/charlie-mike/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Charlie Mike. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a terrible name for a child. It&amp;rsquo;s actually the name of a terribly difficult workout program by Ashley Horner and Bodybuilding.com. You&amp;rsquo;re probably reading this because you&amp;rsquo;re curious about starting this program or you found my article posted on Facebook and figured you&amp;rsquo;d give it a read (thank you).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;program-overview&#34;&gt;program overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the military, &amp;ldquo;Charlie Mike&amp;rdquo; is a command meaning &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Continue Mission.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; Each of Horner&amp;rsquo;s workouts is a mini &amp;ldquo;mission&amp;rdquo; that you have to overcome. The program is 6-weeks long and each week has a theme: week 1 is &amp;ldquo;Try&amp;rdquo;; week 2 is &amp;ldquo;Believe&amp;rdquo;; week 3 is &amp;ldquo;Commit&amp;rdquo;; week 4 is &amp;ldquo;Conquer&amp;rdquo;; week 5 is &amp;ldquo;Earn It&amp;rdquo;; week 6 is &amp;ldquo;Prove it&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t let these themes fool you though. The workouts are tough from the very beginning! &amp;ldquo;Try&amp;rdquo; will certainly become a motif on day 1 of the program. (This is especially true if you&amp;rsquo;re coming from a background of low-intensity work). You may even get a few stares from your average gym-goers because they&amp;rsquo;re thinking, &amp;ldquo;dang, what kind of workout is (s)he doing?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;30&#34; src=&#34;http://www.bodybuilding.com/images/2016/february/Charlie_Mike-NLA-FINAL-desktop-logo.png&#34; width=&#34;30%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on the fence about doing this program, you should stop thinking about doing it and just dive in. The more you ponder whether or not this routine is for you, the more you will talk yourself out of it. Don&amp;rsquo;t over-analyze the routine. I&amp;rsquo;ll simplify it for you here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Each routine follows a similar format: 1 compound exercise followed by 1-2 high-intensity interval circuits and some running/rowing sprinkled in.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s the best of both worlds: you get to work your strength while becoming more agile. For me, this program was such a good choice for the summertime because there&amp;rsquo;s something so rewarding about working until you&amp;rsquo;re about to die during the summer months. (Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because when you walk out of the gym as a sweaty mess, you&amp;rsquo;re greeted by the summer sun and all the happy feelings of summer. Plus, there&amp;rsquo;s always the opportunity to hang poolside with a cold one.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-i-m-a-charlie-mike-fan&#34;&gt;Why I&amp;rsquo;m a Charlie Mike Fan&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This program makes you feel like you&amp;rsquo;re training for something that matters.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to this program, I was stuck in a training rut. I was hitting my typical compound lifts with some accessory work thrown in here and there. While my lifts were progressing, I just felt stale. Training wasn&amp;rsquo;t overly enjoyable because I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was working towards any specific goal. This program provides everything you need in order to feel like you&amp;rsquo;re achieving something ridiculously awesome each training day. Because the program is named after a military command, it made me appreciate those who train this hard all the time in order to protect our nation and our freedom.
The program begins with about a week’s worth of finding your 1-rep-max (1RM) for the following compound lifts: back squat, front squat, deadlift, bench press, and push press. I&amp;rsquo;ve developed a calculator to help you determine the number of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.queenflex.com/p/one-rep-max-1rm-warm-up-calculator.html&#34;&gt;reps per set for a 1RM test&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the 1RM test, you&amp;rsquo;ll jump right into a few cardio circuits. Here&amp;rsquo;s an example of what a typical day looks like (strength + conditioning):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-GETfCoTJcUA/V7DhHSqYpcI/AAAAAAAABDk/0y4HTrZEpagaqRoE7ZXHVo__7IwVWgWCgCLcB/s1600/charlie-mike-example-day16.png&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Charlie Mike Day 16 from Bodybuilding.com&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of rest, Horner does a great job at emphasizing proper rest. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like I was over-trained at all during this program; however, I did have to modify some of the routines to accommodate my schedule. After each conditioning circuit, you&amp;rsquo;re told to take 5-10 minutes of rest, which I found to be plenty of time to both recover and to get ready for the next circuit. Some days I needed closer to 10 minutes of rest, while other days I was ready to go in 5. Just be sure to time yourself because time tends to move quickly when you&amp;rsquo;re in &amp;ldquo;rest&amp;rdquo; mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bonus to this program is that there is a dedicated Charlie Mike App to help track your workouts! It&amp;rsquo;s not an overly complex app, and you can&amp;rsquo;t log data in it; however, it is much better than printing the PDFs off of Bodybuidling.com or trying to view the exercises on the mobile website. I especially liked not having to plan out any routines for the 6-week period. Each day was a different set of exercises, all of which proved to be difficult in their own ways.
Nothing is perfect, that includes Charlie Mike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A downfall to this program is the lack of definitive nutrition plan. I think that nutrition is a major part of any training program; however, Horner did not specify what the macronutrient amounts or percentages should be during this program. This is left to you to figure out. She does recommend eating a variety of whole, nutrient-dense foods, which is the standard recommendation in any program. I ate pretty liberally during this program and didn&amp;rsquo;t follow a specific meal plan. Right now though, I am following your typical principles of IIFYM (if it fits your macros) and am eating roughly 40-40-20 (protein-carbs-fat). If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in dialing in your nutrition, this may not be the exact program for you. I&amp;rsquo;d recommend finding a nutrition program or coach to help you figure out your numbers. Nutrition can make or break your performance, so to be successful on this program, you will want to ensure that you&amp;rsquo;re eating enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-3f3LP2LeNqk/V7DHJIwqgRI/AAAAAAAABCs/CgCnjVp4QBMrtLKNQ3Eyu-vO7sOgT0UEQCLcB/s1600/it-doesnt-get-easier-you-get-better.png&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;center&gt; Week 1 was tough. &lt;em&gt;But so was Week 6.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My body was just more adapted to handle the workouts over time.
Charlie Mike was not a breeze. It was just as tough on week 6 as it was on week 1. I found that each workout was progressively more difficult even with an increased work capacity. I was never bored with these routines because once I was warmed up and into my first cardio circuit, the feeling was analogous to a &amp;ldquo;runner&amp;rsquo;s high.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve read this far and still aren&amp;rsquo;t convinced this workout is for you, then okay, it&amp;rsquo;s probably not. So for that reason alone, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of the reasons why you &lt;u&gt;shouldn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/u&gt; try Charlie Mike:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want an easy workout routine for a deload or relaxation training cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You want to focus on strength or hypertrophy or cardio, separately.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t want to sweat during your workout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re starting a cutting diet cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re afraid to step out of your comfort zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re injured. (Seriously, rest up and get better before exercising!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t want to look like a crazy at your globo-gym.*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Note this isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete list of why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t give this a try. Personally, I think if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this far and are on the fence about trying it, you&amp;rsquo;re just looking for excuses. (Lame)
Final Thoughts and Program Rating&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just like Rotten Tomatoes rates movies, here are my ratings for Charlie Mike in the categories of program exercises, schedule, nutrition, recovery, and overall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;exercises&lt;/strong&gt;  ★  ★  ★  ★  ★  &lt;br&gt;
Charlie Mike has a variety of exercises including your fundamental compound lifts as well as olympic lifts: thrusters, cleans, clean &amp;amp; jerks. Strength and conditioning is included in every workout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;schedule&lt;/strong&gt; ★  ★  ★  ★ &lt;br&gt;
The schedule was pretty easy to follow. Each workout follows the same structure: strength + conditioning circuits. Days can be interchanged as needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;nutrition&lt;/strong&gt; ★  ★  &lt;br&gt;
This program does not provide a specific nutrition program with complete macronutrients or diet recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;recovery&lt;/strong&gt; ★  ★  ★  ★ &lt;br&gt;
There is plenty of recovery time between exercises and between workout days. Like schedule, workouts can be rearranged to accommodate your needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;overall&lt;/strong&gt; ★  ★  ★  ★ &lt;br&gt;
Overall this routine was one of the best I&amp;rsquo;ve completed from Bodybuilding.com. I highly recommend trying it if your current routine is stale, or if you&amp;rsquo;re looking to pump up the intensity in your workouts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After 6-weeks of Charlie Mike, all of my compound lifts have increased in weight. My endurance and my performance have also improved significantly. Charlie Mike was a mentally and physically challenging program, which upon completion made me realize that I’m a lot stronger than I thought I was. My mission was successfully completed. Now it’s your turn. &lt;em&gt;Are you up for the challenge?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have further questions about Charlie Mike? Tweet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things you should know about fitness in 2016</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 18:00:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hpnB2MhMJMI/V3Pec6UCEMI/AAAAAAAAA-o/xYhk-6vhy-sQ4PytNIg3_y_d1YzXw8uYwCLcB/s1600/five-tips-to-reach-your-fitness-goals.png&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Here it is, half-way through 2016. Have you stuck to your New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions? Have you lost the 10 pounds you were planning to lose in January? Maybe the summer weather came sooner than you had planned. Well fret no more; here are five things you should know about achieving your fitness goals as we head into the second half of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-understand-the-bigger-picture&#34;&gt;1) Understand the bigger picture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why does fitness matter to you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to fit into particular clothes? Do you use gym-time as a method to reduce stress? Do you want to look a certain way? Do you want to live a healthy and happy life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your reason may be, you need to be honest with yourself and define the bigger picture. While fitness magazines and websites make healthy living seem so amazing and glamorous, you have to know your why. Not their why or my why, yours. After all, fitness and healthy living is an investment to yourself, so you might as well make it about you and the things that you want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, sit down and ask yourself &lt;strong&gt;WHY?&lt;/strong&gt;. Why does fitness and health matter to me? And once you ask yourself &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; once, go ahead and ask yourself three to four more times. By the fifth &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo;, you should have a pretty good understanding of the bigger picture. Once you know the bigger picture, you can decompose your end goal into a smaller subset of goals. Think of these mini-goals as stepping-stones that will help you get closer to your end goal. This is the most important tip to achieving your fitness goals, so be sure to spend some time really considering what your aspirations are and how you can break those larger goals down into smaller milestones. Once you complete this activity, you will have a better understanding of how to get to where you want to be and can spend time working at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-eat-according-to-your-daily-plans&#34;&gt;2) Eat according to your daily plans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to preface this point with the idea of being realistic and developing a healthy mindset around food and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is critical that you eat enough food for what you&amp;rsquo;re doing during the day. For example, if you are sitting and watching TV, you will not need as much food versus hitting a workout consisting of heavy squats and deadlifts. So on days you plan to workout longer than an hour or WOD for more than twenty minutes, it&amp;rsquo;s important you fuel your body so that it can perform optimally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few fundamental ideas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going through a weight loss cycle, you need to eat fewer calories than your body burns throughout a day. [AKA Caloric Deficit]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to put on weight, you need to eat more calories than your body burns throughout a day. [AKA Caloric Surplus]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with that said, you must also realize that you can&amp;rsquo;t always spend every day in a Caloric Deficit or a Caloric Surplus; it is important that you take breaks from dieting and bulking and spend time maintaining. Metabolism is meant to be dynamic, so incorporating days or periods of time where you eat more and then less, is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I like to do is spend 6-10 weeks at a Caloric Deficit to lose some weight, and then slowly reverse diet out of the deficit to a maintenance calorie level. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll spend 3-4 months in a caloric surplus to promote muscle growth. I&amp;rsquo;ll repeat this cycle until I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with how my figure looks and according to how I feel from a health standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-find-foods-you-like-incorporate-them-into-your-meals&#34;&gt;3) Find foods you like &amp;amp; incorporate them into your meals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eat foods you like. It sounds simple, but if you force yourself to eat “healthy” foods that you don’t like, then it’s going to be a rough battle for you to maintain. Now don’t get me wrong, this point is NOT about eating chicken wings and mac and cheese. (We both know you like those foods; however, a diet of chicken wings and mac and cheese isn’t overly healthy in the long run).  A healthy lifestyle includes a balanced diet of carbohydrates (vegetables, starches, sugars), fats (oils, butters), and proteins (meat, dairy). Try to incorporate as many vegetables and meats that you enjoy eating into your diet. This will make it easier to commit to fitness over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “healthy foods&amp;rdquo; is a slight misconception because what one person thinks is healthy, another person may disagree. I will let you decide what you think is healthy for you; however, a tip that I like to use when picking out food is whether or not the food has been processed (unhealthy), grown on a farm (healthy), or hunted (healthy). That’s not to say that all process foods are created equal: old fashioned oats are different than Cheetos, for example. Use your best judgment when preparing your meals. It’s okay to have most foods in moderation! It’s all about balance and consistency and what contributes to making you feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-train-smarter-and-harder&#34;&gt;4) Train Smarter and Harder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that always is brought up in the fitness world is training. Today’s thought is that &lt;em&gt;“less is more”&lt;/em&gt; and short workouts are better than longer workouts. My response to that is that it depends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a short workout without any intensity, such as going for a 10 minute walk, that is a lot different than completing a high-intensity interval workout for 10 minutes. While both are 10 minutes, there are studies that high-intensity interval training (HIIT) promotes more fat loss in 10 minutes versus 45-60 minutes of low-intensity training, such as walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, I think walking is one of the most important exercises one could do to promote long-term health and wellness; however, if your goal is fat loss (who doesn’t want to lose fat), try to plan your workouts around increased intensity and heavier weights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training smarter also includes choosing exercises that you enjoy doing and a schedule that complements your lifestyle. You shouldn’t be “living to train”; you should be “training to live.” If your routine isn’t one you can stick to, then you won’t be enjoying your time training nor will you have a high likelihood of sticking to the routine over time. Consistency is a huge part of fitness, so the more you can stick to the schedule, the better chance you have of reaching your health goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must challenge yourself if you want to make any progress. For example, if you continuously choose the same weight for the same number of sets and reps, you will not progress to higher weights. Be reasonable, and increase the weight as the exercise becomes easier. Make small adjustments and over time you will see major improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-own-the-decisions-that-you-make-and-be-okay-with-the-outcomes&#34;&gt;5) Own the decisions that you make and be okay with the outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wise person once told me &lt;em&gt;“you may not be where you want to be, but you’re where you should be.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be as strong or fast or as aesthetic as you may want to be, but based on your current actions, you are where you should be. Keep going; be consistent; and work towards being better each day. You won’t be perfect, but having peace with yourself will go a long ways. You have to be your own advocate; no one else can do that for you. Give yourself a realistic amount of time to reach your goals and be honest with yourself about the decisions you make to reach them. 80% of the results come from 20% of the effort. As mentioned before, train smarter and harder and reap the benefits of putting in the work to get to where you want to be. Reassess your progress regularly (weekly, monthly, etc) so that you have a feel for when expectations and milestones should be met. You have complete control of your life, so own the work that you do; own how you speak to yourself; and own the results of your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it: the five things you should know about fitness as we head into Q3 of 2016. And if this article was &amp;ldquo;TL;DR&amp;rdquo;, I encourage you to scroll up and at least read each of the 5 bullet points. Go ahead and do some soul-searching. Find out the bigger picture, your bigger purpose. Eat according to your goals. Choose foods that you enjoy eating that are satiating and nutritious. Develop a smart training plan and go into each workout with a plan. Increase the weights on key lifts over time. And realize that you’re the driver to your destination. Own every decision that you make – the good and the bad. Be okay with who you are and what you stand for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try out these tips and let me know how you fare. Get at it! &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my perspective on daily undulating periodization (dup)</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/daily-undulating-periodization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 18:30:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/daily-undulating-periodization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily Undulating Periodization (DUP) is all the rage these days. For a &amp;ldquo;program hopper&amp;rdquo; like myself, I find that DUP is a great way to feel like you&amp;rsquo;re doing something different each training session, without actually sacrificing progress, strength, or hypertrophy goals. The structure for DUP varies from person-to-person; however, since I am fairly new to this concept of training, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to shed some light and decompose the process of setting up a DUP training program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a few things to consider before writing your own DUP program: strength vs. hypertrophy, number of rest days, personal enjoyment exercises, etc. With that said, I have written this article to help you better assess DUP and whether or not it is the right programming style for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me introduce you to my little friend,&amp;rdquo; DUP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I jump right into my process for DUP programming, I&amp;rsquo;d like to briefly explain the principles behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmaxfitness.com/blog/daily-undulating-periodization/&#34;&gt;Daily Undulating Periodization.&lt;/a&gt; The concept is summarized in rather simple terms: for each training day, the routine includes exercises that are assigned a number of reps (rep scheme). The rep scheme changes each training session over the course of a training period (usually 4-6 weeks). Rep schemes are typically in one of three categories: strength (4-6 reps), hypertrophy (8-12 reps), endurance (15-20 reps). If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to become a more &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; athlete with your training, you may choose to have different rep schemes within the same training session (i.e. exercise 1 for 4 reps, exercise 2 for 8 reps, exercise 3 for 15 reps) or alternate rep schemes throughout a training week. In order to create a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muscleforlife.com/guide-to-muscle-hypertrophy-muscle-growth/&#34;&gt;progressive overload&lt;/a&gt; using DUP, you must increase volume your volume. Training volume can be increased a number of ways, but my two go-to methods are 1) using an as many reps as possible (AMRAP) set to determine whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re ready to increase the weight the next training week; or 2) increasing the number of sets each week within the training period (weight stays the same through the training period). Ok, so now that you have a brief understanding of DUP, I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide a simple methodology to create a DUP training program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming-for-daily-undulating-periodization&#34;&gt;programming for daily undulating periodization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;balance: the human body is a complex system, so training routines are meant to be simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-dup-routine-has-four-main-components&#34;&gt;a DUP routine has four main components:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental Exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rep Scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set Scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Period Length/Deload Schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fundamental-exercises&#34;&gt;fundamental exercises&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talk about &amp;ldquo;fundamental exercises&amp;rdquo;, what I really mean are your &amp;ldquo;main lifts&amp;rdquo; or the &lt;strong&gt;compound lifts&lt;/strong&gt; you want to include in your program: squats, bench, deadlifts, presses, and variations of these lifts. What I typically do is pick three compound lifts to work in a training period. For example, my current program includes front squats, barbell bench press, and rack pulls. The goal is to pick the exercises that you need to work. Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rep-scheme&#34;&gt;rep scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your exercises picked, you need to decide on
your rep scheme. As I stated in the introduction, you can either train
the same rep scheme for each exercise or have a separate rep scheme for each exercise and rotate them throughout a training week. My current program does the latter and 4, 6, and 10 reps each training day, one rep scheme per exercise (i.e. front squat for 4 reps, bench press for 6 reps, and rack pull for 10 reps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-scheme&#34;&gt;set scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s great, but how many sets should I be doing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that question depends on how you want to attack progressive overload. The idea is to have as few variables as possible, while still seeing a maximum result [check out this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4hourlife.com/2012/11/26/the-4-hour-chef-finding-the-minimum-effectiv%20e-dose-med-of-life/&#34;&gt;Minimum Effective Dose&lt;/a&gt;]. For the sake of keeping this article concise, I will only touch on two ways to determine your set scheme: keep the number of sets constant throughout the training cycle and increase the weight used for each exercise each week or increase the number of sets each week while keeping the weight used for each exercise constant. Right now my training period is four weeks long; the first week I do 2 sets; second week 3 sets; third week is 4 sets (3 sets + 1 set AMRAP); fourth week is 2 sets or deload. You can follow this pattern as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former method calls for increasing the weight by 5-10 lbs per exercise per week as long as you have achieved all of your sets and reps for each exercise. If you fail your bench press at 225 for 7 reps when you should have gotten 10, then you probably aren&amp;rsquo;t ready to increase the weight for that exercise. The goal is to make progress on your lifts without sacrificing form, mobility, and overall quality of the movement. A good way to test whether or not you are ready to move up in weight is to do an AMRAP set on your last set of the week prior to deload (i.e. for me, on my 3rd week, my fourth set is an AMRAP set). If you beat the number of reps than prescribed for &amp;gt;85% of your training days for each exercise, respectively, then you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go up in weight on the first week of the next training cycle. Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about training period length and deloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;period-length-deload-schedule&#34;&gt;period length/deload schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you need to decide how long you want your training period to last. A training period can last anywhere from 4-6 or 4-8 weeks, but ultimately depends on your preference, how your body feels with training, and the overall progress you&amp;rsquo;re making. For me, I like to take a deload week on the 4th week of the training cycle by dropping back to 2 sets as I do on week 1. This allows me to recover better and reduces the likelihood that I get burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also follow a 2-days on, 1 day off schedule where the off-day alternates between either a full day of rest/yoga day or an &amp;ldquo;accessory day&amp;rdquo; where I focus on 10-12 isolation movements to help with hypertrophy. For the accessory day, I follow the same set scheme as the week and keep the rep scheme constant at 10-15 reps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/double-stimulation-training&#34;&gt;interesting finding&lt;/a&gt; that says 24 hours after training a muscle group, you have greater ability to increase muscle mass by training it again during that timeframe. This is mainly why I use a 2-day on, 1 day off pattern rather than 5-day on, 2 day off training pattern. I also believe that since you&amp;rsquo;re undulating the rep scheme each day, you have the ability to recover slightly, but also stimulate the muscle enough to continue mass building. I am still playing around with how this works for me personally, but I&amp;rsquo;d be curious to know if any of you have had success with this concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-video&#34;&gt;reference video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still slightly confused? Have a look at this video for a visual demonstration of programming for DUP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;YOUTUBE-iframe-video&#34; data-thumbnail-src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/maE93vRZpAU/0.jpg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/maE93vRZpAU?feature=player_embedded&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;200%&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Consult with your doctor before starting a new exercise regime.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combat office slouch</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-being-such-a-slouch&#34;&gt;Stop being such a slouch!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and work a desk job, it is easy to turn into a slouched over mess. With all the hype out there about &amp;ldquo;sitting is the new smoking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prehab is rehab&amp;rdquo;, I have decided to create a list of the most realistic exercises that you can do at the office to help improve posture, mobility, and overall happiness. &lt;em&gt;And hopefully prevent you from looking like a stupid fool, rolling around on the floor next to your cubical.&lt;/em&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the advice I&amp;rsquo;m providing here is based off of my personal experience with chronic low back, hip, neck, and shoulder pain, and does not substitute or replace medical advice. These tricks have worked for me based on meeting with a physical therapist for my own mobility/stability issues; however, everybody is different, and it&amp;rsquo;s best to seek an opinion from your doctor prior to trying a rehab/stretch/strength program like the one I am about to outline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to working a full-time desk job, I was a college student. When people think college, they may think parties, alcohol, weight gain, and craziness; however, the reality of my college experience was hair-pulling, weight loss, walking everywhere, and craziness. Once I found myself sitting at the same desk for hours on end with little reason to move other than to get water or use the bathroom, I realized I was becoming a slouched over mess. [Cue the mobility issues, back and hip pain.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;neat&amp;rdquo; little thing about exercise: you can work out for an hour—maybe even two hours—a day, but if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/health-medicine/its-not-your-metabolism-its-your-neat-thats-stopping-your-fat-loss&#34;&gt;inactive for 8-15 hours a day, then exercise less effective&lt;/a&gt;. So why is that so “neat” you may ask? Well it has to do with &lt;strong&gt;N.E.A.T or non-exercise activity thermogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;, aka “what you do when you’re not exercising, which burns calories to keep you alive.” So if you put yourself into a lethargic, slumped over position all day long, and think you will have great mobility for your squat session that evening, well good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-prevent-becoming-an-immobile-mess-of-a-human-being&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I prevent becoming an immobile mess of a human being?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer:&lt;/u&gt; get off your butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer explained:&lt;/u&gt; Every 30-45 minutes, get up and perform a series of mobility/stability exercises to counterbalance the poor posture from sitting. Think back to eighth-grade science class where you learned about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/newtlaws/Lesson-4/Newton-s-Third-Law&#34;&gt;Newton’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;. (For you engineers out there, forgive me, this was a very recent topic for y’all). Newton’s Third Law states that for every action force there is a reaction force equal in magnitude and opposite in direction. For example, if you’re sitting in a slouched over position, inducing flexion on your spine, it’d be wise to get up every half hour and do some back bends to induce extension. Refer to the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://teachmeanatomy.info/wp-content/uploads/Terms-of-Movement-Flexion-and-Extension-CC-1024x815.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-15-minute-routine-to-combat-office-slouch&#34;&gt;A 15-minute routine to combat office slouch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a reason why people who live in a constant state of flexion throw their backs out when they pick up a basket of laundry; it’s because they’re inducing extension on a spine that has been molded into the flexion world. It’s time to teach our spines, and other body parts for that matter, what neutral looks like. To do this, I have developed a short list of five exercises that I think are the most effective for resetting the body and prehab for future injuries. You only need therabands/resistance bands to perform all the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you live in the world of &lt;u&gt;extension&lt;/u&gt;, you would probably benefit from &lt;u&gt;flexion&lt;/u&gt; exercises instead of exercises two and three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder W&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end keep your elbows by your sides. Contract your lats and pull the band apart forming a &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; with your arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_G0feLqXA0E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standing back-bends (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Position your feet slightly behind your hips. Place your hands on your low back (or table as shown in the video), and slowly bend backwards. You will feel this stretch in your lower back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjXCgxajrY4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prone Press-ups (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Lie on the floor and place your hands slightly wider than shoulder-width. Contract your lats and press up with your arms. You should feel a stretch in the low back. Exhale at the top of the movement for a deeper low-back stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qCOt_Em11g8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end and hit 6 points to form the shape of a star as shown in the video. Contract your lats and make sure that your shoulders are relaxed and not shrugged up towards your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xTCvBqZz3Bc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bodyweight Squats&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your feet are shoulder-width apart and that you contract your glutes while hinging at the hips. When you come down, try to break just below parallel and come back up. If you feel this in your lower back, you should compare your form to the example in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p3g4wAsu0R4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to perform these exercises every 30-45 minutes (set a timer!) throughout the work day to prevent poor posture and to prehab the body from potential future injuries. Hopefully, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to hit the gym, your body is already primed for the upcoming movements and you&amp;rsquo;ll be less stiff and sore afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these exercises a try, and let me know if they work for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 ingredient mac and cheese</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/mac-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 11:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/mac-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best recipes come by accidentally mixing things together and tasting the outcome. This Mac &amp;amp; Cheese recipe is a simple as it sounds: 2 ingredients + microwave for 1-2 minutes + enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Not a huge fan of cooking? Then this recipe is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CyCVRgNTJ8Q/Vrd2BicikRI/AAAAAAAAA6w/3LDTsjckFVE/s640/mac%2526cheese.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;113g Cottage Cheese (low fat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56g Dry Pasta (any shape you like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave-Safe Bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook and drain the pasta according to the directions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pasta and 113g (1 serving) of cottage cheese to a microwave-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave the mixture of pasta and cottage cheese for 1-2 minutes or until the cottage cheese is completely melted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix the cottage cheese and pasta together and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 5 &amp; 6 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 13:25:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk5-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just say StrongLifts and I have a &lt;strong&gt;LOVE-HATE&lt;/strong&gt; relationship these past 2 weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some major strength gains for bench press (up to 110# 5X5); however, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to reduce the volume of my deadlifts and barbell rows due to low back fatigue and stiffness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sIsl0t4PpBg/VpvVMDXm_4I/AAAAAAAAA6A/1VZUrfJ7IPA/s1600/a%2Bqueenflex.blogspot.com%2Breview.jpg&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;20%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this program is very strenuous on the body and ample recovery is necessary in order to progress by at least 5 lbs each session. I also have never continuously followed a &amp;ldquo;strength building&amp;rdquo; program, where increased volume is a priority. I honestly can say that I LOVE this way of training because it forces you to give everything you&amp;rsquo;ve got and leaves you feeling extremely &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s an addictive feeling, and I&amp;rsquo;m growing to love every training session just a little more. It&amp;rsquo;s become more about ME vs. ME as opposed to  ME vs everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pause a moment and discuss appropriate nutrition for StrongLifts 5X5. You must eat on this program. Let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST EAT ON THIS PROGRAM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not fuel yourself appropriately for these workouts, you will not be able to give the lifts 100% effort. You&amp;rsquo;ll pretty much feel like crap and want to writher up and die. Now that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration; however, YOU MUST EAT if you want to hit PR&amp;rsquo;s and advance your lifts. To do this, it&amp;rsquo;s very suitable to load carbohydrates around your workout. &lt;a href=&#34;http://staging.eattoperform.com/2013/06/20/eight-nutrition-tips/&#34;&gt;2:1 carbohydrates-protein ratio is fine&lt;/a&gt;. I typically have my pre-workout meal about an hour to an hour and a half prior to lifting. My post-workout meal (PWO) is directly after I cool down/stretch and consists of 2:1 fast-digesting carbs (sugars) to fast absorption whey protein isolate. I am also working to become more consistent with taking &lt;a href=&#34;https://examine.com/supplements/Creatine/&#34;&gt;5g of Creatine Monohydrate&lt;/a&gt; PWO to help with muscle recovery and carbohydrate absorption. For an example of a typical day-in-the-life of Liz, check out my MyFitnessPal diary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/diary/stronglizlifts?date=2016-01-16&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider when doing any sort of strength building program is recovery. You must allocate rest days on this program. Again, let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST RECOVER ON THIS PROGRAM. DO NOT CUT REST DAYS!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recovery days are CRITICAL on this program. If you never rest, you&amp;rsquo;ll never recover, and therefore, you&amp;rsquo;ll never feel &amp;ldquo;ready&amp;rdquo; to increase your lifts. You&amp;rsquo;ll be in a continual state of soreness, and trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not fun. Give yourself extra days to recover if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling worn out. You&amp;rsquo;ll feel better and be mentally ready to give it your all in the gym. Remember, heavy, high-volume workouts are tearing your body down. You need time to allow your body to fix the tears and build new tissues and blood vessels to support muscle growth. &lt;strong&gt;Do yourself a favor and rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All and all, StrongLifts has given me a platform to start off my strength training and a flexible plan to meet my weight training goals. I highly recommend jumping in and giving it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to meal prep over a weekend</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 12:26:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Hate cooking? Or do you enjoy cooking but want to try something new in the kitchen? I typically meal prep over the course of a weekend by first making a protein and a carb dish and then mixing them together. In this article, I will walk you through this process of making simple, delicious meals that you can grab-and-go throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cHlo3X4gvbE/VpvNlrZTydI/AAAAAAAAA5c/0oVTGC635kM/s400/IMG_0156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prepare-your-protein-source-chicken&#34;&gt;Prepare Your Protein Source (Chicken)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;ve prepped my meals over the course of two days: Saturday and Sunday. Friday night I washed, trimmed, and seasoned two chicken breasts and placed them in a small crock pot to cook on low for 8 hours overnight. Saturday morning, the chicken was perfectly tender and easy to shred with tongs. Next, I divided the shredded chicken into six portions. I put the chicken away in the fridge and paused the rest of my meal prep until Sunday. Check out this article for additional ways to &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/&#34;&gt;cook perfect chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-some-carbs-potatoes&#34;&gt;Add Some Carbs (Potatoes)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning, I washed, peeled, and diced up two sweet potatoes and one white potato. I also elected to use up some Alexa Sweet Potato fries from my freezer. I set the oven to 425-deg F and baked the fries for about 25 minutes and the diced potatoes for about 35 minutes or until brown. Once the potatoes were cooked, I took the six portions of shredded chicken out of the fridge and put about 150g of potatoes into each container. Click here for more information about &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/cooked-sweet-potatoes/&#34;&gt;cooking perfect sweet potatoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finalize-with-veggies-seasonings-and-sauces&#34;&gt;Finalize with Veggies, Seasonings, and Sauces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m huge on using frozen veggies because I think the taste and cost per serving is unbeatable compared to fresh veggies. Fresh veggies have a lifespan, and if for whatever reason I don&amp;rsquo;t eat all the veggies I buy within a few days, I end up wasting food. I typically buy the microwavable frozen veggie bags because they provide about 3-4 servings per bag, which is great for meal prep. This weekend, I cooked a bag of California blend (broccoli, cauliflower, and carrots), and added it to the shredded chicken and potato meals. Feel free to mix it up and use whatever veggies you like. By incorporating veggies into the pre-made meals, it forces you to eat your vegetables because they&amp;rsquo;re already cooked and included with the other foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also add seasonings: salt, pepper, Mrs. Dash, etc, as well as sauces: hot sauce, salsa, ketchup, mustard, or salad dressings to make the meals more flavorful. I tend to add these dressings or sauces on just before I&amp;rsquo;m about to eat the meal so that the food doesn&amp;rsquo;t get soggy in the refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr-meal-prep-isn-t-difficult&#34;&gt;TL;DR: Meal Prep Isn&amp;rsquo;t Difficult&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a good chef or even spend a lot of time in the kitchen. Between the two days of meal prep, I probably spent about an hour total and was able to make six meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key steps to meal prep are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a protein source that you like to eat: chicken, beef, fish, tofu, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a carb source that you also like to eat: potatoes, rice, pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some veggies, seasonings, and sauces.
If your meal plan requires added fats such as olive oil or nuts, feel free to add those in too. Be sure to emphasize choosing foods you LIKE; otherwise, it will be much more difficult to eat the meals you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use shortcuts such as crockpot shredded chicken, minute rice, and frozen microwavable veggies to help save time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portion foods using the typical serving size per bag or with a small food scale. With time and practice your meal prep skills will improve, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to mix and match multiple protein and carb sources to have a diverse selection of meals for the week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Feel free to drop a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 3 &amp; 4 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 22:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks on the StrongLifts program have been both rewarding and extremely challenging. Between Christmas, New Years, and traveling with family, as well as keeping up with my Eat To Perform numbers, I added about 20 lbs to my Squat and hit PRs on DeadLifts and Bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each workout is increasingly difficult and recovery and pre-workout nutrition are key to having successful sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say I finished 2015 with a bang, and certainly look forward to the remaining two-thirds of the StrongLifts [starter] program. I plan to reassess my goals and progress in early March to determine whether or not I want to continue StrongLifts for another cycle or to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-njamapHPYGg/Voc8zbOX2UI/AAAAAAAAA3o/1irFK5yhA9U/s1600/STRONGLIFTS%2B5X5-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;today-s-workout-day-a-squat-bench-row&#34;&gt;today&amp;rsquo;s workout - day a: squat, bench, row&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifts today; however, were slightly off, ringing in the new year with a less-than-perfect workout. I missed all my working sets 5X5 for Squats and Rows due to lower back instability and fuzziness. Instead I hit a PR on bench for 5X5 and proceeded to work on my posterior chain mobility and flexibility. Some of my favorite mobility workouts are from Kelly Starrett of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilitywod.com/&#34;&gt;mobilityWod&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi099DokYrKAhVPxGMKHfezDmAQtwIIIDAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DJBHzXF-mVjY&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaLWLA1UMVOUFEO6OzZqgok1GmKw&amp;amp;sig2=vz_aHpCAV1Y7K4uGt-dXpw&#34;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiq3O6AkorKAhVY-2MKHVVdBakQtwIIHzAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DzT657soclws&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHiOQ9WoMXXQvfBqAiBtEImgna-mg&amp;amp;sig2=oC2AOgiSS_Ap2C-7dvP-Dw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.110151844,d.cGc&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; are my go-to&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m having lower back instability or hip tightness. I highly recommend checking out the mobility project for improving overall mobility and health while building strength and muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;next steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to give myself the weekend off and start back up on Monday (1/4/16) with Day B. While a disappointing start to the new year, I am very happy with my overall progress on this program and have never been more excited to work out. Even though the exercises are the same, each routine feels different because it is all about trying to increase volume through an increase in weight over 5 sets of 5. I have no doubt that I will be on my way to hitting 225# squat and deadlift and 145# bench in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is. Short and sweet. Until the next update&amp;hellip; Lift Heavy, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meal prep perfect chicken</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:57:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tired of dried, bland, and burnt rubber chicken?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 2016 right around the corner, and meal prep headed into full swing within the next few weeks, here is an article to help you prepare delicious, juicy chicken every time. The following article explains my top 3 methods of preparing chicken for use in delicious dinners and dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4gfh0CU-FfM/VoWWZbM-vkI/AAAAAAAAA3Q/TZqq1KLGEU0/w250-h160-c/Grilled-Chicken3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-1-u-wash-trim-and-season-chicken-before-cooking&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #1:&lt;/u&gt;  Wash, Trim, and Season Chicken BEFORE cooking.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before baking, grilling, frying, or boiling, be sure to wash and trim the chicken. I typically use cold water and a pair of kitchen scissors to trim off extra fat. I recommend these pair of scissors from Walmart. They&amp;rsquo;re very affordable and sharp enough to cut meat. When they&amp;rsquo;re dull, I just buy a new pair. Once you finish washing and trimming the chicken breasts, you are ready to add seasonings or marinades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;these-are-some-of-my-favorite-seasonings&#34;&gt;These are some of my favorite seasonings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mustard (powder or condiment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balsamic Vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bolthouse Farms Italian Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be creative with your seasonings. If you are big into BBQ chicken, then find some BBQ marinades or rubs. Just be mindful of the sodium content since some of the seasonings can have high salt contents While sodium is helpful for athletes, too much of anything can cause health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-2-u-flip-once-when-you-grill-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #2: &lt;/u&gt;  Flip Once when you Grill Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite way to cook chicken is on the grill. The chicken is crispy and juicy and usually tastes great even as leftovers! The key to grilling chicken is to have a hot grill (at least 450-deg F) and to flip the chicken breasts once every 10-12 minutes. This allows each side to obtain perfect grill marks and to become both crispy and juicy. Note: depending on the size/weight of the chicken breast, you may need to adjust the time and temperature so that it is fully cooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-3-u-set-it-and-forget-it-crockpot-chicken-shredded-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #3:&lt;/u&gt;  Set it and forget it. CrockPot Chicken = Shredded Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: right;&#34; src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--bfn1ttBdk4/VoWVGj2DDiI/AAAAAAAAA3I/4SwphTXOZ6M/s320/IMG_0101.JPG&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work a full-time job or are a full-time student without a lot of time to cook chicken, I highly recommend this method. Put two to three chicken breasts in a small CrockPot (8qt), set on high, and then forget it. The chicken will cook through in two to four hours and can be turned or checked every so often. For added flavor, see &lt;strong&gt;Method #1 above:&lt;/strong&gt; Wash, trim, and season with your favorite flavors! When the chicken is fully cooked, take two forks and pull the chicken apart for a ready-made-meal in minutes. Sometimes I will use the shredded chicken in other dishes such as my Italian Chicken Lasagna or &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitmencook.com/fit-healthy-chicken-rice-enchilada-casserole/&#34;&gt;Healthy Chicken &amp;amp; Rice Enchiladas from FitMenCook&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a super simple way to get a lot of chicken cooked without having to babysit a stove, oven, or grill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make 2016 your best #MealPrep year ever with these simple tips for cooking perfect chicken every time! What are your secrets for cooking moist, delicious chicken? Leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>