<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a 10-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:54:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we overlook the cool-down routine as much as our warm-up routine. I think it has something to do with wanting to get to the exciting part of the workout and both warm-ups and cool-downs are &amp;ldquo;boring.&amp;rdquo; I used to think that these routines were a waste of time, but that was before I knew just how much benefit they provide the body. This article explains a quick, ten-minute recovery routine that you can do practically anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you will need the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopwatch or Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair or something about 2-feet off the ground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a circuit of four different exercises that are best performed post-workout or at a time when you want to &amp;ldquo;relax.&amp;rdquo; They are taken from the exercises recommended by Maraynn Berry&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/video/5-simple-exercises-to-eliminate-neck-pain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Simple Exercises to Eliminate Neck Pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be experiencing neck pain in order to do these exercises! I find that this condensed version allows my body to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;relax&amp;rdquo; especially after a heavy lifting session. This routine is especially beneficial for desk jockies because it promotes proper posture from the neck, through the shoulders, down to the hips and adductors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each exercise in this routine, you will hold the position for two minutes. There are five exercises total, therefore, ten-minutes of &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; time for this routine. I recommend you read through the exercise, and then give them a try! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-1-u-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 1:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Back:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay on the floor with your legs propped up on a chair or object 2-feet tall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your legs should be at a 90-degree angle to your hips. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-2-u-static-scapular-extension&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 2:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Scapular Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start on all fours, ensuring that your wrists are directly under your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk your hands about 6-inches in front of the starting position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift your hips forward so that your weight and shoulders are over your wrists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your elbows straight and allow your shoulder blades to sink down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your head hang. Release any tension in your neck and mouth. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;It will be challenging, but try to hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; While it seems counter-intuitive to hold this position, since we spend most of our day in a slouched over position, this exercise moves the scapula into extension, promoting realignment to the shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-3-u-repeat-exercise-1-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 3:&lt;/u&gt;  Repeat Exercise 1, Static Back.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-4-u-wall-hold&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 4:&lt;/u&gt;  Wall Hold:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit on the floor with your back and head against a wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull your shoulder blades together and down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest your legs straight out in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flex your quads. Flex your feet towards your body. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-5-u-static-adductor-frog&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 5:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Adductor (Frog):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start in a seated position with the bottoms of your feet touching each other (a.k.a. butterfly position). Make sure that your feet are aligned with the center of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lie back and relax every muscle in your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your arms at a 45-degree angle to your sides with your palms facing up. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this routine a try after your next workout or before bed. After a week of doing this routine, it&amp;rsquo;ll become second-nature and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it helps with recovery and &amp;ldquo;resets&amp;rdquo; your posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does your cool-down routine look like? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Recover with this easy, 10-minute routine www.queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; with your tips and tricks for improving recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources-for-prehab-rehab-and-recovery&#34;&gt;Additional Resources for Prehab, Rehab, and Recovery:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/au/learn/banish-pain-permanently-basic-drills-to-repair-your-posture?page=0,0&#34;&gt;Banish Pain Permanently by Maryann Berry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uprightposturefitness.com/sitting-floor-exercise/&#34;&gt;Sitting Floor Exercise by Upright Posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/egoscue-method/&#34;&gt;Egoscue Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McKenzie Method / MDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My brain is a continuum of fitnessesque thoughts; I tend to think a lot about how to improve my life through fitness, nutrition, recovery, and lifestyle changes. In the queenflex blog you will find all the random and insightful fitness ideas I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to jot down. This collection of articles is based on what I&amp;rsquo;ve read and what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned through trial-and-error. So go ahead, read some articles, drop a comment (or two), and work with me to become the person you&amp;rsquo;ve dreamt of being.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-fun-facts-about-this-blog&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some fun facts about this blog:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Born in Fall 2015 the aim to promote fitness, motivation, and healthy lifestyles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built in &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt; using &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and hosted on &lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coded and maintained in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sublimetext.com/2&#34;&gt;sublime text 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the articles are written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Redesigned multiple times using various blogger templates before migrating to Hugo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fit links</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/links/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/links/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This page serves as a repertoir of the top-knotch fitness and health websites approved by the queen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Add my favorite fitness site to queenflex.com&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; to have your favorite fitness site added to the queen&amp;rsquo;s list. Shoutout to those who made the cut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strength-standards&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder how your lifts stack up others at the same height, weight, and gender? Well Strength Standards has all this figured out! Just type in your currrent stats, your best &lt;em&gt;weight x reps&lt;/em&gt; for the big 4 (bench, squat, deadlift, press), and Strength Standards will tell you how you compare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website can also be used to generate progressions. If you&amp;rsquo;re stuck in a plateau with any of your lifts, you can generate progressions for popular lifting programs (5/3/1, Stronglifts, Cube Method, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Strength Standards is a great tool for benchmarking your current strength relative to your current size. The only downfall is you cannot &amp;ldquo;log&amp;rdquo; your progress with Strength Standards. Because of this, I recommend taking a look at the Strong App.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;www.strengthstandards.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strong-app-for-ios&#34;&gt;Strong (App for iOS)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Track your progress on any lift with this app for iOS. I have been using this app since Jan 2016, and let me tell you, it beats out the pencil-paper method by a million. (And I was an avid user of notebooks and training templates throughout the years.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an iDevice, switching to Strong provides you the simplicity of a notebook without the complexity and hassle of determining how much weight, how many sets/reps, and what you need to do in order to achieve progressive overload. You can see the exact weight and reps you did previously for each exercise, and that&amp;rsquo;s something that you cannot do with a notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong allows you to create custom workout routines and exercises and also provides a built-in set timer, warm-up calculator, and plate calculator. You can mark sets as &amp;ldquo;warm-up&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;drop-set&amp;rdquo;, or &amp;ldquo;failure&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s also easy to see progress over time, because each completed routine is added to the master calendar and PR&amp;rsquo;s are recorded into charts for each exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strong stores all your data in the cloud and has the option to integrate with Facebook. Overall, it&amp;rsquo;s provided me with a great value for the price. Note, I am not endorsed to say anything positive about Strong. I have had such a great experience with the app, and it&amp;rsquo;s constantly receiving updates (buy the full version with upgrades in perpetuity!) by their development team. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit @strongapp I just visited http://strongapp.io via queenflex.com. What an awesome fitness tracking app!&#34;&gt;Have a look at it, and let me know what you think!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://strongapp.io&#34;&gt;strongapp.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;muscle-for-life-michael-matthews&#34;&gt;Muscle For Life / Michael Matthews&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Matthews has written multiple books and articles around fitness, bodybuilding, and strength training. Notorious for his best-selling books, &amp;ldquo;Bigger Leaner Stronger&amp;rdquo; (for men) and &amp;ldquo;Thinner Leaner Stronger&amp;rdquo; (for women), Matthews provides scientific evidence alongside his recommendations while explaining the &amp;ldquo;how&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; of nutrition and training in language anyone can understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can learn more about him, his training philosophies, and programs on his website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muscleforlife.com&#34;&gt;www.muscleforlife.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;last updated 2016-11-25&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1-rm progression calculator</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 15:20:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/calculator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever struggle to figure out how much weight you should use per set during a 1-rep-max test?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, look no further! Here&amp;rsquo;s a calculator that you can use to determine how much weight you should use for each of your warm-up and working sets in order to reach your target 1RM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input your target 1RM weight into the &amp;ldquo;target 1RM weight&amp;rdquo; field as well as the set number. The calculator will output the number of reps and respective weight you should hit for the given set. All calculations are based on the recommendations from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/training/how-to-warm-up-for-a-one-rep-max&#34;&gt;this T-Nation article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tool courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.com&#34;&gt;queenflex.com&lt;/a&gt;, written by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;https://jscalc.io&#34;&gt;jscalc.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://jscalc.io/embed/aQMGRFvVJOGJW6Iq?autofocus=1&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;600px&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; overflow:&#34;hidden&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combat office slouch</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-being-such-a-slouch&#34;&gt;Stop being such a slouch!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and work a desk job, it is easy to turn into a slouched over mess. With all the hype out there about &amp;ldquo;sitting is the new smoking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prehab is rehab&amp;rdquo;, I have decided to create a list of the most realistic exercises that you can do at the office to help improve posture, mobility, and overall happiness. &lt;em&gt;And hopefully prevent you from looking like a stupid fool, rolling around on the floor next to your cubical.&lt;/em&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the advice I&amp;rsquo;m providing here is based off of my personal experience with chronic low back, hip, neck, and shoulder pain, and does not substitute or replace medical advice. These tricks have worked for me based on meeting with a physical therapist for my own mobility/stability issues; however, everybody is different, and it&amp;rsquo;s best to seek an opinion from your doctor prior to trying a rehab/stretch/strength program like the one I am about to outline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to working a full-time desk job, I was a college student. When people think college, they may think parties, alcohol, weight gain, and craziness; however, the reality of my college experience was hair-pulling, weight loss, walking everywhere, and craziness. Once I found myself sitting at the same desk for hours on end with little reason to move other than to get water or use the bathroom, I realized I was becoming a slouched over mess. [Cue the mobility issues, back and hip pain.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;neat&amp;rdquo; little thing about exercise: you can work out for an hour—maybe even two hours—a day, but if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/health-medicine/its-not-your-metabolism-its-your-neat-thats-stopping-your-fat-loss&#34;&gt;inactive for 8-15 hours a day, then exercise less effective&lt;/a&gt;. So why is that so “neat” you may ask? Well it has to do with &lt;strong&gt;N.E.A.T or non-exercise activity thermogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;, aka “what you do when you’re not exercising, which burns calories to keep you alive.” So if you put yourself into a lethargic, slumped over position all day long, and think you will have great mobility for your squat session that evening, well good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-prevent-becoming-an-immobile-mess-of-a-human-being&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I prevent becoming an immobile mess of a human being?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer:&lt;/u&gt; get off your butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer explained:&lt;/u&gt; Every 30-45 minutes, get up and perform a series of mobility/stability exercises to counterbalance the poor posture from sitting. Think back to eighth-grade science class where you learned about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/newtlaws/Lesson-4/Newton-s-Third-Law&#34;&gt;Newton’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;. (For you engineers out there, forgive me, this was a very recent topic for y’all). Newton’s Third Law states that for every action force there is a reaction force equal in magnitude and opposite in direction. For example, if you’re sitting in a slouched over position, inducing flexion on your spine, it’d be wise to get up every half hour and do some back bends to induce extension. Refer to the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://teachmeanatomy.info/wp-content/uploads/Terms-of-Movement-Flexion-and-Extension-CC-1024x815.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-15-minute-routine-to-combat-office-slouch&#34;&gt;A 15-minute routine to combat office slouch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a reason why people who live in a constant state of flexion throw their backs out when they pick up a basket of laundry; it’s because they’re inducing extension on a spine that has been molded into the flexion world. It’s time to teach our spines, and other body parts for that matter, what neutral looks like. To do this, I have developed a short list of five exercises that I think are the most effective for resetting the body and prehab for future injuries. You only need therabands/resistance bands to perform all the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you live in the world of &lt;u&gt;extension&lt;/u&gt;, you would probably benefit from &lt;u&gt;flexion&lt;/u&gt; exercises instead of exercises two and three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder W&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end keep your elbows by your sides. Contract your lats and pull the band apart forming a &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; with your arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_G0feLqXA0E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standing back-bends (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Position your feet slightly behind your hips. Place your hands on your low back (or table as shown in the video), and slowly bend backwards. You will feel this stretch in your lower back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjXCgxajrY4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prone Press-ups (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Lie on the floor and place your hands slightly wider than shoulder-width. Contract your lats and press up with your arms. You should feel a stretch in the low back. Exhale at the top of the movement for a deeper low-back stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qCOt_Em11g8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end and hit 6 points to form the shape of a star as shown in the video. Contract your lats and make sure that your shoulders are relaxed and not shrugged up towards your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xTCvBqZz3Bc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bodyweight Squats&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your feet are shoulder-width apart and that you contract your glutes while hinging at the hips. When you come down, try to break just below parallel and come back up. If you feel this in your lower back, you should compare your form to the example in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p3g4wAsu0R4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to perform these exercises every 30-45 minutes (set a timer!) throughout the work day to prevent poor posture and to prehab the body from potential future injuries. Hopefully, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to hit the gym, your body is already primed for the upcoming movements and you&amp;rsquo;ll be less stiff and sore afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these exercises a try, and let me know if they work for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 ingredient mac and cheese</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/mac-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 11:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/mac-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best recipes come by accidentally mixing things together and tasting the outcome. This Mac &amp;amp; Cheese recipe is a simple as it sounds: 2 ingredients + microwave for 1-2 minutes + enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Not a huge fan of cooking? Then this recipe is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CyCVRgNTJ8Q/Vrd2BicikRI/AAAAAAAAA6w/3LDTsjckFVE/s640/mac%2526cheese.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;113g Cottage Cheese (low fat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56g Dry Pasta (any shape you like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave-Safe Bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook and drain the pasta according to the directions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pasta and 113g (1 serving) of cottage cheese to a microwave-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave the mixture of pasta and cottage cheese for 1-2 minutes or until the cottage cheese is completely melted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix the cottage cheese and pasta together and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to meal prep over a weekend</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 12:26:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Hate cooking? Or do you enjoy cooking but want to try something new in the kitchen? I typically meal prep over the course of a weekend by first making a protein and a carb dish and then mixing them together. In this article, I will walk you through this process of making simple, delicious meals that you can grab-and-go throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cHlo3X4gvbE/VpvNlrZTydI/AAAAAAAAA5c/0oVTGC635kM/s400/IMG_0156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prepare-your-protein-source-chicken&#34;&gt;Prepare Your Protein Source (Chicken)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;ve prepped my meals over the course of two days: Saturday and Sunday. Friday night I washed, trimmed, and seasoned two chicken breasts and placed them in a small crock pot to cook on low for 8 hours overnight. Saturday morning, the chicken was perfectly tender and easy to shred with tongs. Next, I divided the shredded chicken into six portions. I put the chicken away in the fridge and paused the rest of my meal prep until Sunday. Check out this article for additional ways to &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/&#34;&gt;cook perfect chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-some-carbs-potatoes&#34;&gt;Add Some Carbs (Potatoes)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning, I washed, peeled, and diced up two sweet potatoes and one white potato. I also elected to use up some Alexa Sweet Potato fries from my freezer. I set the oven to 425-deg F and baked the fries for about 25 minutes and the diced potatoes for about 35 minutes or until brown. Once the potatoes were cooked, I took the six portions of shredded chicken out of the fridge and put about 150g of potatoes into each container. Click here for more information about &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/cooked-sweet-potatoes/&#34;&gt;cooking perfect sweet potatoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finalize-with-veggies-seasonings-and-sauces&#34;&gt;Finalize with Veggies, Seasonings, and Sauces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m huge on using frozen veggies because I think the taste and cost per serving is unbeatable compared to fresh veggies. Fresh veggies have a lifespan, and if for whatever reason I don&amp;rsquo;t eat all the veggies I buy within a few days, I end up wasting food. I typically buy the microwavable frozen veggie bags because they provide about 3-4 servings per bag, which is great for meal prep. This weekend, I cooked a bag of California blend (broccoli, cauliflower, and carrots), and added it to the shredded chicken and potato meals. Feel free to mix it up and use whatever veggies you like. By incorporating veggies into the pre-made meals, it forces you to eat your vegetables because they&amp;rsquo;re already cooked and included with the other foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also add seasonings: salt, pepper, Mrs. Dash, etc, as well as sauces: hot sauce, salsa, ketchup, mustard, or salad dressings to make the meals more flavorful. I tend to add these dressings or sauces on just before I&amp;rsquo;m about to eat the meal so that the food doesn&amp;rsquo;t get soggy in the refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr-meal-prep-isn-t-difficult&#34;&gt;TL;DR: Meal Prep Isn&amp;rsquo;t Difficult&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a good chef or even spend a lot of time in the kitchen. Between the two days of meal prep, I probably spent about an hour total and was able to make six meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key steps to meal prep are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a protein source that you like to eat: chicken, beef, fish, tofu, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a carb source that you also like to eat: potatoes, rice, pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some veggies, seasonings, and sauces.
If your meal plan requires added fats such as olive oil or nuts, feel free to add those in too. Be sure to emphasize choosing foods you LIKE; otherwise, it will be much more difficult to eat the meals you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use shortcuts such as crockpot shredded chicken, minute rice, and frozen microwavable veggies to help save time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portion foods using the typical serving size per bag or with a small food scale. With time and practice your meal prep skills will improve, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to mix and match multiple protein and carb sources to have a diverse selection of meals for the week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Feel free to drop a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meal prep perfect chicken</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:57:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tired of dried, bland, and burnt rubber chicken?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 2016 right around the corner, and meal prep headed into full swing within the next few weeks, here is an article to help you prepare delicious, juicy chicken every time. The following article explains my top 3 methods of preparing chicken for use in delicious dinners and dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4gfh0CU-FfM/VoWWZbM-vkI/AAAAAAAAA3Q/TZqq1KLGEU0/w250-h160-c/Grilled-Chicken3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-1-u-wash-trim-and-season-chicken-before-cooking&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #1:&lt;/u&gt;  Wash, Trim, and Season Chicken BEFORE cooking.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before baking, grilling, frying, or boiling, be sure to wash and trim the chicken. I typically use cold water and a pair of kitchen scissors to trim off extra fat. I recommend these pair of scissors from Walmart. They&amp;rsquo;re very affordable and sharp enough to cut meat. When they&amp;rsquo;re dull, I just buy a new pair. Once you finish washing and trimming the chicken breasts, you are ready to add seasonings or marinades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;these-are-some-of-my-favorite-seasonings&#34;&gt;These are some of my favorite seasonings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mustard (powder or condiment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balsamic Vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bolthouse Farms Italian Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be creative with your seasonings. If you are big into BBQ chicken, then find some BBQ marinades or rubs. Just be mindful of the sodium content since some of the seasonings can have high salt contents While sodium is helpful for athletes, too much of anything can cause health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-2-u-flip-once-when-you-grill-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #2: &lt;/u&gt;  Flip Once when you Grill Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite way to cook chicken is on the grill. The chicken is crispy and juicy and usually tastes great even as leftovers! The key to grilling chicken is to have a hot grill (at least 450-deg F) and to flip the chicken breasts once every 10-12 minutes. This allows each side to obtain perfect grill marks and to become both crispy and juicy. Note: depending on the size/weight of the chicken breast, you may need to adjust the time and temperature so that it is fully cooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-3-u-set-it-and-forget-it-crockpot-chicken-shredded-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #3:&lt;/u&gt;  Set it and forget it. CrockPot Chicken = Shredded Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: right;&#34; src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--bfn1ttBdk4/VoWVGj2DDiI/AAAAAAAAA3I/4SwphTXOZ6M/s320/IMG_0101.JPG&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work a full-time job or are a full-time student without a lot of time to cook chicken, I highly recommend this method. Put two to three chicken breasts in a small CrockPot (8qt), set on high, and then forget it. The chicken will cook through in two to four hours and can be turned or checked every so often. For added flavor, see &lt;strong&gt;Method #1 above:&lt;/strong&gt; Wash, trim, and season with your favorite flavors! When the chicken is fully cooked, take two forks and pull the chicken apart for a ready-made-meal in minutes. Sometimes I will use the shredded chicken in other dishes such as my Italian Chicken Lasagna or &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitmencook.com/fit-healthy-chicken-rice-enchilada-casserole/&#34;&gt;Healthy Chicken &amp;amp; Rice Enchiladas from FitMenCook&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a super simple way to get a lot of chicken cooked without having to babysit a stove, oven, or grill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make 2016 your best #MealPrep year ever with these simple tips for cooking perfect chicken every time! What are your secrets for cooking moist, delicious chicken? Leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a mini guide on supplements</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 17:25:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why shell out hundreds of dollars per month on useless supplements when you can have all the health benefits for under $75? Supplements are not magic and will not get the results you have not been working for; they are only useful if you have been working out smart and eating to support your energy balance and training goals. Over the years, my opinions about supplements have changed dramatically: initially I bought into the trendy supplement stacks promoted by famous and aesthetic bodybuilders whom are often receiving free products from the companies they are endorsed by. For this reason alone, it is important to choose supplements based on your own goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-66lpbJ3zzCo/VmNQda3zQvI/AAAAAAAAAyA/s6AK5_LQdL8/s640/bs-thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a goal, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be thinking about supplements! Be critical of yourself. Map out your workout and nutrition plans first before complicating the process with the wealth, media, and pop-culture out there surrounding the &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rsquo;s and don&amp;rsquo;ts&amp;rdquo; of supplementation. In this article, I will outline my current (and minimalistic) approach to supplementation as well as tips you can use to build a meaningful supplementation stack for less than $75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;supplements-so-many-choices-so-few-that-matter&#34;&gt;Supplements: So Many Choices, So Few That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rise of mainstream fitness and the high profitability of supplement companies comes a wealth of random products that may or may not be suitable for taking based on your goals. I base my supplementation around two key components: #1 DIET, #2 TRAINING. Because I am a huge proponent of EatToPerform, I have been slowly introducing the concept of wave dieting the past few months. (You can read more about the wave diet on ETP&amp;rsquo;s website.) My current goal (as of Dec 2015) is to average 2000 calories daily: 140g protein, 298g carbs, 50g fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You might ask:&lt;/em&gt; Ok Liz, what does this have to do with supplementation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And really, the answer is quite simple:&lt;/em&gt; I will only supplement to help meet my macros if eating whole foods alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #1:&lt;/u&gt; If eating three whole food meals including lean meats, chicken, fish, etc doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me meet my protein goals for the day, only then will I add in a protein supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My go-to protein supplement is Whey Protein Isolate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UKV6Fxp9skU/VmNTvgeOvsI/AAAAAAAAAyM/Zd4GdCwFW7k/s320/performance-whey.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a liking to Optimum Nutrition&amp;rsquo;s Performance Whey Isolate. The ingredients label is easy-to-read, the macronutrients fit my needs, and it&amp;rsquo;s affordable (~$35-50  for 50 servings).
There is an exception to Postulate #1, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Exception #1:&lt;/u&gt; If I know I will be having an intense workout that day (HIIT, Heavy Deadlifts, Heavy Squats, etc), I will supplement with Whey Protein Isolate within 30-minutes post-workout. I feel that this method helps speed up recovery for me and reduces soreness/delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS) within the following two days. The main reason why I prefer Whey Protein Isolate over blends, concentrates, caseinate, vegan/vegetarian/soy proteins, etc. is because Whey Protein Isolate is fast-absorption and typically gives you the most protein for the price. To me, if I&amp;rsquo;m going to buy a protein supplement, I want it to contain protein, not fillers, nor proprietary blends, and junk that I have no real reason to put into my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #2:&lt;/u&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s important to check the supplement for purity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nifty website that is focused on supplement quality and value is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.labdoor.com&#34;&gt;Labdoor&lt;/a&gt;. You can search for supplements, and if Labdoor has run quality/purity tests on the product, you will get the lab test results. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to verify that what you&amp;rsquo;re buying and using is a safe product filled with the ingredients reported on the label. With that said, a few other Whey Protein Isolate brands I recommend are Myprotein&amp;rsquo;s Impact Whey Isolate, and Isopure Whey Isolate. &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.myprotein.com/referrals.list?applyCode=LIZ-R4T&amp;amp;li&#34;&gt;Get 10% off your order on myprotein.com&lt;/a&gt; when you make a purchase with my link!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #3:&lt;/u&gt; Take Fish Oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.meme.am/instances/500x/56405802.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone, active or not, should be supplementing with fish oil. Unless you eat salmon every day, you will not reach an optimal level of Omega-3&amp;rsquo;s. You can read more about fish oil and the required dosages here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should be supplementing with 1g Fish Oil/day; active people should be closer to 6g Fish Oil/day. I currently supplement with Vitamin Shoppe&amp;rsquo;s Fish Oil due to its high quality/purity and value ratings on Labdoor. One thing to note about fish oil is that it should be bought in &lt;strong&gt;SMALLER&lt;/strong&gt; packages to reduce the effects of oxidation. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to store fish oil in the refrigerator/freezer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt; Postulate #4: &lt;/u&gt; Maximize Post-Workout Gains with Creatine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HP2qviiAniI/VmNZzq63JCI/AAAAAAAAAyg/kZzwNH-AktA/s640/creatine-safe.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Creatine is safe. Because creatine is well-researched, it is &amp;ldquo;remarkably safe for most people.&amp;rdquo; One of my favorite websites for verifying the safety of products is Examine.com. Not only can you learn more about creatine, but you can search nearly any supplement or drug, and you can learn more about nutrition. Examine.com will provide you dosage information as well as how to maximize absorption of the supplements you decide to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some creatine products I recommend are Con-Cret by ProMera Sports (Creatine HCl) and Creatine Monohydrate from Myprotein. Both have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; ratings on Labdoor, and I have had good results from both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-a-supplement-stack-for-less-than-75-month&#34;&gt;How to Make a Supplement Stack for less than $75/month:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the tips provided above, we can now discuss my $75/month supplement stack. I am not affiliated nor receive a commission for providing you with the brands of products given in my recommendations below. As always, you should consult with your doctor or health professional before starting a health or supplementation program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choose a Reputable Whey Protein Isolate (2 servings/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimum Nutrition Performance Whey Isolate $39 for 4.4lb, 40 days, $1/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pick out Fish Oil (~3g/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Fish Oil - $16 for 60 caps x 2 = $32 for 120 caps, 40 days, $0.80/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buy Creatine (1 serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myprotein Creatine Monohydrate - $11 for 226g, 45 days, $0.28/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top-off with missing Micronutrients/Minerals (1 cap or serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin D 1000IU- $8 for 200 caps, $0.04/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin K 100 Mcg- $5 for 100 caps, $0.05/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt; Natural Calm Magnesium - $18 for 56 servings, $0.32/day. &lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 11/24/16: I no longer recommend Natural Calm Magnesium due to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://labdoor.com/article/labdoors-statement-natural-vitality-calm&#34;&gt;labdoor press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;total-74-70-days-30&#34;&gt;Total - $74.70 # Days- 30&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr-summary&#34;&gt;TL;DR (Summary):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. A starter plan for what supplements to buy, and how to choose meaningful supplements. The first step with any goal is to create your diet and exercise plan; once you have a solid foundation and are eating to match your energy expenditure, you can then add in supplements to help with recovery time and muscle growth. It is important to understand what ingredients you&amp;rsquo;re putting into your body and the safety of the supplements you choose to buy. For that very reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended educating yourself about products before buying and trying. My favorite websites for scientific-based evidence on reputable supplements and dosing information are Labdoor.com and Examine.com. It&amp;rsquo;s your life. Be smart about your supplementation and spending. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall into the pitfall of needing a &amp;ldquo;magic pill&amp;rdquo; to get the results you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you use any of these supplements? Are you surprised by my recommendations? Drop a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until next time&amp;hellip;#queenflexblog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to cook perfect sweet potatoes</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/cooked-sweet-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2015 14:53:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/cooked-sweet-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sweet Potatoes are absolutely delicious when cooked properly. This recipe teaches you how to cook sweet potatoes in the oven. It&amp;rsquo;s the simplest recipe of them all because it only requires one ingredient, the amazingly delicious sweet potato - baked to perfection!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;Life is really simple, but we insist on making it complicated -Confucius&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-9zuFURlAugc/VmM7NaMDNCI/AAAAAAAAAxY/FYRvQZub9V8/s320/sweet-potatoes.jpg&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1500g Sweet Potatoes (I decided to make a large batch to use throughout the week)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Potato Peeler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-stick cooking spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oven Mits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash and peel the sweet potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop each potato into rounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Line baking sheets with aluminum foil. Spray with non-stick cooking spray.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the sweet potatoes to the baking sheets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake for 20 minutes. Remove from oven, flip, and then bake on the opposite side for another 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove from the oven and let cool before eating. Feel free to add seasonings (garlic, italian seasonings, etc) before the potatoes fully cool. They&amp;rsquo;re so sweet on their own that I like to have them plain :D&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mom&#39;s healthy meatballs</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/moms-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 15:23:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/moms-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s meal is a healthy version of a favorite recipe of mine, growing up: Mom&amp;rsquo;s Healthy Meatballs. (Shoutout to my wonderful Mother!) If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a delicious recipe that&amp;rsquo;s both healthy and easy, look no further. I&amp;rsquo;ve combined lean ground beef with diced tomatoes to make a warm, wintery meal suitable for any appetite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-h1OcmdRjb8w/ViaTfVFw3-I/AAAAAAAAAv8/6sJqEFJgfeQ/s320/IMG_1278.JPG&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16oz lean ground beef (I typically buy 93% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Bothouse Farms Italian Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Reduced Fat Mexican Cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can Diced Tomatoes - No Salt Added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder, salt, pepper, Italian seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large skillet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oven dish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tongs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquid measuring cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-stick cooking spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix ground beef, Italian dressing, garlic powder, pepper, and Italian seasonings together in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weigh out four 4oz portions using the kitchen scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide each 4oz portion into four 1oz portions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a large skillet on high. Spray with non-stick cooking spray and lightly coat the pan with some Italian seasonings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the pan is hot, add all of the meatballs to it. Cook the meatballs for roughly 3 minutes each side or until both sides have browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat the oven dish with non-stick cooking spray and add half of the can of diced tomatoes to the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the meatballs from the skillet and add to the oven dish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat each meatball with the remaining diced tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add cheese to the top and additional seasonings, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake at 375-deg F for 20-25 minutes or until the meatballs are fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes. Pair with a side of spaghetti or veggies and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>raspberry ricotta triple chocolate lava cake</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/choco-lava-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2015 20:45:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/choco-lava-cake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-i-could-literally-kiss-myself-this-recipe-is-so-good-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt; &lt;em&gt;I could literally kiss myself; this recipe is so good.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can chocolate be healthy? Make a healthy chocolate dessert with my Raspberry Ricotta Triple Chocolate Lava Cake. In this recipe, I teach you how to make a delicious, healthy, chocolate cake from scratch using fresh ingredients: chocolate cake mix, chocolate pudding, and raspberries. My chocolate lava cake is healthy, tasty, and easy, taking 20 minutes to prepare and 1 hour to cook. No baby-sitting the oven; just add the ingredients to the crock pot and let the heat do its magic!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HxYMlo9dexE/Vg_iaXVOy_I/AAAAAAAAAs4/3Nr2eqBYbLc/s400/blogger-image--7980637.jpg&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the Cake Batter: (Feel free to substitute store-bought cake mix; however, the macronutrients will be way different!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-eOjBw_cvzvg/Vg_zcuh4YII/AAAAAAAAAuY/dkLGk0qIgWk/s400/NutritionLabel-3.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; c. Liquid Egg Whites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Large Egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; - &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; c. Unsweetened Cocoa Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinch - &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp. Baking Soda&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinch - &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp. Baking Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 Packet Stevia/Truvia&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinch of Sea Salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;15g Pancake Mix (I used Great Value from Walmart)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5 oz. Fage 2% Plain Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; Cake Batter Adapted from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rippedrecipes.com/recipe/macro-friendly-chocolate-cupcake-2966.html&#34;&gt;Ripped Recipes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the Fudge Component:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 c. Fat Free Skim Milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40g Sugar Free/Low Fat Chocolate Pudding Pie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For the &amp;lsquo;Triple&amp;rsquo; Chocolate Effect:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Cacao 60% Dark Chocolate Chips (I used Ghirardelli) Filling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For Toppings: (Because you really need more love after all of that)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10 Fresh or frozen raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;68g/1 Serving of Part Skim Ricotta Cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Expect to add roughly 100 calories from these toppings to the total calorie count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small mixing bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crock Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquid and solid Measuring Cups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-yxF2nY8y7nY/Vg_ib5YLj9I/AAAAAAAAAtI/HQclmvxoes0/s320/blogger-image--1762881420.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;90%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn crock pot on low heat to pre-heat the ceramic base while we&amp;rsquo;re preparing the ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine all of the &amp;ldquo;Cake Batter&amp;rdquo; ingredients into a small mixing bowl using the wisk. Mix until the batter is smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour into the crock pot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix the skim milk into the pudding pie filling. Wisk until smooth. (Do not worry about mixing until the pudding sets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the pudding mixture into the crock pot.Use the spatula to remove any remaining batter from the small mixing bowl. (Nothing goes to waste!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle in the 60% Dark Chocolate chips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set the crock pot to high heat and add the lid.8. Let cook for 1-1.5 hours or until the mixture is cooked and has risen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of the lava cake from the crock pot and top with ricotta cheese and raspberries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with cocoa powder and stevia/Truvia, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stand there admiring your work of art. How in the world is this under 300 calories??&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-1jwqcH_s_Y8/Vg_iY1HEqQI/AAAAAAAAAso/3Qzp0jU7YSU/s400/blogger-image--1084269938.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;25%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for a healthy recipe? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>seasonal apple crisp pre-workout snack</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/apple-crisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/apple-crisp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s meal is a seasonal pre-workout packed with carbs and protein to give you that extra kick during your workout. For those of you who love utilizing the flavors of fall, freshly picked apples go perfectly with this quick, 15 minute snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ZTPdzBiK0EE/Vg_ibGMaiUI/AAAAAAAAAtA/uGcVwC4DcXE/s400/blogger-image--1529127191.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3OTlWg-O6Qs/Vg_ktoDyBNI/AAAAAAAAAtU/QsppF6NUMDE/s400/NutritionLabel-2.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150-180g Apple- typically the size of a medium apple (Whichever kind you prefer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Old Fashioned Oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150g Danon Greek Yogurt, Vanilla (Feel free to substitute your favorite flavor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stevia/Truvia to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bowls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; hspace=40 src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HuHUjejcQKY/Vg_nJb7l-VI/AAAAAAAAAtg/rhFtNeLJodY/s320/blogger-image-543035887.jpg&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add oats to small pot. Fill with ~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of water (almond milk or milk) or until the top of the oats are covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir in cinnamon and stevia/Truvia, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove to high heat and let the oats/seasonings mixture heat until the oats start to bubble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to low and stir the oat mixture. This process is similar to cooking oatmeal on the stove.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop up the apple into cubes. Feel free to remove the peel, if desired. I leave the peel on for extra crunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix in &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the apples with the oatmeal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of the apples and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the Vanilla Greek Yogurt to the bottom of a heat-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The oatmeal/apples mixture is fully cooked when the apples are soft and 80%+ of the water has been absorbed by the oats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the oatmeal/apples mixture into the heat-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top with the remaining &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; apples and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the Vanilla Greek Yogurt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with cinnamon and stevia/Truvia, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for Meal of the Week? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>healthy mini chicken pot pies</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/chicken-pot-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 12:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/chicken-pot-pies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you craving this classic taste of Fall, and your macros don&amp;rsquo;t allow for the traditional chicken pot pie recipe, give this a try! For under 300 calories, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a tasty dose of this deliciously seasonal, healthy chicken pot pie made with fresh ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the Meal Prep Series, this week&amp;rsquo;s meal is Mini Chicken Pot Pies (adopted and modified from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitnessmagazine.com/recipe/chicken/mini-chicken-pot-pies/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; original recipe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-byQuTHmmeKo/VgdRcPo_jzI/AAAAAAAAArY/ed78Y2tvwDo/s640/blogger-image-1255513652.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ZUqU8qzH4Ak/VgdTQEErGHI/AAAAAAAAArs/rFrMx5S_OoA/s320/NutritionLabel.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80g yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70g celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g baby carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups Reduced-Sodium Chicken Broth (not all will be consumed; mainly used for cooking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Bothouse Farms Italian Vinaigrette Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Grands Jr Golden Layer Buttermilk Biscuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 serving frozen veggies of your choice (I chose Kroger&amp;rsquo;s Recipe Secrets - Vegetable Soup, Mix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 oz Chicken Breast (Raw measure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Stick, Fat-Free Cooking Spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 single-serve oven-safe bowls or ramekins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baking Rack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove on high and coat large pot with non-stick spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop up onion, celery, and carrots. Mix with seasonings in the large pot. Cook until onions are browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to medium. Add chicken broth and Italian Vinaigrette to large pot and let simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash and prep chicken breast. Cut into smaller pieces and add to large pot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let simmer ~10 minutes or until the chicken is fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add frozen veggies. Cook until completely thawed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce stove to low heat. Remove chicken and add to a separate bowl. Shred if desired using a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the kitchen scale, find the total weight of chicken and divide by 4. This will be the serving size per mini chicken pie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chicken and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of veggies to the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ~1-2 tbsp of broth to the bowls. Season with more garlic, black pepper, italian seasonings, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flatten and mold the 4 Grands Jr Biscuits to fit the top of each of the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat the top of the biscuits with a small amount (~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp) of left over broth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle top of biscuits with more seasonings if desired. (I coated with some garlic powder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake for 8-12 minutes or until the biscuits are fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes and enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But wait …what do I do with the left over broth?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be left with ~90% of the chicken broth. Instead of throwing it out, I used it to cook the rest of my chicken as a part of my #MealPrepSunday. To do this, I added 3 raw chicken breasts and the chicken broth to a small crock pot and cooked on high for roughly 3 hours. Once the chicken was fully cooked, I removed it from the broth and shredded it down. I put 2 servings of chicken back into the crock pot with 2 servings of frozen veggies and 1 serving of tortellini to make a soup (YUM!). I let this cook for another 30-60 minutes on low heat. I packed up the remaining shredded chicken in a tupperware for use throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for Meal of the Week? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>