<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/topics/recovery-series/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/topics/recovery-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a 10-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:54:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we overlook the cool-down routine as much as our warm-up routine. I think it has something to do with wanting to get to the exciting part of the workout and both warm-ups and cool-downs are &amp;ldquo;boring.&amp;rdquo; I used to think that these routines were a waste of time, but that was before I knew just how much benefit they provide the body. This article explains a quick, ten-minute recovery routine that you can do practically anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you will need the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopwatch or Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair or something about 2-feet off the ground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a circuit of four different exercises that are best performed post-workout or at a time when you want to &amp;ldquo;relax.&amp;rdquo; They are taken from the exercises recommended by Maraynn Berry&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/video/5-simple-exercises-to-eliminate-neck-pain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Simple Exercises to Eliminate Neck Pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be experiencing neck pain in order to do these exercises! I find that this condensed version allows my body to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;relax&amp;rdquo; especially after a heavy lifting session. This routine is especially beneficial for desk jockies because it promotes proper posture from the neck, through the shoulders, down to the hips and adductors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each exercise in this routine, you will hold the position for two minutes. There are five exercises total, therefore, ten-minutes of &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; time for this routine. I recommend you read through the exercise, and then give them a try! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-1-u-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 1:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Back:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay on the floor with your legs propped up on a chair or object 2-feet tall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your legs should be at a 90-degree angle to your hips. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-2-u-static-scapular-extension&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 2:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Scapular Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start on all fours, ensuring that your wrists are directly under your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk your hands about 6-inches in front of the starting position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift your hips forward so that your weight and shoulders are over your wrists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your elbows straight and allow your shoulder blades to sink down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your head hang. Release any tension in your neck and mouth. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;It will be challenging, but try to hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; While it seems counter-intuitive to hold this position, since we spend most of our day in a slouched over position, this exercise moves the scapula into extension, promoting realignment to the shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-3-u-repeat-exercise-1-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 3:&lt;/u&gt;  Repeat Exercise 1, Static Back.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-4-u-wall-hold&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 4:&lt;/u&gt;  Wall Hold:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit on the floor with your back and head against a wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull your shoulder blades together and down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest your legs straight out in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flex your quads. Flex your feet towards your body. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-5-u-static-adductor-frog&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 5:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Adductor (Frog):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start in a seated position with the bottoms of your feet touching each other (a.k.a. butterfly position). Make sure that your feet are aligned with the center of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lie back and relax every muscle in your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your arms at a 45-degree angle to your sides with your palms facing up. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this routine a try after your next workout or before bed. After a week of doing this routine, it&amp;rsquo;ll become second-nature and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it helps with recovery and &amp;ldquo;resets&amp;rdquo; your posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does your cool-down routine look like? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Recover with this easy, 10-minute routine www.queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; with your tips and tricks for improving recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources-for-prehab-rehab-and-recovery&#34;&gt;Additional Resources for Prehab, Rehab, and Recovery:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/au/learn/banish-pain-permanently-basic-drills-to-repair-your-posture?page=0,0&#34;&gt;Banish Pain Permanently by Maryann Berry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uprightposturefitness.com/sitting-floor-exercise/&#34;&gt;Sitting Floor Exercise by Upright Posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/egoscue-method/&#34;&gt;Egoscue Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McKenzie Method / MDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>