<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/topics/recovery-series/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/topics/recovery-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>a 10-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:54:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we overlook the cool-down routine as much as our warm-up routine. I think it has something to do with wanting to get to the exciting part of the workout and both warm-ups and cool-downs are &amp;ldquo;boring.&amp;rdquo; I used to think that these routines were a waste of time, but that was before I knew just how much benefit they provide the body. This article explains a quick, ten-minute recovery routine that you can do practically anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you will need the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopwatch or Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair or something about 2-feet off the ground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a circuit of four different exercises that are best performed post-workout or at a time when you want to &amp;ldquo;relax.&amp;rdquo; They are taken from the exercises recommended by Maraynn Berry&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/video/5-simple-exercises-to-eliminate-neck-pain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Simple Exercises to Eliminate Neck Pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be experiencing neck pain in order to do these exercises! I find that this condensed version allows my body to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;relax&amp;rdquo; especially after a heavy lifting session. This routine is especially beneficial for desk jockies because it promotes proper posture from the neck, through the shoulders, down to the hips and adductors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each exercise in this routine, you will hold the position for two minutes. There are five exercises total, therefore, ten-minutes of &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; time for this routine. I recommend you read through the exercise, and then give them a try! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-1-u-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 1:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Back:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay on the floor with your legs propped up on a chair or object 2-feet tall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your legs should be at a 90-degree angle to your hips. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-2-u-static-scapular-extension&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 2:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Scapular Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start on all fours, ensuring that your wrists are directly under your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk your hands about 6-inches in front of the starting position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift your hips forward so that your weight and shoulders are over your wrists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your elbows straight and allow your shoulder blades to sink down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your head hang. Release any tension in your neck and mouth. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;It will be challenging, but try to hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; While it seems counter-intuitive to hold this position, since we spend most of our day in a slouched over position, this exercise moves the scapula into extension, promoting realignment to the shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-3-u-repeat-exercise-1-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 3:&lt;/u&gt;  Repeat Exercise 1, Static Back.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-4-u-wall-hold&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 4:&lt;/u&gt;  Wall Hold:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit on the floor with your back and head against a wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull your shoulder blades together and down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest your legs straight out in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flex your quads. Flex your feet towards your body. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-5-u-static-adductor-frog&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 5:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Adductor (Frog):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start in a seated position with the bottoms of your feet touching each other (a.k.a. butterfly position). Make sure that your feet are aligned with the center of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lie back and relax every muscle in your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your arms at a 45-degree angle to your sides with your palms facing up. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this routine a try after your next workout or before bed. After a week of doing this routine, it&amp;rsquo;ll become second-nature and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it helps with recovery and &amp;ldquo;resets&amp;rdquo; your posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does your cool-down routine look like? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Recover with this easy, 10-minute routine www.queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; with your tips and tricks for improving recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources-for-prehab-rehab-and-recovery&#34;&gt;Additional Resources for Prehab, Rehab, and Recovery:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/au/learn/banish-pain-permanently-basic-drills-to-repair-your-posture?page=0,0&#34;&gt;Banish Pain Permanently by Maryann Berry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uprightposturefitness.com/sitting-floor-exercise/&#34;&gt;Sitting Floor Exercise by Upright Posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/egoscue-method/&#34;&gt;Egoscue Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McKenzie Method / MDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combat office slouch</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-being-such-a-slouch&#34;&gt;Stop being such a slouch!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and work a desk job, it is easy to turn into a slouched over mess. With all the hype out there about &amp;ldquo;sitting is the new smoking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prehab is rehab&amp;rdquo;, I have decided to create a list of the most realistic exercises that you can do at the office to help improve posture, mobility, and overall happiness. &lt;em&gt;And hopefully prevent you from looking like a stupid fool, rolling around on the floor next to your cubical.&lt;/em&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the advice I&amp;rsquo;m providing here is based off of my personal experience with chronic low back, hip, neck, and shoulder pain, and does not substitute or replace medical advice. These tricks have worked for me based on meeting with a physical therapist for my own mobility/stability issues; however, everybody is different, and it&amp;rsquo;s best to seek an opinion from your doctor prior to trying a rehab/stretch/strength program like the one I am about to outline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to working a full-time desk job, I was a college student. When people think college, they may think parties, alcohol, weight gain, and craziness; however, the reality of my college experience was hair-pulling, weight loss, walking everywhere, and craziness. Once I found myself sitting at the same desk for hours on end with little reason to move other than to get water or use the bathroom, I realized I was becoming a slouched over mess. [Cue the mobility issues, back and hip pain.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;neat&amp;rdquo; little thing about exercise: you can work out for an hour—maybe even two hours—a day, but if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/health-medicine/its-not-your-metabolism-its-your-neat-thats-stopping-your-fat-loss&#34;&gt;inactive for 8-15 hours a day, then exercise less effective&lt;/a&gt;. So why is that so “neat” you may ask? Well it has to do with &lt;strong&gt;N.E.A.T or non-exercise activity thermogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;, aka “what you do when you’re not exercising, which burns calories to keep you alive.” So if you put yourself into a lethargic, slumped over position all day long, and think you will have great mobility for your squat session that evening, well good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-prevent-becoming-an-immobile-mess-of-a-human-being&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I prevent becoming an immobile mess of a human being?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer:&lt;/u&gt; get off your butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer explained:&lt;/u&gt; Every 30-45 minutes, get up and perform a series of mobility/stability exercises to counterbalance the poor posture from sitting. Think back to eighth-grade science class where you learned about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/newtlaws/Lesson-4/Newton-s-Third-Law&#34;&gt;Newton’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;. (For you engineers out there, forgive me, this was a very recent topic for y’all). Newton’s Third Law states that for every action force there is a reaction force equal in magnitude and opposite in direction. For example, if you’re sitting in a slouched over position, inducing flexion on your spine, it’d be wise to get up every half hour and do some back bends to induce extension. Refer to the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://teachmeanatomy.info/wp-content/uploads/Terms-of-Movement-Flexion-and-Extension-CC-1024x815.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-15-minute-routine-to-combat-office-slouch&#34;&gt;A 15-minute routine to combat office slouch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a reason why people who live in a constant state of flexion throw their backs out when they pick up a basket of laundry; it’s because they’re inducing extension on a spine that has been molded into the flexion world. It’s time to teach our spines, and other body parts for that matter, what neutral looks like. To do this, I have developed a short list of five exercises that I think are the most effective for resetting the body and prehab for future injuries. You only need therabands/resistance bands to perform all the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you live in the world of &lt;u&gt;extension&lt;/u&gt;, you would probably benefit from &lt;u&gt;flexion&lt;/u&gt; exercises instead of exercises two and three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder W&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end keep your elbows by your sides. Contract your lats and pull the band apart forming a &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; with your arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_G0feLqXA0E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standing back-bends (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Position your feet slightly behind your hips. Place your hands on your low back (or table as shown in the video), and slowly bend backwards. You will feel this stretch in your lower back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjXCgxajrY4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prone Press-ups (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Lie on the floor and place your hands slightly wider than shoulder-width. Contract your lats and press up with your arms. You should feel a stretch in the low back. Exhale at the top of the movement for a deeper low-back stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qCOt_Em11g8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end and hit 6 points to form the shape of a star as shown in the video. Contract your lats and make sure that your shoulders are relaxed and not shrugged up towards your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xTCvBqZz3Bc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bodyweight Squats&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your feet are shoulder-width apart and that you contract your glutes while hinging at the hips. When you come down, try to break just below parallel and come back up. If you feel this in your lower back, you should compare your form to the example in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p3g4wAsu0R4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to perform these exercises every 30-45 minutes (set a timer!) throughout the work day to prevent poor posture and to prehab the body from potential future injuries. Hopefully, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to hit the gym, your body is already primed for the upcoming movements and you&amp;rsquo;ll be less stiff and sore afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these exercises a try, and let me know if they work for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>turn your injury into an opportunity</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 21:44:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;30&#34; src=&#34;http://spotmegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/@physio_fit.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Injuries happen quite often in fitness and athletics in general–whether it is a minor case of the shin-splints or a broken bone, athletes are prone to getting hurt. Somehow it has become part of a vicious cycle; a known part of the game. But does it have to be this way? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Over the past four years of my fit lifestyle I have managed to train my way through and around injuries. One of the key things I have learned is that many training-related injuries can be prevented. It all comes down to knowing your body and how it performs. There’s a difference between “cry-baby pain” and pain you should take seriously. Listening to your body is a true way to gauge this line. If your gut-instinct tells you to take a step back, then you should probably listen to it! Push through it, and you could miss more than a few reps or even steps in the long run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay, so now you’re telling me to just stop training when the alarm sounds?&lt;/em&gt;
Actually, I’m suggesting an alternative method, selective training. If you feel shin-splints coming on and you need to perform HIIT as part of your training regime, then stop the treadmill work. Switch to HIIT on a rower or elliptical machine. Even better, use this opportunity to go outside and ride a bicycle. Be the badass on a bike performing 1 minute of hard-out pedaling and 30 seconds of leisurely, relaxed riding. Turn your injury into a chance to rest that body part. There are over 500 muscles in the human body; if one of them needs a break, then switch your attention to the other 499-plus muscles that need work. Read on for some more great tips to turning an injury into an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;switch-to-body-weight-exercises&#34;&gt;Switch to Body-Weight Exercises&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel an injury coming on, switch to body weight exercises for a couple of days. This will reduce the stress placed on your body from lifting heavy. Plus, you will still get a great workout! Body-weight exercises allow you to concentrate on supporting your own weight through balance and endurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for more of a challenge? Try completing 500 reps of common body-weight exercises such as planks, pullups, sit-ups, and push-ups with a 7 minute cutoff time for each. Trust me, it’s more difficult than it sounds! You could also try switching it up and do multiple rounds of tabata: 20 seconds of reps followed by 10 seconds of rest for a total of 4 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-cardio-training&#34;&gt;Alternative Cardio Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardio doesn’t have to be about running, biking, or elliptical work. Use this opportunity to go for a long hike, try out rock climbing, or even pick up boxing. Challenge yourself by trying something new. Even kayaking can be a great cardio workout! Be creative and think about opportunities you can take part in rather than worry about opportunities you’re missing out on due to an injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rehab-and-stretch&#34;&gt;Rehab and Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times athletes get injured, go to physical therapy, finish up the sessions and then stop doing the exercises. I’ll admit, I’m not as proactive when it comes to doing the stretching and prep work before a workout. If you are given exercises by a physical therapist, be sure to do them! Stretching is a great way to prepare your body for the stresses of lifting. It promotes oxygen flow to the muscles and will help loosen you up beforehand. Use this time to throw in your favorite playlist and get pumped for the workout!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shoulder-related-injury&#34;&gt;Shoulder-related Injury?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem. After a few rounds of surgery to remove a bone mass between my scapula and rib cage, I’ve become more aware of alternative shoulder and upper body exercises. Typically when I’m working shoulders and chest I will modify the flat bench press to an incline press just so that my shoulders aren’t under so much stress. I still get the added benefit of a dumbbell or barbell press just without the added tension. If you have another sensitive area from previous injuries, modified exercises always help and can get you on track to where you want to be without stopping a plan entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-down-and-heat-up&#34;&gt;Ice Down and Heat Up!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this recovery period as an excuse to relax with a heating pad or ice pack. Whether you like ice or heat, just relaxing after your workout with one or the other can help your muscles start to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know that sometimes injuries are much more complex than a little case of the shin-splints. In complex injuries, you need to use your best judgement. Don’t push yourself to the point where you’re physically disintegrating. You’re training with a purpose. You want to become a better, more polished version of yourself. So instead of dropping all fitness entirely when an injury strikes, strike back and play smart. If upper body is injured, work legs. Go for a jog. Keep up your cardio. Do some active stretching and rehabilitation exercises. Be mindful of yourself and your goals, and take the time to turn your injury into an opportunity for future prevention and a successful recovery. Fitness is probably the greatest game composed of lifting, nutrition, and competition. Take care of yourself by doing the recommended stretches in preparation for your training routine. Your body will thank you for it afterwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Previously published on December 3, 2014 on SpotMeGirl.com&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>