<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/life-update/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/life-update/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I Fell Off The Wagon</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/i-fell-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 11:55:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/i-fell-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sometimes other things in your life take priority.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ve been absent on the queenflex blog for over a month, so this article is meant to fill you in on some life updates and changes to the queenflex blog. I&amp;rsquo;m back for the next 90-days with some exciting news. READ ON!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;competing-the-time-is-now&#34;&gt;Competing - &lt;em&gt;The Time is NOW&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;March 5th is the first day of the Alphalete 90-day challenge. Because this challenge was announced the end of January, I decided to stop my 20-week cut and use the 6 weeks leading up to the challenge to perform a reverse diet. I&amp;rsquo;d say that my reverse diet was very successful. I managed to maintain my weight of about 153 throughout the 6 weeks, while adding in addtional calories. My training has also been pretty successful. I completed two cycles of 5/3/1 and have transitioned into a hybrid-TLS &amp;amp; 5/3/1 program. Essentially, I am performing one to two compound movements at the beginning of my workout followed by a few isolation movements. I plan to continue this program throughout the 90-day challenge. The only thing I will be changing is my diet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-nutrition-weight&#34;&gt;Current Nutrition &amp;amp; Weight&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I am maintaining on ~2050 calories. 154g Protein, 197g Carb, 78g Fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 1 of the challenge (starting tomorrow!), I will be dieting on 1650 calories. 154g Protein, 170g Carb, 35g Fat. I&amp;rsquo;ll be weighing myself about 3-4x/wk and adjusting these numbers based on how much weight I&amp;rsquo;m losing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I track my macros using MyFitnessPal. Feel free to add me here ==&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/profile/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;StrongLizLifts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I weighed in yesterday at 154.8 lb and will re-weigh myself tomorrow for the start of this challenge. It is my goal to &lt;strong&gt;lose 23-25 lbs&lt;/strong&gt; during the 90-days and hit the low-130&amp;rsquo;s while &lt;strong&gt;maintaining&lt;/strong&gt; as much muscle as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s my progress ticker. I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding it to the home page during this 90-day challenge.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/weight-loss-ticker&#34;&gt;&lt;img border=&#34;0&#34; src=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/ticker/show/6600/3117/66003117.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-new-series-is-born&#34;&gt;A New Series is Born&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am concluding the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1 series&amp;rdquo; and starting a new series to go along with the 90-day Alphalete challenge. If you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar with Alphalete, or Christian Guzman (founder), this challenge was created from previous &amp;ldquo;Summer Shredding&amp;rdquo; challenges that Christian completed over the past few years. This year the goal is to motivate and challenge others to complete the Summer Shred with Chrisitan and the best &amp;ldquo;transformations&amp;rdquo; will win prizes. When Christian made the announcement, he mentioned vlogging &lt;u&gt;90 videos in 90 days&lt;/u&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;(What a commitment!)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan is to document my progress at least once a week with a new article under the honorary QFB series, &amp;ldquo;Summer Shredding.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the rough outline of things I&amp;rsquo;m going to be tracking and updating you on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My current weight / lowest weigh-in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bodyfat percentage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Measurements (waist, hips, thighs, chest, arms)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macros (&amp;amp; if adjustments were made)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Challenges, Successes, and Life Updates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I may throw in a few audio/video clips along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty excited to start this challenge because I haven&amp;rsquo;t competed in a challenge like this since 2014. I had pretty decent results from that challenge; however, this time my goal is to get as lean as possible for the sake of getting lean. I want to place top 10 in this challenge, and that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I set out to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Watch out Christian Guzman, I&amp;rsquo;ll be bringing on the shreds, too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks queenflexers for the support. As always, drop a comment if you have any questions, and I&amp;rsquo;ll update you on my progress throughout these next 90-days!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>