<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/topics/life-on-5/3/1/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/topics/life-on-5/3/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>you don&#39;t know squat if you don&#39;t squat</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:10:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article 2 of the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series is brought to you by legs day. You don&amp;rsquo;t know squat, if you don&amp;rsquo;t squat! This article takes a step into my day, my workout, and my nutrition. Click to read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rise-and-grind-it-s-legs-day-dec-6&#34;&gt;rise and grind, it&amp;rsquo;s legs day! - Dec 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, today was an early start. I woke up at about 5:10am for a 6am shift start. I arrived into the office and was able to grind out a lot of logistics for various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on. And, it turns out I will be heading to Las Vegas in a MONTH for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ces.tech/&#34;&gt;Consumer Electronics Show (CES)&lt;/a&gt;! Tonight, I have a squat workout scheduled and as you may or may not know, I have a love-hate relationship with squats. While I think squats are key to having a solid and functional fitness foundation, form is critical to being able to move a lot of weight. I am still trying to perfect my squat form, and it&amp;rsquo;s been challenging returning to a &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; squat from a lower-back injury. Ever since sustaining the initial injury, my squats have taken a toll in terms of how much weight I can actually tollerate. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that 5/3/1 will help me take a few steps back, adjust my form, my breathing, and my technique, and ultimately allow me to get stronger. I thing the higher-volume nature of &amp;ldquo;Boring but Big&amp;rdquo; is just what I need to get confident and comfortable with performing the squatting movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trying-so-hard-to-hit-those-macros&#34;&gt;trying so hard to hit those macros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk nutrition for a little bit. I mentioned yesterday how difficult it&amp;rsquo;s been for me to hit my macros (155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats), lately. If you had asked me a year ago, I&amp;rsquo;d be able to hit those numbers at 3PM if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t careful. So I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s up. My appetite has disappeared! Tracking my food has seemed to help, because no matter what I want to eat, it fits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gluten-free diet has been really great so far in terms of how I feel and how I&amp;rsquo;ve been digesting. I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed too many changes with my skin, but it&amp;rsquo;s only been a few days, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure it takes time. The downfall with being gluten-free is that I feel so limited with what I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; eat. It&amp;rsquo;s a choice to eat this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m doing it because I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have a greater health benefit long-term. I just think I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to find other carbohydrates that are gluten-free and low in sugar (&lt;em&gt;good luck&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some foods that are becoming staples to my diet right now are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chex/GF cereal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweet Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean ground beef (90-96% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whey Protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corn tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60% dark chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; salad mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pickles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to mix it up and have a bit more variety, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be limited when it comes to staying gluten-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-and-feeling-under-the-weather-dec-7-and-8&#34;&gt;health and feeling &amp;ldquo;under the weather&amp;rdquo; - Dec 7 and 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last article I spoke a lot about how &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; this routine was going to be. Unfortunately, that was before I got sick. So these past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling off a headcold, therefore, I didn&amp;rsquo;t train on Wednesday or Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I will get back to the gym on Friday for Bench Press, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to depend on how I feel and how much food I&amp;rsquo;m eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=Life always throws a monkey-wrench. Just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans. @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;Life always throws a monkey-wrench, and just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to just go with it, and make the most of what you set out to do. I want to nip this cold in the bud, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing everything I can to take care of myself and make a 80-90% recovery before going back to the gym. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about being &amp;ldquo;tough&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo; or whatever when it comes to training while sick. I personally think that it&amp;rsquo;s dumb to train when you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling well. Your mind will be focused on how terrible you feel rather than focusing on perfecting your form. Rest up, get over the cold or illness, and the gym will be there when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return.
The other part of training while sick is that your body is already trying to &amp;ldquo;fight&amp;rdquo; off the illness. When you throw in additional stressors, such as lack of sleep, lifting, etc., it makes it difficult for your body to get rid of it. I think this is why people end up with these &amp;ldquo;lingering&amp;rdquo; colds for weeks and months. They don&amp;rsquo;t give their bodies&amp;rsquo; the breaks they need in order to see full recovery. So, do yourself a favor and sleep!
For me, I notice the onset of an illness when I don&amp;rsquo;t get 7-8 hours of sleep consistently, and I am working 10+ hour days, and working out, and doing too much. So the illness is an alarm telling me &amp;ldquo;hey! you need to take a break!&amp;rdquo; So tonight&amp;rsquo;s chest workout is still tentative. It&amp;rsquo;s about 9:30am here, and I have many hours to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m going to train tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut this article off here, but thank you, if you have read this far, and I will be back with another article on Day 3 of 5/3/1, whether that is tonight or this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question or comment? Find me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>