<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/topics/life-on-5/3/1/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/topics/life-on-5/3/1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>reflecting on 2016 &amp; upcoming fitness plans</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/reflecting-on-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 11:13:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/reflecting-on-2016/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The holidays have come and gone and it&amp;rsquo;s time to get in the right headspace for 2017. New Year&amp;rsquo;s is a time to reflect on the past year and gear up for the future. And while 2016, may have been short-lived, I know I still have many more goals that I want to accomplish that have been sitting in the &amp;ldquo;in progress&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;incomplete&amp;rdquo; bucket for a couple years now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fitness is one of those &amp;ldquo;incomplete&amp;rdquo; goals.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt; For the most part, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it will ever be complete; however, I want to push myself into being the best version of myself possible, both physically and mentally. I think that&amp;rsquo;s why this series is so important to me. I want to have a record of the journey and be able to capture not only the successes, but the failures, and day-to-day struggles of working towards a goal. So starting Jan 1 through May 20, I will be undergoing the longest intentional cut of my fitness lifestyle. The real goal is to FINALLY get to 19% bodyfat, and really challenge myself to get as lean as possible for the sake of getting lean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, I&amp;rsquo;m going to document it for you guys right here on queenflex.com. Everything from the weigh-ins to the diet to the macros to the workouts. The crappy days and the record-breaking days. Everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So what does this mean for the 5/3/1 series, you might ask?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s going to continue through the last week of January, and then I will start up another series (title to be determined).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also in the process of updating my website to attract greater readership with the goal of inspiring others to make the changes in their lives that they&amp;rsquo;ve been avoiding for months and years. There&amp;rsquo;s lots of people who do that already on YouTube, but I find that there aren&amp;rsquo;t too many old school &amp;ldquo;blogs&amp;rdquo; dedicated to posts about going through a fitness journey like this. And if there are, or you have one of them, please drop a comment below! I&amp;rsquo;d love to connect with you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-intent-for-this-cut&#34;&gt;my intent for this cut&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who know me, or follow this blog, on any given day, I sit around 23-25% bodyfat with the lowest I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been at 21%. So for the most part, I have a pretty &amp;ldquo;average&amp;rdquo; frame. Sub-20% is going to look pretty crazy for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2016 was a year of rebuilding and returning to lifting after a lower back injury. While I never intended to put on a lot of weight, I was able to get up to 158 lbs (my highest scale weight, ever), while staying 25% bodyfat. I suspect I was able to put on about 7 lbs of lean mass this year, which is &lt;u&gt; really great&lt;/u&gt;. My goal weight for this cut is &lt;strong&gt;134 lbs at 19%&lt;/strong&gt;. I am confident that 20 weeks will give me plenty of time to get there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-case-you-want-to-see-the-numbers-for-this-cut&#34;&gt;in case you want to see the numbers for this cut&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting weight: ~153-155 lb &lt;br&gt;
Goal weight:      134 lb &lt;br&gt;
Weight lost:       19-21 lb &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting bodyfat: 25% &lt;br&gt;
Goal bodyfat: 19% &lt;br&gt;
Bodyfat lost: 6%&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over 20 weeks ~ 1 lb per week with &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt; of that being fat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now staying in a deficit for 20 weeks will be more of a mind-game than anything. The workouts won&amp;rsquo;t be as tough as consistently hitting my deficit macros, water, and fiber intake. And, of course, the weekly weigh-ins and measurements have always been a head-game for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other consideration for this cut, is if I reach my goal of 134 at 19% before 20 weeks (say around 16 weeks), then I will determine at that time, if I want to continue staying in a deficit. For me, I get pretty delusional/weak/unhappy at around the 10 week mark. However, with that said, based on my last formal cut, 12-16 weeks is really when my physique will shine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-opportunity-to-compete&#34;&gt;the opportunity to compete&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The really cool thing, is if my physique is on point at around 12-16 weeks, I may be able to compete in the Memorial Day weekend bikini/figure show in Bloomfield, CT. That would be pretty crazy cool, right?! A lot to look forward to in 2017. There are a couple more shows scheduled for summer 2017 in CT, so it&amp;rsquo;s possible I&amp;rsquo;ll be ready for one of them, if not the one in May. But for now, the true focus is getting really lean while trying to maintain my strength as best as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get started and to share this journey with you. As always thanks for your readership, and I&amp;rsquo;ll be back this week(end) with the next update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drop a comment below or find me on twitter @lizmillerfit!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>holiday weekend &amp; goal setting for the new year</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/holiday-weekend-goal-setting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 18:53:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/holiday-weekend-goal-setting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The holidays are quickly approaching, and this week&amp;rsquo;s training schedule has been very sporadic. While I missed two training sessions (Wednesday and Thursday), I am hitting deadlifts today! The fitness lifestyle has to be dynamic, and you have to be both accountable, committed, and flexible. If you&amp;rsquo;re in it for the long-haul, this is an important consideration to have, so that you aren&amp;rsquo;t frustrated with yourself when life tends to get in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;9-20am-dec-23&#34;&gt;9:20am | Dec 23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been awake for about two hours now&amp;hellip;cleaning up the blog and developing content for this post. As I said in the article preview, I missed a few training sessions this week. Since I can&amp;rsquo;t go backwards, I plan on getting to the gym around &lt;del&gt;10:30am&lt;/del&gt; 1:30pm for a deadlift session at the Hartford YMCA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;deadlift session&lt;/strong&gt; is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;warm-up&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/warm-up-routine/&#34;&gt;my warm-up routine&lt;/a&gt;, then deadlifts at
95 x 5 | 120 x 5 | 145 x 3 |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;5/3/1&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt;
170 x 3 | 190 x 3 | 215 x 3+ |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;boring but big&lt;/u&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
deadlifts: 5 x 10 at 120 &lt;br&gt;
hanging leg raises: 5 x 10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you who may not know, I have my own set of warm-up exercises I like to perform prior to the barbell warm-up sets. I&amp;rsquo;ve written a separate post on this &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/warm-up-routine/&#34;&gt;warm-up routine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; as well as my &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;10-minute cool-down routine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. While warming up and cooling down are &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo;, they are necessary to a successful training program. Warm-ups routines, when designed and executed properly, prevent injuries. Cool-down routines, promote recovery. Over time, injury prevention and proper recovery will help you get to the next level with your training. &lt;br&gt;&lt;em&gt;So just do them.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;11-30am-dec-23&#34;&gt;11:30am | Dec 23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;goal-setting-and-a-look-at-2017&#34;&gt;goal-setting and a look at 2017&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a tendency to get sidetracked or distracted while I&amp;rsquo;m on a training program. That is why in 2017 I want to focus on being more mindful and living in the present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#1: Do a little &lt;em&gt;less&lt;/em&gt; planning of the future, and a little &lt;em&gt;more&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;commitment to now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I also want to take my strength and hypertrophy training to the next level. By that, I want to achieve &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; for all of the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#2: Hit the &amp;ldquo;elite&amp;rdquo; weight targets for my current weight. At a bodyweight of ~150 lb, this means a 1RM of 168 lb for bench, 237 lb for squat, 303 lb for deadlift, and 100 lb for overhead press.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mar 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bench: 130 | Squat: 185 | Deadlift: 245 | Press: 70 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bench: 145 | Squat: 205 | Deadlift: 260 | Press: 80 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sept 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bench: 158 | Squat: 225 | Deadlift: 280 | Press: 90 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dec 2017:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt; Bench: 168 | Squat: 237 | Deadlift: 303 | Press: 100 &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Body recomposition/fat loss always makes my list. I think the biggest reason why it&amp;rsquo;s been an &amp;ldquo;incomplete&amp;rdquo; goal for all these years, is my lack of consistency with diet and lack of programming my nutrition to complement my training goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;#3. This year, I want to work on being &lt;strong&gt;more consistent&lt;/strong&gt; with my nutrition and &lt;em&gt;train to match my goals&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what the &lt;strong&gt;first half of 2016&lt;/strong&gt; will look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;January: finish up 5/3/1 (strength block)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February - March: body recomp (blended hypertrophy-strength)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;April - June: Cut for 10-12 weeks (hypertrophy training)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as I &lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; to start cutting in January, I think it&amp;rsquo;s too soon to do so. I&amp;rsquo;d rather wait and put more weight on my lifts and start cutting early spring. Then if I decide I want to continue cutting in July (make it a 16 week cut), I&amp;rsquo;ll have the added time to do so. (Somehow cutting and summertime go hand-in-hand, so why not?) Plus, this go-around, I want to end up being ~18% and down about 15-20lbs (~130-135). Ideally, I want to set up a quicker, 8-10 week cut, and that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a possibility down the road, but for now, I&amp;rsquo;ll factor in 10-12 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-training-more-food&#34;&gt;food, training, more food&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;pre-workout-nutrition&#34;&gt;pre-workout nutrition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I planned to train fasted today (and I like training fasted), I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get to the gym for 10:30am, and my stomach was very grumbly around 11am. Today&amp;rsquo;s pre-workout meal consisted of 5g of ON Gold Standard BCAA&amp;rsquo;s and a bowl of 1c. cinnamon chex with ~5oz of plain greek yogurt, 8g natural peanut butter, and 1/4c. unsweetened vanilla almond milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;hitting-deadlifts-at-my-old-gym&#34;&gt;hitting deadlifts at my old gym&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Downtown Hartford YMCA brings back a lot of lifting/fitness memories. It&amp;rsquo;s where I had horrible back pain, some of my heaviest deadlifts, and good workouts with good people. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I was able to hit deadlifts there today. &lt;strong&gt;PSA: I hit 215 for 3!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-smile-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; Even though it felt &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo;, I think I need to get used to holding &amp;ldquo;heavier&amp;rdquo; weights. That&amp;rsquo;ll come with time and strategic training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;6-50pm-dec-23&#34;&gt;6:50pm | Dec 23&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;post-workout-nutrition&#34;&gt;post-workout nutrition&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not a &lt;strong&gt;huge&lt;/strong&gt; fan of supplements because most of them are unnecessary and expensive; however, you can read my &lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;mini guide on supplementation&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; to help determine which supplements might be beneficial for you. Typically, I will take 5g of creatine, 3g of fish oil, and 5000iu of vitamin D post-workout, &lt;em&gt;if I remember&lt;/em&gt;. Which lately, hasn&amp;rsquo;t been happening. I know this year I&amp;rsquo;m stressing consistency, so I&amp;rsquo;ll add that to my list of things to be more consistent with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After deadlifts, I like to eat &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of calories (anywhere from 450-800 calories). Mostly because I trained fasted, but also because it tends to be later in the day, and it&amp;rsquo;s much harder for me to eat 1000&amp;rsquo;s of calories after 4pm. So why not?! Today I made a bowl of cream of rice with vanilla greek yogurt, peanut butter, and marshmellow fluff. Pretty odd combo, but it tastes great! For dinner, we had haddock, sweet &amp;amp; white potatoes, and veggies. I plan to eat some more food pre-bed, just to top off my protein and carb macros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate you sticking through this longer article. I will be back tomorrow with a post on my &amp;ldquo;ab routine&amp;rdquo; and some training progress updates. The goal is to hit bench press to catch up from the week I missed while I was sick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come on this 5/3/1 journey&amp;hellip; &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;
As always, feel free to drop a comment or question below!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lifts, food, travels</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/lifts-food-travels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 08:55:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/lifts-food-travels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week has flown by, and I promise you, I haven&amp;rsquo;t forgotten about the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. This is going to be a bit of a longer article recapping my week, some travel, workouts, and food (because, who could forget talking about what they eat during a training program?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just jump to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, I don&amp;rsquo;t even know what happened. It&amp;rsquo;s like I woke up and did a bunch of things, but can&amp;rsquo;t really remember what I did or when I did it. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of how life goes between travelling, working 10+ hour shifts, and of course, the HOLIDAYS! Did I mention we&amp;rsquo;re 5 days out from Christmas?! How did that happen? 2016 was so short-lived. Anyone else feel like we aren&amp;rsquo;t ready for 2017?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing my talk about last week&amp;hellip;let&amp;rsquo;s talk first about training:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-3-1-training-progress&#34;&gt;5/3/1 training progress&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to meet my training plans as mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-3_5-3-1/&#34;&gt;Article 3 - real talk in the real life&lt;/a&gt;, which is awesome considering I just came off a brief cold. Squats still feel &amp;ldquo;weak&amp;rdquo; for me, and as I start to think about my fitness purpose for 2017, I definitely want to make sure I include Squat form and strength to the list of things to accomplish. Saturday morning deadlifts were on point, and I&amp;rsquo;m really looking forward to this weekend&amp;rsquo;s session (back to the good ole Hartford YMCA!). The only sad part about Saturday morning deadlifts is the fact that I am no longer having waffles as part of the post-workout routine. &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/&#34;&gt;You can read more about my efforts in going Gluten Free in the first article.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt; Spoiler Alert:&lt;/u&gt; so far mission Gluten Free has been a &lt;em&gt;failure&lt;/em&gt; for a couple reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My skin is still acne-ridden.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My digestion is all over the place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With that said, I&amp;rsquo;m still going to continue being Gluten Free for another few months, with the hope that my skin and digestive problems will clear up over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-week-s-training-schedule&#34;&gt;this week&amp;rsquo;s training schedule&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to travel Sunday - Tuesday my workouts have been rearranged this week. I&amp;rsquo;m also feeling a spur of mid-to-upper back/low neck stiffness, which is usually a sign that I need to rest and stretch out my neck and shoulders. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that will resolve itself in a few days, as it&amp;rsquo;s pretty gnarly trying to move or &amp;ldquo;crane&amp;rdquo; my neck in multiple directions. (You&amp;rsquo;d be surprised how often you do this in a given day!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what my estimated training plan is for this week:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun - &amp;ldquo;rest&amp;rdquo; / travelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mon - &amp;ldquo;rest&amp;rdquo; / travelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tues - &amp;ldquo;rest&amp;rdquo; / travelling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed - Squats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thurs - Military Press&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fri - Deadlift&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sat - Bench (pending an open gym on Dec 24)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sun - HIIT/Abs at home (Christmas Day)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-look-at-my-lifting-progress-2016&#34;&gt;a look at my lifting progress (2016)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those of you who follow this blog know that I am a HUGE fan of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://queenflex.github.io/links#strongapp&#34;&gt;Strong App&lt;/a&gt;. I just want to take a moment and share with you the progress I&amp;rsquo;ve made on my estimated 1RM for the big 4 during 2016. All weights are measured in pounds, below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;style type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;padding:10px 5px;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;overflow:hidden;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;font-weight:normal;padding:10px 5px;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;overflow:hidden;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-s6z2{text-align:center}
.tg .tg-baqh{text-align:center;vertical-align:top}
&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;table class=&#34;tg&#34; style=&#34;undefined;table-layout: fixed; width: 100%&#34;&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 20%&#34;&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 30%&#34;&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 30%&#34;&gt;
&lt;col style=&#34;width: 20%&#34;&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;th class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;start&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;end&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;th class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;Δ&lt;/th&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;squat&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;90 x 10&lt;br&gt;~120 1RM&lt;br&gt;January&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;130 x 10&lt;br&gt;~174 1RM&lt;br&gt;December&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;+54 lbs&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;12 mos&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;bench&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;85 x 10&lt;br&gt;~113 1RM&lt;br&gt;February&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;115 x 4&lt;br&gt;~125 1RM&lt;br&gt;December&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;+12 lbs&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;11 mos&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;deadlift&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;135 x 12&lt;br&gt;~180 1RM&lt;br&gt;April&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;205 x 10&lt;br&gt;~273 1RM&lt;br&gt;December&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;+93 lbs&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;8 mos&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;press&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;45 x 10&lt;br&gt;~60 1RM&lt;br&gt;February&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-s6z2&#34;&gt;65 x 12&lt;br&gt;~93 1RM&lt;br&gt;December&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td class=&#34;tg-baqh&#34;&gt;+33 lb&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;11 mos&lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t emphasize how much &lt;u&gt; tracking&lt;/u&gt; helps with making &lt;strong&gt;progress&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know where you&amp;rsquo;re starting, how will you know where you&amp;rsquo;re going?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take a look at the Strong App, let me know what you think, and make that effort to log all your workouts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;food-enough-said&#34;&gt;FOOD. &lt;em&gt;enough said&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday and Saturday were packing and prepare for travel days. Sunday through today (Tuesday) were travel across the U.S. (First a short trip to Texas, then to Connecticut to spend time with family.) Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that my diet was far from perfect. Something I want to emphasize here is a common notion of &amp;ldquo;under-eating&amp;rdquo;. When you&amp;rsquo;re on an IIFYM diet, it&amp;rsquo;s really important to actually &lt;u&gt;hit&lt;/u&gt; the macros: not more, not less, but as close to the numbers as possible. Chronically under-eating is certainly a problem I pick up periodically due to shifts in my lifestyle. (The busier I tend to be, the easier it is for me to &amp;ldquo;forget&amp;rdquo; to eat or &amp;ldquo;under-eat&amp;rdquo;.) It&amp;rsquo;s a habit I need to work on breaking, which is why I&amp;rsquo;m going to provide some tips as to how to hit your macros while constantly on-the-go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll start with a brief commentary about airport foods and restaurants, and then shift gears to travelling with already prepared food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;buy-this-food-at-the-airport&#34;&gt;buy &lt;strong&gt;[this]&lt;/strong&gt; food at the airport&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s often easier and more expensive to buy food at the airport rather than bringing it. If you have the financial means to pick something up at the airport, I personally recommend it, for convenience and food safety purposes. &lt;em&gt;(There&amp;rsquo;s nothing worse than trying to eat that smelly, warm chicken that&amp;rsquo;s been mushed in your bag while you&amp;rsquo;re traveling.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some ideas for food choices while you&amp;rsquo;re at the airport. Remember, it&amp;rsquo;s all about hitting your macros, so if it fits, go ahead and eat it. And these tips are most applicable to short-haul flights and not your 8+ hour trips. I&amp;rsquo;ve linked the nutritional information to the restaurant/food name to give you an idea of the calories and macros for each item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;foods&#34;&gt;foods&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/calories/subway-double-chicken-chopped-salad-all-veggies-no-cheese-dressing-350179610&#34;&gt;Subway | Chopped Salad Double Chicken&lt;/a&gt;: Since I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating gluten-free for the past few weeks, I like getting their chopped salad with double chicken and spicy brown mustard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fatsecret.com/Diary.aspx?pa=fjrd&amp;amp;rid=896256&#34;&gt;Pinkberry | Original Tart Yogurt Small&lt;/a&gt;: I always seem to get dehydrated while traveling, so something about this frozen original tart makes me feel refreshed without feeling stuffed. Other than the high sugar content, fro-yo is something I&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally get if it&amp;rsquo;s later in the day, and I have some carb macros to play with.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nutritiondata.self.com/facts/fruits-and-fruit-juices/1809/2&#34;&gt;Any newstand | Fruit: Apples, Bananas&lt;/a&gt;: For shelf-life and longevity, I like getting apples over bananas, but for a quick snack, a banana is a great choice as well. These are great choices for boosting your micronutrients as well as fiber for the day!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/nutrition-facts-calories/quest-bar&#34;&gt;Any newstand | QuestBar/Protein Bars&lt;/a&gt;: I&amp;rsquo;m not a huge fan of protein bars and shakes because I don&amp;rsquo;t find them to taste overly good nor are they overly filling. But if cost is a problem and you want a quick snack, this will do!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;drinks&#34;&gt;drinks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am always dehydrated while I travel, so I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to be sure you pick up a bottle of water and drink it throughout the day! Since you can&amp;rsquo;t bring liquids through airport security, you can either purchase a bottle once you pass the TSA screening, or you can bring an empty waterbottle and have it filled up by a restaurant, bar, fast food place, or water fountain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/calories/zero-ultra-white-monster-energy-drink-drink-378945313?v2=false&#34;&gt;Any newstand | White Monster Energy Zero&lt;/a&gt;: If I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling a hot coffee, I&amp;rsquo;ll grab a cold Monster for the caffeine, and because they taste good! They&amp;rsquo;re relatively expensive at the airport, but I figure the can has two servings and a tall coffee from Starbucks is about the same price per serving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fatsecret.com/calories-nutrition/starbucks/sugar-free-mocha-syrup&#34;&gt;Starbucks | Tall Dark Roast with 2 pumps of SF Mocha&lt;/a&gt;: I wasn&amp;rsquo;t usually a &amp;ldquo;fancy&amp;rdquo; Starbucks drink person, but this one has become a travel favorite because it tastes like hot chocolate with coffee and has all the flavor without all the calories. I&amp;rsquo;ve linked you to the SF Mocha nutrition facts, which for two pumps is about 10 calories! Not too shabby! But of course, if you have the macros to &lt;em&gt;spend&lt;/em&gt;, by all means get a higher caloric drink. &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-smile-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;if-you-re-going-to-meal-prep-before-travelling-this-is-what-you-should-do&#34;&gt;if you&amp;rsquo;re going to meal-prep before travelling, this is what you should do&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook up a batch of protein (chicken, beef) and a batch of carbs (rice, pasta, etc.) and store them in large zip baggies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pack yourself one or two tupperware with lids and cutlery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pack some napkins.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Store inside of a cooler or bag with a small, TSA-approved ice pack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also be sure to call your hotel ahead of time to request a refrigerator and microwave within your room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This method is best performed if you&amp;rsquo;re going to be gone for a certain period of time that you know you need to have meals pre-made or if you&amp;rsquo;re on a prep where all your food has to be accounted for. With all the different restaurants and grocery stores available, it&amp;rsquo;s almost too easy to buy food when you arrive at your destination and make food within your hotel room. Some of my staples for in-room cooking with a microwave are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;carbs:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;oatmeal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minute rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cream of rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microwavable frozen veggies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;microwavable frozen bagels, waffles, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fruits: apples, bananas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;proteins:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;greek yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cottage cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;protein powders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;precooked chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frozen chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;eggs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;fats:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cashews&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your room includes breakfast, there&amp;rsquo;s often cereals, hard boiled eggs, and scrambled eggs! IIFYM is supposed to be a simpler way of maintaining a healthier lifestyle. Don&amp;rsquo;t over-complicate things by avoiding certain foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like this article? Have a question about what to eat while traveling? Leave a comment below or find me on Twitter @lizmillerfit. Until Next One -QFB&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>real talk in the real life</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/real-talk-in-real-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 16:46:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/real-talk-in-real-life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consider this the written version of Jake Owen&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;em&gt;Real Life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever have one of those days where you&amp;rsquo;re like &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;what just happened?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;where&amp;rsquo;s the undo button, ctrl-z!!!!?!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;. Well, today was pretty much that for me. And while my nutrition and my lifting hasn&amp;rsquo;t been on point for any sort of regulated training program, I am still going to continue this series and make up for this &lt;strong&gt;[awful]&lt;/strong&gt; first week of events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe align = &#34;right&#34; hspace = &#34;20&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/O-a4ttJnbBk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excerpt from &lt;em&gt;Real Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Fall real hard, shake off the dirt&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Pray to God, let&amp;rsquo;s make a deal&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I guess it just got real&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;We get real low, we get real high&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It ain&amp;rsquo;t all good, baby, but it&amp;rsquo;s alright&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Real life&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;sunday-dec-11&#34;&gt;sunday, dec 11&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So yesterday, even though I was feeling better, I still wasn&amp;rsquo;t my usual, healthy self, so I missed my 5/3/1 deadlift workout. &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-frown-o&#34; aria-hidden=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; This is real life, so I&amp;rsquo;m not going to say what did happen when it didn&amp;rsquo;t, or what should have happened on some sort of ideal journey. No excuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; src=&#34;https://media.makeameme.org/created/guess-what-day-12xlpu.jpg&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;
It&amp;rsquo;s really unfortunate because I have grown to really &lt;u&gt;love&lt;/u&gt; deadlifts, so missing yesterday&amp;rsquo;s session was a bummer. I planned on making up the session today, but it just didn&amp;rsquo;t happen. I woke up at about 9am, had some coffee, got back in bed, and then woke up at 2:30pm like &lt;em&gt;WHAT?!&lt;/em&gt;. So that&amp;rsquo;s how my day went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m sitting here with you guys writing this up and watching the Packers crush the Seahawks, while listening to Jake Owen&amp;rsquo;s, &lt;em&gt;Real Life&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;moving-forward&#34;&gt;moving forward&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we can&amp;rsquo;t go backwards, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about this upcoming week.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;u&gt;Monday (tomorrow)&lt;/u&gt;, I have a rest day scheduled, but if I&amp;rsquo;m feeling well after work, I plan to do a 20 minute Ab workout followed by a 20 minute HIIT session. If not, then I will go home and rest. Nothing like capitalizing on the extra scheduled day off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Tuesday&lt;/u&gt;, I hit squats! Looks to be pretty similar to last week&amp;rsquo;s split, with the working-set weight at 100 x 3, 115 x 3, and 130 at 3+. My goal is to hit about 15 squats at 130. Following the 5/3/1 squats, I will perform squats for 5 sets of 10 at 70 lbs and then Leg Curls for 5 sets of 10. I will end my workout with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;10-minute cool-down routine&lt;/a&gt; and call it a night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Wednesday&lt;/u&gt;, I have week 2&amp;rsquo;s military press routine, which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; hspace=&#34;30&#34; src=&#34;https://3.bp.blogspot.com/-NLy6s4hTA_w/WE3oWpTVGYI/AAAAAAAADXg/lAGygOu-3hkQZENbQRaoHxmK3_Ym7WlOgCLcB/s1600/military-press-week2.png&#34; width=&#34;25%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;/&gt; &lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Screenshot courtesy of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am planning to use just the barbell (45 lbs) for the accessory 5 x 10, because it&amp;rsquo;s easier, and just more realistic for functional purposes.  My chin-ups need some serious work, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been managing to hit about 10 sets of 5 reps. (Got to start somewhere!). Last week after hitting all 10 sets of chin-ups, I thought my shoulders were going to fall off, so I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that much volume is &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; necessary to get better at chins. I may switch to assisted chin-ups for 5 sets of 10 just to reduce the post-workout soreness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Thursday&lt;/u&gt; is an &amp;ldquo;optional&amp;rdquo; workout day for HIIT and Abs. I will plan to document my HIIT and Abs workouts sometime this week so you have a better understanding of the types of exercises I like to do!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Friday &amp;amp; Saturday&lt;/u&gt; are bench and deadlifts, respectively, and since I missed a 5/3/1 chest and deadlift workout from last Friday and Saturday, I will be completing those workouts using the planned numbers from last week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to come about the end of this week, as we get closer to those days, but there&amp;rsquo;s just an example of what&amp;rsquo;s to come in this &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1 series.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you like this series or want to see particular content, feel free to drop a comment below or tweet me &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt;. Until next time &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com?subject=life on 5/3/1 article 3 comments&#34;&gt;-QFB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>you don&#39;t know squat if you don&#39;t squat</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/you-dont-know-squat-if-you-dont-squat/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:10:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/you-dont-know-squat-if-you-dont-squat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article 2 of the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series is brought to you by legs day. You don&amp;rsquo;t know squat, if you don&amp;rsquo;t squat! This article takes a step into my day, my workout, and my nutrition. Click to read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rise-and-grind-it-s-legs-day-dec-6&#34;&gt;rise and grind, it&amp;rsquo;s legs day! - Dec 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, today was an early start. I woke up at about 5:10am for a 6am shift start. I arrived into the office and was able to grind out a lot of logistics for various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on. And, it turns out I will be heading to Las Vegas in a MONTH for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ces.tech/&#34;&gt;Consumer Electronics Show (CES)&lt;/a&gt;! Tonight, I have a squat workout scheduled and as you may or may not know, I have a love-hate relationship with squats. While I think squats are key to having a solid and functional fitness foundation, form is critical to being able to move a lot of weight. I am still trying to perfect my squat form, and it&amp;rsquo;s been challenging returning to a &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; squat from a lower-back injury. Ever since sustaining the initial injury, my squats have taken a toll in terms of how much weight I can actually tollerate. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that 5/3/1 will help me take a few steps back, adjust my form, my breathing, and my technique, and ultimately allow me to get stronger. I thing the higher-volume nature of &amp;ldquo;Boring but Big&amp;rdquo; is just what I need to get confident and comfortable with performing the squatting movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trying-so-hard-to-hit-those-macros&#34;&gt;trying so hard to hit those macros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk nutrition for a little bit. I mentioned yesterday how difficult it&amp;rsquo;s been for me to hit my macros (155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats), lately. If you had asked me a year ago, I&amp;rsquo;d be able to hit those numbers at 3PM if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t careful. So I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s up. My appetite has disappeared! Tracking my food has seemed to help, because no matter what I want to eat, it fits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gluten-free diet has been really great so far in terms of how I feel and how I&amp;rsquo;ve been digesting. I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed too many changes with my skin, but it&amp;rsquo;s only been a few days, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure it takes time. The downfall with being gluten-free is that I feel so limited with what I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; eat. It&amp;rsquo;s a choice to eat this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m doing it because I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have a greater health benefit long-term. I just think I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to find other carbohydrates that are gluten-free and low in sugar (&lt;em&gt;good luck&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some foods that are becoming staples to my diet right now are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chex/GF cereal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweet Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean ground beef (90-96% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whey Protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corn tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60% dark chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; salad mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pickles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to mix it up and have a bit more variety, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be limited when it comes to staying gluten-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-and-feeling-under-the-weather-dec-7-and-8&#34;&gt;health and feeling &amp;ldquo;under the weather&amp;rdquo; - Dec 7 and 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last article I spoke a lot about how &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; this routine was going to be. Unfortunately, that was before I got sick. So these past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling off a headcold, therefore, I didn&amp;rsquo;t train on Wednesday or Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I will get back to the gym on Friday for Bench Press, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to depend on how I feel and how much food I&amp;rsquo;m eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=Life always throws a monkey-wrench. Just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans. @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;Life always throws a monkey-wrench, and just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to just go with it, and make the most of what you set out to do. I want to nip this cold in the bud, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing everything I can to take care of myself and make a 80-90% recovery before going back to the gym. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about being &amp;ldquo;tough&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo; or whatever when it comes to training while sick. I personally think that it&amp;rsquo;s dumb to train when you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling well. Your mind will be focused on how terrible you feel rather than focusing on perfecting your form. Rest up, get over the cold or illness, and the gym will be there when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return.
The other part of training while sick is that your body is already trying to &amp;ldquo;fight&amp;rdquo; off the illness. When you throw in additional stressors, such as lack of sleep, lifting, etc., it makes it difficult for your body to get rid of it. I think this is why people end up with these &amp;ldquo;lingering&amp;rdquo; colds for weeks and months. They don&amp;rsquo;t give their bodies&amp;rsquo; the breaks they need in order to see full recovery. So, do yourself a favor and sleep!
For me, I notice the onset of an illness when I don&amp;rsquo;t get 7-8 hours of sleep consistently, and I am working 10+ hour days, and working out, and doing too much. So the illness is an alarm telling me &amp;ldquo;hey! you need to take a break!&amp;rdquo; So tonight&amp;rsquo;s chest workout is still tentative. It&amp;rsquo;s about 9:30am here, and I have many hours to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m going to train tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut this article off here, but thank you, if you have read this far, and I will be back with another article on Day 3 of 5/3/1, whether that is tonight or this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question or comment? Find me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/it-shouldnt-be-this-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/it-shouldnt-be-this-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>