<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/it-shouldnt-be-this-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/life-on-531/it-shouldnt-be-this-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>things you should know about fitness in 2016</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 18:00:20 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-hpnB2MhMJMI/V3Pec6UCEMI/AAAAAAAAA-o/xYhk-6vhy-sQ4PytNIg3_y_d1YzXw8uYwCLcB/s1600/five-tips-to-reach-your-fitness-goals.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Here it is, half-way through 2016. Have you stuck to your New Year&amp;rsquo;s Resolutions? Have you lost the 10 pounds you were planning to lose in January? Maybe the summer weather came sooner than you had planned. Well fret no more; here are five things you should know about achieving your fitness goals as we head into the second half of 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-understand-the-bigger-picture&#34;&gt;1) Understand the bigger picture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why does fitness matter to you?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to fit into particular clothes? Do you use gym-time as a method to reduce stress? Do you want to look a certain way? Do you want to live a healthy and happy life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever your reason may be, you need to be honest with yourself and define the bigger picture. While fitness magazines and websites make healthy living seem so amazing and glamorous, you have to know your why. Not their why or my why, yours. After all, fitness and healthy living is an investment to yourself, so you might as well make it about you and the things that you want to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So go ahead, sit down and ask yourself &lt;strong&gt;WHY?&lt;/strong&gt;. Why does fitness and health matter to me? And once you ask yourself &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo; once, go ahead and ask yourself three to four more times. By the fifth &amp;ldquo;why&amp;rdquo;, you should have a pretty good understanding of the bigger picture. Once you know the bigger picture, you can decompose your end goal into a smaller subset of goals. Think of these mini-goals as stepping-stones that will help you get closer to your end goal. This is the most important tip to achieving your fitness goals, so be sure to spend some time really considering what your aspirations are and how you can break those larger goals down into smaller milestones. Once you complete this activity, you will have a better understanding of how to get to where you want to be and can spend time working at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-eat-according-to-your-daily-plans&#34;&gt;2) Eat according to your daily plans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to preface this point with the idea of being realistic and developing a healthy mindset around food and exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is critical that you eat enough food for what you&amp;rsquo;re doing during the day. For example, if you are sitting and watching TV, you will not need as much food versus hitting a workout consisting of heavy squats and deadlifts. So on days you plan to workout longer than an hour or WOD for more than twenty minutes, it&amp;rsquo;s important you fuel your body so that it can perform optimally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few fundamental ideas:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re going through a weight loss cycle, you need to eat fewer calories than your body burns throughout a day. [AKA Caloric Deficit]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to put on weight, you need to eat more calories than your body burns throughout a day. [AKA Caloric Surplus]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, with that said, you must also realize that you can&amp;rsquo;t always spend every day in a Caloric Deficit or a Caloric Surplus; it is important that you take breaks from dieting and bulking and spend time maintaining. Metabolism is meant to be dynamic, so incorporating days or periods of time where you eat more and then less, is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that I like to do is spend 6-10 weeks at a Caloric Deficit to lose some weight, and then slowly reverse diet out of the deficit to a maintenance calorie level. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll spend 3-4 months in a caloric surplus to promote muscle growth. I&amp;rsquo;ll repeat this cycle until I&amp;rsquo;m satisfied with how my figure looks and according to how I feel from a health standpoint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-find-foods-you-like-incorporate-them-into-your-meals&#34;&gt;3) Find foods you like &amp;amp; incorporate them into your meals&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eat foods you like. It sounds simple, but if you force yourself to eat “healthy” foods that you don’t like, then it’s going to be a rough battle for you to maintain. Now don’t get me wrong, this point is NOT about eating chicken wings and mac and cheese. (We both know you like those foods; however, a diet of chicken wings and mac and cheese isn’t overly healthy in the long run).  A healthy lifestyle includes a balanced diet of carbohydrates (vegetables, starches, sugars), fats (oils, butters), and proteins (meat, dairy). Try to incorporate as many vegetables and meats that you enjoy eating into your diet. This will make it easier to commit to fitness over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term “healthy foods&amp;rdquo; is a slight misconception because what one person thinks is healthy, another person may disagree. I will let you decide what you think is healthy for you; however, a tip that I like to use when picking out food is whether or not the food has been processed (unhealthy), grown on a farm (healthy), or hunted (healthy). That’s not to say that all process foods are created equal: old fashioned oats are different than Cheetos, for example. Use your best judgment when preparing your meals. It’s okay to have most foods in moderation! It’s all about balance and consistency and what contributes to making you feel good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-train-smarter-and-harder&#34;&gt;4) Train Smarter and Harder&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something that always is brought up in the fitness world is training. Today’s thought is that &lt;em&gt;“less is more”&lt;/em&gt; and short workouts are better than longer workouts. My response to that is that it depends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a short workout without any intensity, such as going for a 10 minute walk, that is a lot different than completing a high-intensity interval workout for 10 minutes. While both are 10 minutes, there are studies that high-intensity interval training (HIIT) promotes more fat loss in 10 minutes versus 45-60 minutes of low-intensity training, such as walking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, I think walking is one of the most important exercises one could do to promote long-term health and wellness; however, if your goal is fat loss (who doesn’t want to lose fat), try to plan your workouts around increased intensity and heavier weights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Training smarter also includes choosing exercises that you enjoy doing and a schedule that complements your lifestyle. You shouldn’t be “living to train”; you should be “training to live.” If your routine isn’t one you can stick to, then you won’t be enjoying your time training nor will you have a high likelihood of sticking to the routine over time. Consistency is a huge part of fitness, so the more you can stick to the schedule, the better chance you have of reaching your health goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must challenge yourself if you want to make any progress. For example, if you continuously choose the same weight for the same number of sets and reps, you will not progress to higher weights. Be reasonable, and increase the weight as the exercise becomes easier. Make small adjustments and over time you will see major improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-own-the-decisions-that-you-make-and-be-okay-with-the-outcomes&#34;&gt;5) Own the decisions that you make and be okay with the outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A wise person once told me &lt;em&gt;“you may not be where you want to be, but you’re where you should be.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be as strong or fast or as aesthetic as you may want to be, but based on your current actions, you are where you should be. Keep going; be consistent; and work towards being better each day. You won’t be perfect, but having peace with yourself will go a long ways. You have to be your own advocate; no one else can do that for you. Give yourself a realistic amount of time to reach your goals and be honest with yourself about the decisions you make to reach them. 80% of the results come from 20% of the effort. As mentioned before, train smarter and harder and reap the benefits of putting in the work to get to where you want to be. Reassess your progress regularly (weekly, monthly, etc) so that you have a feel for when expectations and milestones should be met. You have complete control of your life, so own the work that you do; own how you speak to yourself; and own the results of your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr&#34;&gt;TL;DR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it: the five things you should know about fitness as we head into Q3 of 2016. And if this article was &amp;ldquo;TL;DR&amp;rdquo;, I encourage you to scroll up and at least read each of the 5 bullet points. Go ahead and do some soul-searching. Find out the bigger picture, your bigger purpose. Eat according to your goals. Choose foods that you enjoy eating that are satiating and nutritious. Develop a smart training plan and go into each workout with a plan. Increase the weights on key lifts over time. And realize that you’re the driver to your destination. Own every decision that you make – the good and the bad. Be okay with who you are and what you stand for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try out these tips and let me know how you fare. Get at it! &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combat office slouch</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-being-such-a-slouch&#34;&gt;Stop being such a slouch!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and work a desk job, it is easy to turn into a slouched over mess. With all the hype out there about &amp;ldquo;sitting is the new smoking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prehab is rehab&amp;rdquo;, I have decided to create a list of the most realistic exercises that you can do at the office to help improve posture, mobility, and overall happiness. &lt;em&gt;And hopefully prevent you from looking like a stupid fool, rolling around on the floor next to your cubical.&lt;/em&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the advice I&amp;rsquo;m providing here is based off of my personal experience with chronic low back, hip, neck, and shoulder pain, and does not substitute or replace medical advice. These tricks have worked for me based on meeting with a physical therapist for my own mobility/stability issues; however, everybody is different, and it&amp;rsquo;s best to seek an opinion from your doctor prior to trying a rehab/stretch/strength program like the one I am about to outline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to working a full-time desk job, I was a college student. When people think college, they may think parties, alcohol, weight gain, and craziness; however, the reality of my college experience was hair-pulling, weight loss, walking everywhere, and craziness. Once I found myself sitting at the same desk for hours on end with little reason to move other than to get water or use the bathroom, I realized I was becoming a slouched over mess. [Cue the mobility issues, back and hip pain.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;neat&amp;rdquo; little thing about exercise: you can work out for an hour—maybe even two hours—a day, but if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/health-medicine/its-not-your-metabolism-its-your-neat-thats-stopping-your-fat-loss&#34;&gt;inactive for 8-15 hours a day, then exercise less effective&lt;/a&gt;. So why is that so “neat” you may ask? Well it has to do with &lt;strong&gt;N.E.A.T or non-exercise activity thermogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;, aka “what you do when you’re not exercising, which burns calories to keep you alive.” So if you put yourself into a lethargic, slumped over position all day long, and think you will have great mobility for your squat session that evening, well good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-prevent-becoming-an-immobile-mess-of-a-human-being&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I prevent becoming an immobile mess of a human being?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer:&lt;/u&gt; get off your butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer explained:&lt;/u&gt; Every 30-45 minutes, get up and perform a series of mobility/stability exercises to counterbalance the poor posture from sitting. Think back to eighth-grade science class where you learned about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/newtlaws/Lesson-4/Newton-s-Third-Law&#34;&gt;Newton’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;. (For you engineers out there, forgive me, this was a very recent topic for y’all). Newton’s Third Law states that for every action force there is a reaction force equal in magnitude and opposite in direction. For example, if you’re sitting in a slouched over position, inducing flexion on your spine, it’d be wise to get up every half hour and do some back bends to induce extension. Refer to the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://teachmeanatomy.info/wp-content/uploads/Terms-of-Movement-Flexion-and-Extension-CC-1024x815.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-15-minute-routine-to-combat-office-slouch&#34;&gt;A 15-minute routine to combat office slouch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a reason why people who live in a constant state of flexion throw their backs out when they pick up a basket of laundry; it’s because they’re inducing extension on a spine that has been molded into the flexion world. It’s time to teach our spines, and other body parts for that matter, what neutral looks like. To do this, I have developed a short list of five exercises that I think are the most effective for resetting the body and prehab for future injuries. You only need therabands/resistance bands to perform all the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you live in the world of &lt;u&gt;extension&lt;/u&gt;, you would probably benefit from &lt;u&gt;flexion&lt;/u&gt; exercises instead of exercises two and three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder W&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end keep your elbows by your sides. Contract your lats and pull the band apart forming a &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; with your arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_G0feLqXA0E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standing back-bends (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Position your feet slightly behind your hips. Place your hands on your low back (or table as shown in the video), and slowly bend backwards. You will feel this stretch in your lower back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjXCgxajrY4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prone Press-ups (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Lie on the floor and place your hands slightly wider than shoulder-width. Contract your lats and press up with your arms. You should feel a stretch in the low back. Exhale at the top of the movement for a deeper low-back stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qCOt_Em11g8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end and hit 6 points to form the shape of a star as shown in the video. Contract your lats and make sure that your shoulders are relaxed and not shrugged up towards your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xTCvBqZz3Bc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bodyweight Squats&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your feet are shoulder-width apart and that you contract your glutes while hinging at the hips. When you come down, try to break just below parallel and come back up. If you feel this in your lower back, you should compare your form to the example in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p3g4wAsu0R4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to perform these exercises every 30-45 minutes (set a timer!) throughout the work day to prevent poor posture and to prehab the body from potential future injuries. Hopefully, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to hit the gym, your body is already primed for the upcoming movements and you&amp;rsquo;ll be less stiff and sore afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these exercises a try, and let me know if they work for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 ingredient mac and cheese</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/mac-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 11:52:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/mac-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the best recipes come by accidentally mixing things together and tasting the outcome. This Mac &amp;amp; Cheese recipe is a simple as it sounds: 2 ingredients + microwave for 1-2 minutes + enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Not a huge fan of cooking? Then this recipe is for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/-CyCVRgNTJ8Q/Vrd2BicikRI/AAAAAAAAA6w/3LDTsjckFVE/s640/mac%2526cheese.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;113g Cottage Cheese (low fat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;56g Dry Pasta (any shape you like)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Medium Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave-Safe Bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook and drain the pasta according to the directions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add pasta and 113g (1 serving) of cottage cheese to a microwave-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Microwave the mixture of pasta and cottage cheese for 1-2 minutes or until the cottage cheese is completely melted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix the cottage cheese and pasta together and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lessons from stronglifts</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/lessons-from-stronglifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 13:25:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/lessons-from-stronglifts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just say StrongLifts and I have a &lt;strong&gt;LOVE-HATE&lt;/strong&gt; relationship these past 2 weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some major strength gains for bench press (up to 110# 5X5); however, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to reduce the volume of my deadlifts and barbell rows due to low back fatigue and stiffness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sIsl0t4PpBg/VpvVMDXm_4I/AAAAAAAAA6A/1VZUrfJ7IPA/s1600/a%2Bqueenflex.blogspot.com%2Breview.jpg&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;20%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this program is very strenuous on the body and ample recovery is necessary in order to progress by at least 5 lbs each session. I also have never continuously followed a &amp;ldquo;strength building&amp;rdquo; program, where increased volume is a priority. I honestly can say that I LOVE this way of training because it forces you to give everything you&amp;rsquo;ve got and leaves you feeling extremely &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s an addictive feeling, and I&amp;rsquo;m growing to love every training session just a little more. It&amp;rsquo;s become more about ME vs. ME as opposed to  ME vs everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pause a moment and discuss appropriate nutrition for StrongLifts 5X5. You must eat on this program. Let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST EAT ON THIS PROGRAM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not fuel yourself appropriately for these workouts, you will not be able to give the lifts 100% effort. You&amp;rsquo;ll pretty much feel like crap and want to writher up and die. Now that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration; however, YOU MUST EAT if you want to hit PR&amp;rsquo;s and advance your lifts. To do this, it&amp;rsquo;s very suitable to load carbohydrates around your workout. &lt;a href=&#34;http://staging.eattoperform.com/2013/06/20/eight-nutrition-tips/&#34;&gt;2:1 carbohydrates-protein ratio is fine&lt;/a&gt;. I typically have my pre-workout meal about an hour to an hour and a half prior to lifting. My post-workout meal (PWO) is directly after I cool down/stretch and consists of 2:1 fast-digesting carbs (sugars) to fast absorption whey protein isolate. I am also working to become more consistent with taking &lt;a href=&#34;https://examine.com/supplements/Creatine/&#34;&gt;5g of Creatine Monohydrate&lt;/a&gt; PWO to help with muscle recovery and carbohydrate absorption. For an example of a typical day-in-the-life of Liz, check out my MyFitnessPal diary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/diary/stronglizlifts?date=2016-01-16&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider when doing any sort of strength building program is recovery. You must allocate rest days on this program. Again, let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST RECOVER ON THIS PROGRAM. DO NOT CUT REST DAYS!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recovery days are CRITICAL on this program. If you never rest, you&amp;rsquo;ll never recover, and therefore, you&amp;rsquo;ll never feel &amp;ldquo;ready&amp;rdquo; to increase your lifts. You&amp;rsquo;ll be in a continual state of soreness, and trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not fun. Give yourself extra days to recover if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling worn out. You&amp;rsquo;ll feel better and be mentally ready to give it your all in the gym. Remember, heavy, high-volume workouts are tearing your body down. You need time to allow your body to fix the tears and build new tissues and blood vessels to support muscle growth. &lt;strong&gt;Do yourself a favor and rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All and all, StrongLifts has given me a platform to start off my strength training and a flexible plan to meet my weight training goals. I highly recommend jumping in and giving it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how to meal prep over a weekend</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 12:26:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/how-to-meal-prep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Short on time? Hate cooking? Or do you enjoy cooking but want to try something new in the kitchen? I typically meal prep over the course of a weekend by first making a protein and a carb dish and then mixing them together. In this article, I will walk you through this process of making simple, delicious meals that you can grab-and-go throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-cHlo3X4gvbE/VpvNlrZTydI/AAAAAAAAA5c/0oVTGC635kM/s400/IMG_0156.JPG&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;prepare-your-protein-source-chicken&#34;&gt;Prepare Your Protein Source (Chicken)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;ve prepped my meals over the course of two days: Saturday and Sunday. Friday night I washed, trimmed, and seasoned two chicken breasts and placed them in a small crock pot to cook on low for 8 hours overnight. Saturday morning, the chicken was perfectly tender and easy to shred with tongs. Next, I divided the shredded chicken into six portions. I put the chicken away in the fridge and paused the rest of my meal prep until Sunday. Check out this article for additional ways to &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/perfect-chicken/&#34;&gt;cook perfect chicken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-some-carbs-potatoes&#34;&gt;Add Some Carbs (Potatoes)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday morning, I washed, peeled, and diced up two sweet potatoes and one white potato. I also elected to use up some Alexa Sweet Potato fries from my freezer. I set the oven to 425-deg F and baked the fries for about 25 minutes and the diced potatoes for about 35 minutes or until brown. Once the potatoes were cooked, I took the six portions of shredded chicken out of the fridge and put about 150g of potatoes into each container. Click here for more information about &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.github.io/post/cooked-sweet-potatoes/&#34;&gt;cooking perfect sweet potatoes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;finalize-with-veggies-seasonings-and-sauces&#34;&gt;Finalize with Veggies, Seasonings, and Sauces&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m huge on using frozen veggies because I think the taste and cost per serving is unbeatable compared to fresh veggies. Fresh veggies have a lifespan, and if for whatever reason I don&amp;rsquo;t eat all the veggies I buy within a few days, I end up wasting food. I typically buy the microwavable frozen veggie bags because they provide about 3-4 servings per bag, which is great for meal prep. This weekend, I cooked a bag of California blend (broccoli, cauliflower, and carrots), and added it to the shredded chicken and potato meals. Feel free to mix it up and use whatever veggies you like. By incorporating veggies into the pre-made meals, it forces you to eat your vegetables because they&amp;rsquo;re already cooked and included with the other foods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also add seasonings: salt, pepper, Mrs. Dash, etc, as well as sauces: hot sauce, salsa, ketchup, mustard, or salad dressings to make the meals more flavorful. I tend to add these dressings or sauces on just before I&amp;rsquo;m about to eat the meal so that the food doesn&amp;rsquo;t get soggy in the refrigerator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr-meal-prep-isn-t-difficult&#34;&gt;TL;DR: Meal Prep Isn&amp;rsquo;t Difficult&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to be a good chef or even spend a lot of time in the kitchen. Between the two days of meal prep, I probably spent about an hour total and was able to make six meals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key steps to meal prep are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a protein source that you like to eat: chicken, beef, fish, tofu, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Choose a carb source that you also like to eat: potatoes, rice, pasta&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add some veggies, seasonings, and sauces.
If your meal plan requires added fats such as olive oil or nuts, feel free to add those in too. Be sure to emphasize choosing foods you LIKE; otherwise, it will be much more difficult to eat the meals you&amp;rsquo;ve prepared.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional tips:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use shortcuts such as crockpot shredded chicken, minute rice, and frozen microwavable veggies to help save time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portion foods using the typical serving size per bag or with a small food scale. With time and practice your meal prep skills will improve, and you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to mix and match multiple protein and carb sources to have a diverse selection of meals for the week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions? Feel free to drop a comment below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts results: strength and muscle growth</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/stronglifts-program-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 22:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/stronglifts-program-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks on the StrongLifts program have been both rewarding and extremely challenging. Between Christmas, New Years, and traveling with family, as well as keeping up with my Eat To Perform numbers, I added about 20 lbs to my Squat and hit PRs on DeadLifts and Bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each workout is increasingly difficult and recovery and pre-workout nutrition are key to having successful sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say I finished 2015 with a bang, and certainly look forward to the remaining two-thirds of the StrongLifts [starter] program. I plan to reassess my goals and progress in early March to determine whether or not I want to continue StrongLifts for another cycle or to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-njamapHPYGg/Voc8zbOX2UI/AAAAAAAAA3o/1irFK5yhA9U/s1600/STRONGLIFTS%2B5X5-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;today-s-workout-day-a-squat-bench-row&#34;&gt;today&amp;rsquo;s workout - day a: squat, bench, row&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifts today; however, were slightly off, ringing in the new year with a less-than-perfect workout. I missed all my working sets 5X5 for Squats and Rows due to lower back instability and fuzziness. Instead I hit a PR on bench for 5X5 and proceeded to work on my posterior chain mobility and flexibility. Some of my favorite mobility workouts are from Kelly Starrett of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilitywod.com/&#34;&gt;mobilityWod&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi099DokYrKAhVPxGMKHfezDmAQtwIIIDAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DJBHzXF-mVjY&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaLWLA1UMVOUFEO6OzZqgok1GmKw&amp;amp;sig2=vz_aHpCAV1Y7K4uGt-dXpw&#34;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiq3O6AkorKAhVY-2MKHVVdBakQtwIIHzAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DzT657soclws&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHiOQ9WoMXXQvfBqAiBtEImgna-mg&amp;amp;sig2=oC2AOgiSS_Ap2C-7dvP-Dw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.110151844,d.cGc&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; are my go-to&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m having lower back instability or hip tightness. I highly recommend checking out the mobility project for improving overall mobility and health while building strength and muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;next steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to give myself the weekend off and start back up on Monday (1/4/16) with Day B. While a disappointing start to the new year, I am very happy with my overall progress on this program and have never been more excited to work out. Even though the exercises are the same, each routine feels different because it is all about trying to increase volume through an increase in weight over 5 sets of 5. I have no doubt that I will be on my way to hitting 225# squat and deadlift and 145# bench in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is. Short and sweet. Until the next update&amp;hellip; Lift Heavy, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>meal prep perfect chicken</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/perfect-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:57:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/perfect-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tired of dried, bland, and burnt rubber chicken?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 2016 right around the corner, and meal prep headed into full swing within the next few weeks, here is an article to help you prepare delicious, juicy chicken every time. The following article explains my top 3 methods of preparing chicken for use in delicious dinners and dishes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://1.bp.blogspot.com/-4gfh0CU-FfM/VoWWZbM-vkI/AAAAAAAAA3Q/TZqq1KLGEU0/w250-h160-c/Grilled-Chicken3.jpg&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-1-u-wash-trim-and-season-chicken-before-cooking&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #1:&lt;/u&gt;  Wash, Trim, and Season Chicken BEFORE cooking.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before baking, grilling, frying, or boiling, be sure to wash and trim the chicken. I typically use cold water and a pair of kitchen scissors to trim off extra fat. I recommend these pair of scissors from Walmart. They&amp;rsquo;re very affordable and sharp enough to cut meat. When they&amp;rsquo;re dull, I just buy a new pair. Once you finish washing and trimming the chicken breasts, you are ready to add seasonings or marinades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;these-are-some-of-my-favorite-seasonings&#34;&gt;These are some of my favorite seasonings:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organic Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mustard (powder or condiment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Red pepper flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Balsamic Vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bolthouse Farms Italian Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be creative with your seasonings. If you are big into BBQ chicken, then find some BBQ marinades or rubs. Just be mindful of the sodium content since some of the seasonings can have high salt contents While sodium is helpful for athletes, too much of anything can cause health problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-2-u-flip-once-when-you-grill-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #2: &lt;/u&gt;  Flip Once when you Grill Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite way to cook chicken is on the grill. The chicken is crispy and juicy and usually tastes great even as leftovers! The key to grilling chicken is to have a hot grill (at least 450-deg F) and to flip the chicken breasts once every 10-12 minutes. This allows each side to obtain perfect grill marks and to become both crispy and juicy. Note: depending on the size/weight of the chicken breast, you may need to adjust the time and temperature so that it is fully cooked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;u-method-3-u-set-it-and-forget-it-crockpot-chicken-shredded-chicken&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Method #3:&lt;/u&gt;  Set it and forget it. CrockPot Chicken = Shredded Chicken.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;float: right;&#34; src=&#34;https://2.bp.blogspot.com/--bfn1ttBdk4/VoWVGj2DDiI/AAAAAAAAA3I/4SwphTXOZ6M/s320/IMG_0101.JPG&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you work a full-time job or are a full-time student without a lot of time to cook chicken, I highly recommend this method. Put two to three chicken breasts in a small CrockPot (8qt), set on high, and then forget it. The chicken will cook through in two to four hours and can be turned or checked every so often. For added flavor, see &lt;strong&gt;Method #1 above:&lt;/strong&gt; Wash, trim, and season with your favorite flavors! When the chicken is fully cooked, take two forks and pull the chicken apart for a ready-made-meal in minutes. Sometimes I will use the shredded chicken in other dishes such as my Italian Chicken Lasagna or &lt;a href=&#34;http://fitmencook.com/fit-healthy-chicken-rice-enchilada-casserole/&#34;&gt;Healthy Chicken &amp;amp; Rice Enchiladas from FitMenCook&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a super simple way to get a lot of chicken cooked without having to babysit a stove, oven, or grill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make 2016 your best #MealPrep year ever with these simple tips for cooking perfect chicken every time! What are your secrets for cooking moist, delicious chicken? Leave a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts training overview &amp; guide</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/stronglifts-training-overview-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 13:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/stronglifts-training-overview-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the StrongLifts 5x5 program. For those of you unfamiliar with the training plan, it&amp;rsquo;s very simple and most workouts take an hour or less to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-stronglifts-5x5&#34;&gt;overview of stronglifts 5X5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-npDASfZJi1s/VnWXXfQvKtI/AAAAAAAAA0Y/n-Jb0SKgxvc/s1600/SL5x5_1%25262.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are two types of days for this program: Day A and Day B. The 5 exercises this program includes are Squats, Bench Press, Overhead Press, Barbell Rows, and Deadlifts. Each exercise is done for 5 sets of 5 reps with the exception of Deadlifts (I&amp;rsquo;ll explain that further in a moment). See the graphic below for the exercises and routine schedule for Day A and Day B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, you will want to do more on this program because it seems so simple. Do not do extra sets or reps or additional exercises! This is a 12-week + strength building program that forces progressive overload by increasing the weight by 2.5 - 5 lbs each day. You will burn yourself out if you add in additional work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-s47R91gqxX8/VnWl1J_iZ9I/AAAAAAAAA1s/Fj-epoNRI8E/s1600/5_5.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternating-workouts-days-a-and-b&#34;&gt;alternating workouts days a and b&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical schedule on StrongLifts 5x5 is set up alternating Days A and B. For example, the first week of the program goes A, B, A with at least 1 day of rest between each workout day. My first week was Thursday (Day A), Saturday (Day B), Monday (Day A). On the right, I have included the calendar of my workouts for the first two weeks of the program. I highly recommend using the StrongLifts App to help track your workouts and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wpwu3F2Juac/VnWfxuq3ctI/AAAAAAAAA1c/XgWeBZExexE/s1600/dec_calendar.png&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progress-weeks-1-2&#34;&gt;progress weeks 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Week 1 started off pretty slow, and I was very skeptical that my body could handle squatting 3x/week, Week 2 proved to me that this program is going to be awesome! So if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting off, give it at least 5 sessions to make your initial judgement. I especially like how the StrongLifts app has a timer to keep the sets going at an appropriate pace; after each set, once you log it, the app will tell you to take 90 seconds of rest if the set was easy or 3 minutes rest if it was challenging. If you missed any reps, it will tell you to take 5 minutes rest and provide encouragement that you will make all 5 reps the next set. Pretty great if you ask me! Below is the graph generated by the StrongLifts app for all 5 of my core lifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FgZSU473vMI/VnWfgHoYiJI/AAAAAAAAA1Q/b6ZnN_y6qhk/s1600/FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead press is in purple; Bench is in gray; Barbell row is orange; Squats are in blue; and deadlifts are in green. Not too bad for 5 sessions. My goal is to crush 200 lbs in the 12 weeks of the StrongLifts program. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty static in terms of progression these last two years; however, 2016 will be my year to change it up and #MakeItCount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-rant-about-nutrition&#34;&gt;a brief rant about nutrition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, with any strength training program, be sure you&amp;rsquo;re eating enough! Do not try to be in a caloric deficit or on a fat-burning program during StrongLifts. You will need the fuel (carbs!) to get through all your sets and progress. For someone who has always had the &amp;ldquo;diet-mind,&amp;rdquo; it will be tough to bump up the calories and eat more; however, if you want to feel good in the gym, become a better athlete, and recover at an optimal level, you must eat to perform. No this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean eat crap or junk food all day. It means making healthy choices and having a balance of all the macronutrient groups (proteins, carbs, fats). Personally, my ratios have been around 50% Carbs, 30% Protein, and 20% fats. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of food for someone who has been eating around BMR (bad idea, don&amp;rsquo;t do this); however, almost immediately after increasing my intake and upping my carbs, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt more refreshed, and more mentally focused on hitting new PR&amp;rsquo;s each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions about my progress or my opinions about the program. Until next review&amp;hellip;Stay Fit. Stay Strong. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>build muscle with stronglifts 5X5</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/build-muscle-stronglifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 23:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts/build-muscle-stronglifts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So typically I like to plan out my routines and schedule what, when, and why I&amp;rsquo;m training and eating a certain way. In this case; however, I decided to jump head-first into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stronglifts.com/&#34;&gt;StrongLifts 5X5&lt;/a&gt; because, frankly, I&amp;rsquo;m tired of dancing around the bush with fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2EtzjoI-4ro/VmuoW5hWaLI/AAAAAAAAAzM/04pZQJxEQFU/s1600/is%2Bit%2Bin%2Byou%253F%2523makeitcount-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 12 weeks I will be training according to the StrongLifts 5X5 program and continuing to Eat To Perform. My 2016 goals include considerable strength gains, so to FINALLY meet these goals, I am going to give this 5X5 program a try. You can find my StrongLifts updates here. I will work in real-time so that you can see first-hand how good-bad-ugly this program ends up being. With that said, I am using this article to introduce the first Strategy in the #MAKEITCOUNT series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategy-1-accountability-everyone-wants-to-say-they-did-it-without-actually-doing-it&#34;&gt;strategy #1 accountability: everyone wants to say they did it, without actually doing it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be that person who commits to something and then fails to actually follow through with it. Now I understand some situations are circumstantial, but let&amp;rsquo;s face it, who likes excuses? Not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I will be spending the early part of winter working on my strength with StrongLifts 5X5, what will you be doing? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s starting to workout for the first time in ten years; maybe your goal is to start flossing twice a day (dental hygiene is important); maybe you&amp;rsquo;re starting a new job and your goal is to save for retirement; whatever your 2016 goals are, you have to jump all in and go for them. Challenge yourself to do something every day to work towards your goal. 2% changes each day add up to major improvements over the course of weeks, months, and years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Strategy #2&amp;hellip; #MAKEITCOUNT. Learn to become Accountable&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a mini guide on supplements</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 17:25:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-66lpbJ3zzCo/VmNQda3zQvI/AAAAAAAAAyA/s6AK5_LQdL8/s640/bs-thumb.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;
Why shell out hundreds of dollars per month on useless supplements when you can have all the health benefits for under $75? Supplements are not magic and will not get the results you have not been working for; they are only useful if you have been working out smart and eating to support your energy balance and training goals. Over the years, my opinions about supplements have changed dramatically: initially I bought into the trendy supplement stacks promoted by famous and aesthetic bodybuilders whom are often receiving free products from the companies they are endorsed by. For this reason alone, it is important to choose supplements based on your own goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a goal, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be thinking about supplements! Be critical of yourself. Map out your workout and nutrition plans first before complicating the process with the wealth, media, and pop-culture out there surrounding the &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rsquo;s and don&amp;rsquo;ts&amp;rdquo; of supplementation. In this article, I will outline my current (and minimalistic) approach to supplementation as well as tips you can use to build a meaningful supplementation stack for less than $75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;supplements-so-many-choices-so-few-that-matter&#34;&gt;Supplements: So Many Choices, So Few That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rise of mainstream fitness and the high profitability of supplement companies comes a wealth of random products that may or may not be suitable for taking based on your goals. I base my supplementation around two key components: #1 DIET, #2 TRAINING. Because I am a huge proponent of EatToPerform, I have been slowly introducing the concept of wave dieting the past few months. (You can read more about the wave diet on ETP&amp;rsquo;s website.) My current goal (as of Dec 2015) is to average 2000 calories daily: 140g protein, 298g carbs, 50g fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You might ask:&lt;/em&gt; Ok Liz, what does this have to do with supplementation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And really, the answer is quite simple:&lt;/em&gt; I will only supplement to help meet my macros if eating whole foods alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #1:&lt;/u&gt; If eating three whole food meals including lean meats, chicken, fish, etc doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me meet my protein goals for the day, only then will I add in a protein supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My go-to protein supplement is Whey Protein Isolate.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UKV6Fxp9skU/VmNTvgeOvsI/AAAAAAAAAyM/Zd4GdCwFW7k/s320/performance-whey.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a liking to Optimum Nutrition&amp;rsquo;s Performance Whey Isolate. The ingredients label is easy-to-read, the macronutrients fit my needs, and it&amp;rsquo;s affordable (~$35-50  for 50 servings).
There is an exception to Postulate #1, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Exception #1:&lt;/u&gt; If I know I will be having an intense workout that day (HIIT, Heavy Deadlifts, Heavy Squats, etc), I will supplement with Whey Protein Isolate within 30-minutes post-workout. I feel that this method helps speed up recovery for me and reduces soreness/delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS) within the following two days. The main reason why I prefer Whey Protein Isolate over blends, concentrates, caseinate, vegan/vegetarian/soy proteins, etc. is because Whey Protein Isolate is fast-absorption and typically gives you the most protein for the price. To me, if I&amp;rsquo;m going to buy a protein supplement, I want it to contain protein, not fillers, nor proprietary blends, and junk that I have no real reason to put into my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #2:&lt;/u&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s important to check the supplement for purity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nifty website that is focused on supplement quality and value is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.labdoor.com&#34;&gt;Labdoor&lt;/a&gt;. You can search for supplements, and if Labdoor has run quality/purity tests on the product, you will get the lab test results. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to verify that what you&amp;rsquo;re buying and using is a safe product filled with the ingredients reported on the label. With that said, a few other Whey Protein Isolate brands I recommend are Myprotein&amp;rsquo;s Impact Whey Isolate, and Isopure Whey Isolate. &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.myprotein.com/referrals.list?applyCode=LIZ-R4T&amp;amp;li&#34;&gt;Get 10% off your order on myprotein.com&lt;/a&gt; when you make a purchase with my link!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #3:&lt;/u&gt; Take Fish Oil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.meme.am/instances/500x/56405802.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone, active or not, should be supplementing with fish oil. Unless you eat salmon every day, you will not reach an optimal level of Omega-3&amp;rsquo;s. You can read more about fish oil and the required dosages here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should be supplementing with 1g Fish Oil/day; active people should be closer to 6g Fish Oil/day. I currently supplement with Vitamin Shoppe&amp;rsquo;s Fish Oil due to its high quality/purity and value ratings on Labdoor. One thing to note about fish oil is that it should be bought in &lt;strong&gt;SMALLER&lt;/strong&gt; packages to reduce the effects of oxidation. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to store fish oil in the refrigerator/freezer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt; Postulate #4: &lt;/u&gt; Maximize Post-Workout Gains with Creatine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HP2qviiAniI/VmNZzq63JCI/AAAAAAAAAyg/kZzwNH-AktA/s640/creatine-safe.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;95%&#34; height=&#34;60%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Creatine is safe. Because creatine is well-researched, it is &amp;ldquo;remarkably safe for most people.&amp;rdquo; One of my favorite websites for verifying the safety of products is Examine.com. Not only can you learn more about creatine, but you can search nearly any supplement or drug, and you can learn more about nutrition. Examine.com will provide you dosage information as well as how to maximize absorption of the supplements you decide to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some creatine products I recommend are Con-Cret by ProMera Sports (Creatine HCl) and Creatine Monohydrate from Myprotein. Both have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; ratings on Labdoor, and I have had good results from both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-a-supplement-stack-for-less-than-75-month&#34;&gt;How to Make a Supplement Stack for less than $75/month:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the tips provided above, we can now discuss my $75/month supplement stack. I am not affiliated nor receive a commission for providing you with the brands of products given in my recommendations below. As always, you should consult with your doctor or health professional before starting a health or supplementation program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choose a Reputable Whey Protein Isolate (2 servings/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimum Nutrition Performance Whey Isolate $39 for 4.4lb, 40 days, $1/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pick out Fish Oil (~3g/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Fish Oil - $16 for 60 caps x 2 = $32 for 120 caps, 40 days, $0.80/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buy Creatine (1 serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myprotein Creatine Monohydrate - $11 for 226g, 45 days, $0.28/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top-off with missing Micronutrients/Minerals (1 cap or serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin D 1000IU- $8 for 200 caps, $0.04/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin K 100 Mcg- $5 for 100 caps, $0.05/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt; Natural Calm Magnesium - $18 for 56 servings, $0.32/day. &lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 11/24/16: I no longer recommend Natural Calm Magnesium due to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://labdoor.com/article/labdoors-statement-natural-vitality-calm&#34;&gt;labdoor press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;total-74-70-days-30&#34;&gt;Total - $74.70 # Days- 30&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr-summary&#34;&gt;TL;DR (Summary):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. A starter plan for what supplements to buy, and how to choose meaningful supplements. The first step with any goal is to create your diet and exercise plan; once you have a solid foundation and are eating to match your energy expenditure, you can then add in supplements to help with recovery time and muscle growth. It is important to understand what ingredients you&amp;rsquo;re putting into your body and the safety of the supplements you choose to buy. For that very reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended educating yourself about products before buying and trying. My favorite websites for scientific-based evidence on reputable supplements and dosing information are Labdoor.com and Examine.com. It&amp;rsquo;s your life. Be smart about your supplementation and spending. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall into the pitfall of needing a &amp;ldquo;magic pill&amp;rdquo; to get the results you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you use any of these supplements? Are you surprised by my recommendations? Drop a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until next time&amp;hellip;#queenflexblog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mom&#39;s healthy meatballs</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/moms-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 15:23:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/moms-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s meal is a healthy version of a favorite recipe of mine, growing up: Mom&amp;rsquo;s Healthy Meatballs. (Shoutout to my wonderful Mother!) If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a delicious recipe that&amp;rsquo;s both healthy and easy, look no further. I&amp;rsquo;ve combined lean ground beef with diced tomatoes to make a warm, wintery meal suitable for any appetite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-h1OcmdRjb8w/ViaTfVFw3-I/AAAAAAAAAv8/6sJqEFJgfeQ/s320/IMG_1278.JPG&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16oz lean ground beef (I typically buy 93% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Bothouse Farms Italian Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Reduced Fat Mexican Cheese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 can Diced Tomatoes - No Salt Added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder, salt, pepper, Italian seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large skillet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oven dish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tongs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Liquid measuring cup&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-stick cooking spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix ground beef, Italian dressing, garlic powder, pepper, and Italian seasonings together in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weigh out four 4oz portions using the kitchen scale.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide each 4oz portion into four 1oz portions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heat a large skillet on high. Spray with non-stick cooking spray and lightly coat the pan with some Italian seasonings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once the pan is hot, add all of the meatballs to it. Cook the meatballs for roughly 3 minutes each side or until both sides have browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 375-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat the oven dish with non-stick cooking spray and add half of the can of diced tomatoes to the bottom.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the meatballs from the skillet and add to the oven dish.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat each meatball with the remaining diced tomatoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add cheese to the top and additional seasonings, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake at 375-deg F for 20-25 minutes or until the meatballs are fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes. Pair with a side of spaghetti or veggies and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>seasonal apple crisp pre-workout snack</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/apple-crisp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2015 14:15:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/apple-crisp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week&amp;rsquo;s meal is a seasonal pre-workout packed with carbs and protein to give you that extra kick during your workout. For those of you who love utilizing the flavors of fall, freshly picked apples go perfectly with this quick, 15 minute snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-ZTPdzBiK0EE/Vg_ibGMaiUI/AAAAAAAAAtA/uGcVwC4DcXE/s400/blogger-image--1529127191.jpg&#34; width=&#34;75%&#34; height=&#34;65%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-3OTlWg-O6Qs/Vg_ktoDyBNI/AAAAAAAAAtU/QsppF6NUMDE/s400/NutritionLabel-2.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150-180g Apple- typically the size of a medium apple (Whichever kind you prefer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Old Fashioned Oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150g Danon Greek Yogurt, Vanilla (Feel free to substitute your favorite flavor)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stevia/Truvia to taste&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Small pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 bowls&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spoon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; hspace=40 src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-HuHUjejcQKY/Vg_nJb7l-VI/AAAAAAAAAtg/rhFtNeLJodY/s320/blogger-image-543035887.jpg&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add oats to small pot. Fill with ~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;-&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup of water (almond milk or milk) or until the top of the oats are covered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir in cinnamon and stevia/Truvia, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove to high heat and let the oats/seasonings mixture heat until the oats start to bubble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to low and stir the oat mixture. This process is similar to cooking oatmeal on the stove.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop up the apple into cubes. Feel free to remove the peel, if desired. I leave the peel on for extra crunch.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix in &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the apples with the oatmeal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of the apples and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the Vanilla Greek Yogurt to the bottom of a heat-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The oatmeal/apples mixture is fully cooked when the apples are soft and 80%+ of the water has been absorbed by the oats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour the oatmeal/apples mixture into the heat-safe bowl.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top with the remaining &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; apples and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; of the Vanilla Greek Yogurt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle with cinnamon and stevia/Truvia, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool and enjoy!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for Meal of the Week? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>healthy mini chicken pot pies</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/chicken-pot-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 12:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/recipes/chicken-pot-pies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you craving this classic taste of Fall, and your macros don&amp;rsquo;t allow for the traditional chicken pot pie recipe, give this a try! For under 300 calories, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a tasty dose of this deliciously seasonal, healthy chicken pot pie made with fresh ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the Meal Prep Series, this week&amp;rsquo;s meal is Mini Chicken Pot Pies (adopted and modified from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitnessmagazine.com/recipe/chicken/mini-chicken-pot-pies/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; original recipe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-byQuTHmmeKo/VgdRcPo_jzI/AAAAAAAAArY/ed78Y2tvwDo/s640/blogger-image-1255513652.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ZUqU8qzH4Ak/VgdTQEErGHI/AAAAAAAAArs/rFrMx5S_OoA/s320/NutritionLabel.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80g yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70g celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g baby carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups Reduced-Sodium Chicken Broth (not all will be consumed; mainly used for cooking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Bothouse Farms Italian Vinaigrette Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Grands Jr Golden Layer Buttermilk Biscuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 serving frozen veggies of your choice (I chose Kroger&amp;rsquo;s Recipe Secrets - Vegetable Soup, Mix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 oz Chicken Breast (Raw measure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Stick, Fat-Free Cooking Spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 single-serve oven-safe bowls or ramekins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baking Rack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove on high and coat large pot with non-stick spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop up onion, celery, and carrots. Mix with seasonings in the large pot. Cook until onions are browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to medium. Add chicken broth and Italian Vinaigrette to large pot and let simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash and prep chicken breast. Cut into smaller pieces and add to large pot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let simmer ~10 minutes or until the chicken is fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add frozen veggies. Cook until completely thawed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce stove to low heat. Remove chicken and add to a separate bowl. Shred if desired using a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the kitchen scale, find the total weight of chicken and divide by 4. This will be the serving size per mini chicken pie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chicken and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of veggies to the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ~1-2 tbsp of broth to the bowls. Season with more garlic, black pepper, italian seasonings, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flatten and mold the 4 Grands Jr Biscuits to fit the top of each of the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat the top of the biscuits with a small amount (~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp) of left over broth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle top of biscuits with more seasonings if desired. (I coated with some garlic powder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake for 8-12 minutes or until the biscuits are fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes and enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But wait …what do I do with the left over broth?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be left with ~90% of the chicken broth. Instead of throwing it out, I used it to cook the rest of my chicken as a part of my #MealPrepSunday. To do this, I added 3 raw chicken breasts and the chicken broth to a small crock pot and cooked on high for roughly 3 hours. Once the chicken was fully cooked, I removed it from the broth and shredded it down. I put 2 servings of chicken back into the crock pot with 2 servings of frozen veggies and 1 serving of tortellini to make a soup (YUM!). I let this cook for another 30-60 minutes on low heat. I packed up the remaining shredded chicken in a tupperware for use throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for Meal of the Week? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>daily fitness must-haves</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-must-haves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 15:37:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-must-haves/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stop right there. Yes, you. Did you forget something?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you have a few staple items that you always leave the house with: wallet, keys, phone..(gum, ha)&amp;hellip;check. But what about the fitness enthusiasts out there. It seems like we are always carrying around more &lt;s&gt;random&lt;/s&gt; necessary things as we venture to work, the grocery store, or even the gym (gasp). So what things define you as part of the #fitfam? For me, I have a few staple items (other than those presented above) that seem to follow me wherever I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fitmark-bag&#34;&gt;Fitmark Bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.fitmarkbags.com//image/data/products/transporter-tote-2015/black/Transporter-Tote-Bag_black_front.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;45%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two months ago, I was in the market for a meal-prep/work/all-around bag to replace my kindergarten lunch box. I figured since I am now in the working world, I owe it to myself to look the part. It took me awhile to decide on a meal-prep bag; there are so many choose from&amp;ndash;Six Pack Bags to Isobag to Fitmark to Target&amp;rsquo;s dollar deal. I originally started off with the Renee Tote from Six Pack Bags and as beautiful of a bag as it was when it arrived, I could barely fit my laptop or a book or anything (besides food) in it. Very disappointing to say the least. Instead of holding on to a $160 meal bag that I had no use for, I began some research into my next bag. In June, the TranSPORTer tote from Fitmark Bags came out in black. It has the ability to hold a Small BOX with two meal containers as well as serve as a full duffle bag. As soon as it arrived, I did a quick test for storage and usability, and the rest is history; I don&amp;rsquo;t leave my house without my TranSPORTer tote. Talk about the best of both worlds: store two-to-three meals, plus a laptop/books/drinks/workout clothes all in one bag. Wonderful! So to those of you out there looking for an all-around bag, I highly recommend taking a look at Fitmark&amp;rsquo;s products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notebook-workout-log&#34;&gt;Notebook/Workout Log&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I find myself listening to a podcast or reading an article or two and find myself jotting notes on random sheets of paper, only to lose those notes a week later. I decided to carry around a single-subject composition book along with my workout log so that I can keep all my fitness-related thoughts together in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workout logs have changed shape and form over the years of lifting. Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to designing my own workout log in iBooks based on my routine over a 12-week period. I include each workout, the respective exercises, sets and reps within a table, which makes it seamlessly easy to track progress and continuously work towards achieving a PR or goal. Check out my FREE &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.blogspot.com/p/official-workout-log.html&#34;&gt;downloadable workout training log&lt;/a&gt; template!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lacrosse-tennis-yoga-tuneup-balls&#34;&gt;Lacrosse/Tennis/Yoga TuneUp Balls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know when you&amp;rsquo;ll have a trigger point or shooting shoulder pain. So why not be prepared with the right tools? Also since migrating to a stand-up desk, my feet and calves can use some extra love throughout the day. Plus, some days are just meant for fidgeting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-2-gallon-water-jug&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Gallon Water Jug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://s4.thcdn.com/productimg/600/600/11133450-2084319696682723.jpg&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;
I never leave the house without my &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Gallon water jug. While it probably looks silly to some, I&amp;rsquo;m always thirsty (especially in the Arizona heat), so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind that it becomes a conversation-starter in most social scenarios. Receive &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.myprotein.com/protein-accessories/myprotein-1-2-gallon-hydrator/11133450.html?feature=locale-popup&amp;amp;referringSite=myprotein_en_GB&amp;amp;countrySelected=Y&#34;&gt;10% off your order with the promo code &amp;ldquo;LIZ-R4T&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gallon hydrator on myprotein.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are your daily must-haves? Do you use any of these items as religiously as me? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; Note: I do not represent Fitmark Bags in any way, shape, or form. The opinions of this article are strictly mine, and I have not been compensated to say anything written in this article about any of these staple items.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>