<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/warm-up/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/warm-up/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>tried and true warm-up routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/warm-up-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2016 14:40:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/warm-up-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I never really had a &lt;em&gt;consistent&lt;/em&gt; warm-up routine until I struggled to come back to the sport of lifting after a lower-back injury. Had I properly warmed up prior to lifting each session, I might not have suffered the injury in the first place. I treat warm-up routines as a method of injury prevention and will not start the warm-up sets with a barbell until I feel completely warm and ready to lift - both physically and mentally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This article outlines my 10-15 minute warm-up routine that I like to perform before any of my compound lifts (squat, bench, press, deadlift). There are some slight variations depending on the movement I am performing, but at the heart of the routine are four key movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I jump into outlining the routine, I want to explain a few principles of what and why I picked certain movements. The exercises given below are a combination of my lower-back rehabilitation program as well as functional movements to help promote the proper motor patterns prior to performing a key lift with weights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve found that if my muscles are warmed up and my body has performed the movement with bodyweight or lighter weights, I am not as worried or concerned to go heavier because I&amp;rsquo;ve already activated the targeted muscle group and practiced proper form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These exercises are performed for as many reps and sets as needed depending on how I feel. So if I feel especially stiff or sore in a particular area, I may spend more time warming up. That&amp;rsquo;s the neat thing about warm-ups, you&amp;rsquo;re warming up for &lt;em&gt;that particular session&lt;/em&gt;, so be sure to listen to your body and make sure you&amp;rsquo;re getting what you need to have a successful training day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;queenflex-warm-up-routine&#34;&gt;queenflex warm-up routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1) &lt;u&gt;Shoulder Dislocation Mobility Drill&lt;/u&gt;: grab a band or a pipe and perform 2-3 sets of 12-15 reps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/02HdChcpyBs&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2) &lt;u&gt;Kettlebell Bottoms-Up Carry&lt;/u&gt;: grab a 15-25lb kettlebell and perform 2-4 sets of 50-100 ft walks per arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UpBzi0HIdAI&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3) &lt;u&gt;Kettlebell Arm Bar &lt;/u&gt;:  grab a 15-25lb kettlebell and perform 1-2 sets of 10 reps per arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aHVBrsysBUY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4) &lt;u&gt; Back Extensions&lt;/u&gt;: (weighted or bodyweight) I like to do 2 sets of 12 reps of the weighted back extensions (machine or plate) as well as 2 sets of 12 standing back extensions. Some days I may even throw in a third round of bodyweight back extensions on the back extension bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Standing:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xqz_S7Znh9g&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back Extension Machine:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ab0eIyp9CWQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back Extension Bench:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vx0jZBEmZcE&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5) &lt;u&gt; Dumbbell Sumo Deadlift &lt;/u&gt;: I like to perform these movements on squat and deadlift days to help activate the glutes. Perform 2-3 sets of 10 reps with a 50-75lb dumbbell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/vr8yOR_YwXg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before deadlifts or squats, I will throw in a few sets of kneeling leg curls to warm up my hamstrings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is relatively short, but as I said above, if I feel tightness in a particular muscle group or bodypart, I will pick a movement and perform a few sets to warm-up that area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make things easier for you, I&amp;rsquo;ve included a printable version of this list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/2hjXHJD&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Click here for the printable version&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you do for your warm-up routine? Comment below with your favorite exercises. Until next time &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>