<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/recovery/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. queenflex.com. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/recovery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>an 8-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/eight-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 20:10:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/eight-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a mini guide on supplements</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2015 17:25:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/supplement-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why shell out hundreds of dollars per month on useless supplements when you can have all the health benefits for under $75? Supplements are not magic and will not get the results you have not been working for; they are only useful if you have been working out smart and eating to support your energy balance and training goals. Over the years, my opinions about supplements have changed dramatically: initially I bought into the trendy supplement stacks promoted by famous and aesthetic bodybuilders whom are often receiving free products from the companies they are endorsed by. For this reason alone, it is important to choose supplements based on your own goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-66lpbJ3zzCo/VmNQda3zQvI/AAAAAAAAAyA/s6AK5_LQdL8/s640/bs-thumb.jpg&#34; width=&#34;660&#34; height=&#34;315&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a goal, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be thinking about supplements! Be critical of yourself. Map out your workout and nutrition plans first before complicating the process with the wealth, media, and pop-culture out there surrounding the &amp;ldquo;do&amp;rsquo;s and don&amp;rsquo;ts&amp;rdquo; of supplementation. In this article, I will outline my current (and minimalistic) approach to supplementation as well as tips you can use to build a meaningful supplementation stack for less than $75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;supplements-so-many-choices-so-few-that-matter&#34;&gt;Supplements: So Many Choices, So Few That Matter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the rise of mainstream fitness and the high profitability of supplement companies comes a wealth of random products that may or may not be suitable for taking based on your goals. I base my supplementation around two key components: #1 DIET, #2 TRAINING. Because I am a huge proponent of EatToPerform, I have been slowly introducing the concept of wave dieting the past few months. (You can read more about the wave diet on ETP&amp;rsquo;s website.) My current goal (as of Dec 2015) is to average 2000 calories daily: 140g protein, 298g carbs, 50g fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You might ask:&lt;/em&gt; Ok Liz, what does this have to do with supplementation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And really, the answer is quite simple:&lt;/em&gt; I will only supplement to help meet my macros if eating whole foods alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #1:&lt;/u&gt; If eating three whole food meals including lean meats, chicken, fish, etc doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me meet my protein goals for the day, only then will I add in a protein supplement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My go-to protein supplement is Whey Protein Isolate.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-UKV6Fxp9skU/VmNTvgeOvsI/AAAAAAAAAyM/Zd4GdCwFW7k/s320/performance-whey.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;315&#34; height=&#34;250&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a liking to Optimum Nutrition&amp;rsquo;s Performance Whey Isolate. The ingredients label is easy-to-read, the macronutrients fit my needs, and it&amp;rsquo;s affordable (~$35-50  for 50 servings).
There is an exception to Postulate #1, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Exception #1:&lt;/u&gt; If I know I will be having an intense workout that day (HIIT, Heavy Deadlifts, Heavy Squats, etc), I will supplement with Whey Protein Isolate within 30-minutes post-workout. I feel that this method helps speed up recovery for me and reduces soreness/delayed onset muscle soreness (DOMS) within the following two days. The main reason why I prefer Whey Protein Isolate over blends, concentrates, caseinate, vegan/vegetarian/soy proteins, etc. is because Whey Protein Isolate is fast-absorption and typically gives you the most protein for the price. To me, if I&amp;rsquo;m going to buy a protein supplement, I want it to contain protein, not fillers, nor proprietary blends, and junk that I have no real reason to put into my body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #2:&lt;/u&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s important to check the supplement for purity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nifty website that is focused on supplement quality and value is called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.labdoor.com&#34;&gt;Labdoor&lt;/a&gt;. You can search for supplements, and if Labdoor has run quality/purity tests on the product, you will get the lab test results. It&amp;rsquo;s a nice way to verify that what you&amp;rsquo;re buying and using is a safe product filled with the ingredients reported on the label. With that said, a few other Whey Protein Isolate brands I recommend are Myprotein&amp;rsquo;s Impact Whey Isolate, and Isopure Whey Isolate. &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.myprotein.com/referrals.list?applyCode=LIZ-R4T&amp;amp;li&#34;&gt;Get 10% off your order on myprotein.com&lt;/a&gt; when you make a purchase with my link!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Postulate #3:&lt;/u&gt; Take Fish Oil.
&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.meme.am/instances/500x/56405802.jpg&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;250&#34; height=&#34;250&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly everyone, active or not, should be supplementing with fish oil. Unless you eat salmon every day, you will not reach an optimal level of Omega-3&amp;rsquo;s. You can read more about fish oil and the required dosages here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone should be supplementing with 1g Fish Oil/day; active people should be closer to 6g Fish Oil/day. I currently supplement with Vitamin Shoppe&amp;rsquo;s Fish Oil due to its high quality/purity and value ratings on Labdoor. One thing to note about fish oil is that it should be bought in &lt;strong&gt;SMALLER&lt;/strong&gt; packages to reduce the effects of oxidation. It&amp;rsquo;s also a good idea to store fish oil in the refrigerator/freezer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt; Postulate #4: &lt;/u&gt; Maximize Post-Workout Gains with Creatine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-HP2qviiAniI/VmNZzq63JCI/AAAAAAAAAyg/kZzwNH-AktA/s640/creatine-safe.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;275&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes. Creatine is safe. Because creatine is well-researched, it is &amp;ldquo;remarkably safe for most people.&amp;rdquo; One of my favorite websites for verifying the safety of products is Examine.com. Not only can you learn more about creatine, but you can search nearly any supplement or drug, and you can learn more about nutrition. Examine.com will provide you dosage information as well as how to maximize absorption of the supplements you decide to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some creatine products I recommend are Con-Cret by ProMera Sports (Creatine HCl) and Creatine Monohydrate from Myprotein. Both have &amp;ldquo;A&amp;rdquo; ratings on Labdoor, and I have had good results from both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-a-supplement-stack-for-less-than-75-month&#34;&gt;How to Make a Supplement Stack for less than $75/month:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the tips provided above, we can now discuss my $75/month supplement stack. I am not affiliated nor receive a commission for providing you with the brands of products given in my recommendations below. As always, you should consult with your doctor or health professional before starting a health or supplementation program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Choose a Reputable Whey Protein Isolate (2 servings/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Optimum Nutrition Performance Whey Isolate $39 for 4.4lb, 40 days, $1/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pick out Fish Oil (~3g/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Fish Oil - $16 for 60 caps x 2 = $32 for 120 caps, 40 days, $0.80/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Buy Creatine (1 serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Myprotein Creatine Monohydrate - $11 for 226g, 45 days, $0.28/day&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Top-off with missing Micronutrients/Minerals (1 cap or serving/day)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin D 1000IU- $8 for 200 caps, $0.04/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vitamin Shoppe Vitamin K 100 Mcg- $5 for 100 caps, $0.05/day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt; Natural Calm Magnesium - $18 for 56 servings, $0.32/day. &lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update 11/24/16: I no longer recommend Natural Calm Magnesium due to this &lt;a href=&#34;https://labdoor.com/article/labdoors-statement-natural-vitality-calm&#34;&gt;labdoor press release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;total-74-70-days-30&#34;&gt;Total - $74.70 # Days- 30&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tl-dr-summary&#34;&gt;TL;DR (Summary):&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. A starter plan for what supplements to buy, and how to choose meaningful supplements. The first step with any goal is to create your diet and exercise plan; once you have a solid foundation and are eating to match your energy expenditure, you can then add in supplements to help with recovery time and muscle growth. It is important to understand what ingredients you&amp;rsquo;re putting into your body and the safety of the supplements you choose to buy. For that very reason, I&amp;rsquo;ve recommended educating yourself about products before buying and trying. My favorite websites for scientific-based evidence on reputable supplements and dosing information are Labdoor.com and Examine.com. It&amp;rsquo;s your life. Be smart about your supplementation and spending. Don&amp;rsquo;t fall into the pitfall of needing a &amp;ldquo;magic pill&amp;rdquo; to get the results you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you use any of these supplements? Are you surprised by my recommendations? Drop a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Until next time&amp;hellip;#queenflexblog&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>turn your injury into an opportunity</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 21:44:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Injuries happen quite often in fitness and athletics in general–whether it is a minor case of the shin-splints or a broken bone, athletes are prone to getting hurt. Somehow it has become part of a vicious cycle; a known part of the game. But does it have to be this way?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://spotmegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/@physio_fit.png&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; height=&#34;315&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past four years of my fit lifestyle I have managed to train my way through and around injuries. One of the key things I have learned is that many training-related injuries can be prevented. It all comes down to knowing your body and how it performs. There’s a difference between “cry-baby pain” and pain you should take seriously. Listening to your body is a true way to gauge this line. If your gut-instinct tells you to take a step back, then you should probably listen to it! Push through it, and you could miss more than a few reps or even steps in the long run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay, so now you’re telling me to just stop training when the alarm sounds?&lt;/em&gt;
Actually, I’m suggesting an alternative method, selective training. If you feel shin-splints coming on and you need to perform HIIT as part of your training regime, then stop the treadmill work. Switch to HIIT on a rower or elliptical machine. Even better, use this opportunity to go outside and ride a bicycle. Be the badass on a bike performing 1 minute of hard-out pedaling and 30 seconds of leisurely, relaxed riding. Turn your injury into a chance to rest that body part. There are over 500 muscles in the human body; if one of them needs a break, then switch your attention to the other 499-plus muscles that need work. Read on for some more great tips to turning an injury into an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;switch-to-body-weight-exercises&#34;&gt;Switch to Body-Weight Exercises&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel an injury coming on, switch to body weight exercises for a couple of days. This will reduce the stress placed on your body from lifting heavy. Plus, you will still get a great workout! Body-weight exercises allow you to concentrate on supporting your own weight through balance and endurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for more of a challenge? Try completing 500 reps of common body-weight exercises such as planks, pullups, sit-ups, and push-ups with a 7 minute cutoff time for each. Trust me, it’s more difficult than it sounds! You could also try switching it up and do multiple rounds of tabata: 20 seconds of reps followed by 10 seconds of rest for a total of 4 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-cardio-training&#34;&gt;Alternative Cardio Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardio doesn’t have to be about running, biking, or elliptical work. Use this opportunity to go for a long hike, try out rock climbing, or even pick up boxing. Challenge yourself by trying something new. Even kayaking can be a great cardio workout! Be creative and think about opportunities you can take part in rather than worry about opportunities you’re missing out on due to an injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rehab-and-stretch&#34;&gt;Rehab and Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times athletes get injured, go to physical therapy, finish up the sessions and then stop doing the exercises. I’ll admit, I’m not as proactive when it comes to doing the stretching and prep work before a workout. If you are given exercises by a physical therapist, be sure to do them! Stretching is a great way to prepare your body for the stresses of lifting. It promotes oxygen flow to the muscles and will help loosen you up beforehand. Use this time to throw in your favorite playlist and get pumped for the workout!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shoulder-related-injury&#34;&gt;Shoulder-related Injury?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem. After a few rounds of surgery to remove a bone mass between my scapula and rib cage, I’ve become more aware of alternative shoulder and upper body exercises. Typically when I’m working shoulders and chest I will modify the flat bench press to an incline press just so that my shoulders aren’t under so much stress. I still get the added benefit of a dumbbell or barbell press just without the added tension. If you have another sensitive area from previous injuries, modified exercises always help and can get you on track to where you want to be without stopping a plan entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-down-and-heat-up&#34;&gt;Ice Down and Heat Up!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this recovery period as an excuse to relax with a heating pad or ice pack. Whether you like ice or heat, just relaxing after your workout with one or the other can help your muscles start to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know that sometimes injuries are much more complex than a little case of the shin-splints. In complex injuries, you need to use your best judgement. Don’t push yourself to the point where you’re physically disintegrating. You’re training with a purpose. You want to become a better, more polished version of yourself. So instead of dropping all fitness entirely when an injury strikes, strike back and play smart. If upper body is injured, work legs. Go for a jog. Keep up your cardio. Do some active stretching and rehabilitation exercises. Be mindful of yourself and your goals, and take the time to turn your injury into an opportunity for future prevention and a successful recovery. Fitness is probably the greatest game composed of lifting, nutrition, and competition. Take care of yourself by doing the recommended stretches in preparation for your training routine. Your body will thank you for it afterwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Previously published on December 3, 2014 on SpotMeGirl.com&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>