<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/2015/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/2015/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 3 &amp; 4 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 22:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks on the StrongLifts program have been both rewarding and extremely challenging. Between Christmas, New Years, and traveling with family, as well as keeping up with my Eat To Perform numbers, I added about 20 lbs to my Squat and hit PRs on DeadLifts and Bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each workout is increasingly difficult and recovery and pre-workout nutrition are key to having successful sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say I finished 2015 with a bang, and certainly look forward to the remaining two-thirds of the StrongLifts [starter] program. I plan to reassess my goals and progress in early March to determine whether or not I want to continue StrongLifts for another cycle or to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-njamapHPYGg/Voc8zbOX2UI/AAAAAAAAA3o/1irFK5yhA9U/s1600/STRONGLIFTS%2B5X5-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;today-s-workout-day-a-squat-bench-row&#34;&gt;today&amp;rsquo;s workout - day a: squat, bench, row&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifts today; however, were slightly off, ringing in the new year with a less-than-perfect workout. I missed all my working sets 5X5 for Squats and Rows due to lower back instability and fuzziness. Instead I hit a PR on bench for 5X5 and proceeded to work on my posterior chain mobility and flexibility. Some of my favorite mobility workouts are from Kelly Starrett of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilitywod.com/&#34;&gt;mobilityWod&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi099DokYrKAhVPxGMKHfezDmAQtwIIIDAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DJBHzXF-mVjY&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaLWLA1UMVOUFEO6OzZqgok1GmKw&amp;amp;sig2=vz_aHpCAV1Y7K4uGt-dXpw&#34;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiq3O6AkorKAhVY-2MKHVVdBakQtwIIHzAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DzT657soclws&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHiOQ9WoMXXQvfBqAiBtEImgna-mg&amp;amp;sig2=oC2AOgiSS_Ap2C-7dvP-Dw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.110151844,d.cGc&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; are my go-to&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m having lower back instability or hip tightness. I highly recommend checking out the mobility project for improving overall mobility and health while building strength and muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;next steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to give myself the weekend off and start back up on Monday (1/4/16) with Day B. While a disappointing start to the new year, I am very happy with my overall progress on this program and have never been more excited to work out. Even though the exercises are the same, each routine feels different because it is all about trying to increase volume through an increase in weight over 5 sets of 5. I have no doubt that I will be on my way to hitting 225# squat and deadlift and 145# bench in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is. Short and sweet. Until the next update&amp;hellip; Lift Heavy, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 1 &amp; 2 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 13:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the StrongLifts 5x5 program. For those of you unfamiliar with the training plan, it&amp;rsquo;s very simple and most workouts take an hour or less to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-stronglifts-5x5&#34;&gt;overview of stronglifts 5X5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-npDASfZJi1s/VnWXXfQvKtI/AAAAAAAAA0Y/n-Jb0SKgxvc/s1600/SL5x5_1%25262.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are two types of days for this program: Day A and Day B. The 5 exercises this program includes are Squats, Bench Press, Overhead Press, Barbell Rows, and Deadlifts. Each exercise is done for 5 sets of 5 reps with the exception of Deadlifts (I&amp;rsquo;ll explain that further in a moment). See the graphic below for the exercises and routine schedule for Day A and Day B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, you will want to do more on this program because it seems so simple. Do not do extra sets or reps or additional exercises! This is a 12-week + strength building program that forces progressive overload by increasing the weight by 2.5 - 5 lbs each day. You will burn yourself out if you add in additional work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-s47R91gqxX8/VnWl1J_iZ9I/AAAAAAAAA1s/Fj-epoNRI8E/s1600/5_5.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternating-workouts-days-a-and-b&#34;&gt;alternating workouts days a and b&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical schedule on StrongLifts 5x5 is set up alternating Days A and B. For example, the first week of the program goes A, B, A with at least 1 day of rest between each workout day. My first week was Thursday (Day A), Saturday (Day B), Monday (Day A). On the right, I have included the calendar of my workouts for the first two weeks of the program. I highly recommend using the StrongLifts App to help track your workouts and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wpwu3F2Juac/VnWfxuq3ctI/AAAAAAAAA1c/XgWeBZExexE/s1600/dec_calendar.png&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progress-weeks-1-2&#34;&gt;progress weeks 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Week 1 started off pretty slow, and I was very skeptical that my body could handle squatting 3x/week, Week 2 proved to me that this program is going to be awesome! So if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting off, give it at least 5 sessions to make your initial judgement. I especially like how the StrongLifts app has a timer to keep the sets going at an appropriate pace; after each set, once you log it, the app will tell you to take 90 seconds of rest if the set was easy or 3 minutes rest if it was challenging. If you missed any reps, it will tell you to take 5 minutes rest and provide encouragement that you will make all 5 reps the next set. Pretty great if you ask me! Below is the graph generated by the StrongLifts app for all 5 of my core lifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FgZSU473vMI/VnWfgHoYiJI/AAAAAAAAA1Q/b6ZnN_y6qhk/s1600/FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead press is in purple; Bench is in gray; Barbell row is orange; Squats are in blue; and deadlifts are in green. Not too bad for 5 sessions. My goal is to crush 200 lbs in the 12 weeks of the StrongLifts program. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty static in terms of progression these last two years; however, 2016 will be my year to change it up and #MakeItCount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-rant-about-nutrition&#34;&gt;a brief rant about nutrition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, with any strength training program, be sure you&amp;rsquo;re eating enough! Do not try to be in a caloric deficit or on a fat-burning program during StrongLifts. You will need the fuel (carbs!) to get through all your sets and progress. For someone who has always had the &amp;ldquo;diet-mind,&amp;rdquo; it will be tough to bump up the calories and eat more; however, if you want to feel good in the gym, become a better athlete, and recover at an optimal level, you must eat to perform. No this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean eat crap or junk food all day. It means making healthy choices and having a balance of all the macronutrient groups (proteins, carbs, fats). Personally, my ratios have been around 50% Carbs, 30% Protein, and 20% fats. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of food for someone who has been eating around BMR (bad idea, don&amp;rsquo;t do this); however, almost immediately after increasing my intake and upping my carbs, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt more refreshed, and more mentally focused on hitting new PR&amp;rsquo;s each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions about my progress or my opinions about the program. Until next review&amp;hellip;Stay Fit. Stay Strong. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>build muscle with stronglifts 5X5</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/build-muscle-stronglifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 23:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/build-muscle-stronglifts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So typically I like to plan out my routines and schedule what, when, and why I&amp;rsquo;m training and eating a certain way. In this case; however, I decided to jump head-first into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stronglifts.com/&#34;&gt;StrongLifts 5X5&lt;/a&gt; because, frankly, I&amp;rsquo;m tired of dancing around the bush with fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2EtzjoI-4ro/VmuoW5hWaLI/AAAAAAAAAzM/04pZQJxEQFU/s1600/is%2Bit%2Bin%2Byou%253F%2523makeitcount-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 12 weeks I will be training according to the StrongLifts 5X5 program and continuing to Eat To Perform. My 2016 goals include considerable strength gains, so to FINALLY meet these goals, I am going to give this 5X5 program a try. You can find my StrongLifts updates here. I will work in real-time so that you can see first-hand how good-bad-ugly this program ends up being. With that said, I am using this article to introduce the first Strategy in the #MAKEITCOUNT series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategy-1-accountability-everyone-wants-to-say-they-did-it-without-actually-doing-it&#34;&gt;strategy #1 accountability: everyone wants to say they did it, without actually doing it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be that person who commits to something and then fails to actually follow through with it. Now I understand some situations are circumstantial, but let&amp;rsquo;s face it, who likes excuses? Not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I will be spending the early part of winter working on my strength with StrongLifts 5X5, what will you be doing? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s starting to workout for the first time in ten years; maybe your goal is to start flossing twice a day (dental hygiene is important); maybe you&amp;rsquo;re starting a new job and your goal is to save for retirement; whatever your 2016 goals are, you have to jump all in and go for them. Challenge yourself to do something every day to work towards your goal. 2% changes each day add up to major improvements over the course of weeks, months, and years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Strategy #2&amp;hellip; #MAKEITCOUNT. Learn to become Accountable&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>