<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/fitness-gear/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. queenflex.com. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/fitness-gear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>daily fitness must-haves</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-must-haves/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 15:37:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/fitness-must-haves/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stop right there. Yes, you. Did you forget something?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me, you have a few staple items that you always leave the house with: wallet, keys, phone..(gum, ha)&amp;hellip;check. But what about the fitness enthusiasts out there. It seems like we are always carrying around more &lt;s&gt;random&lt;/s&gt; necessary things as we venture to work, the grocery store, or even the gym (gasp). So what things define you as part of the #fitfam? For me, I have a few staple items (other than those presented above) that seem to follow me wherever I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fitmark-bag&#34;&gt;Fitmark Bag&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://cdn.fitmarkbags.com//image/data/products/transporter-tote-2015/black/Transporter-Tote-Bag_black_front.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;45%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About two months ago, I was in the market for a meal-prep/work/all-around bag to replace my kindergarten lunch box. I figured since I am now in the working world, I owe it to myself to look the part. It took me awhile to decide on a meal-prep bag; there are so many choose from&amp;ndash;Six Pack Bags to Isobag to Fitmark to Target&amp;rsquo;s dollar deal. I originally started off with the Renee Tote from Six Pack Bags and as beautiful of a bag as it was when it arrived, I could barely fit my laptop or a book or anything (besides food) in it. Very disappointing to say the least. Instead of holding on to a $160 meal bag that I had no use for, I began some research into my next bag. In June, the TranSPORTer tote from Fitmark Bags came out in black. It has the ability to hold a Small BOX with two meal containers as well as serve as a full duffle bag. As soon as it arrived, I did a quick test for storage and usability, and the rest is history; I don&amp;rsquo;t leave my house without my TranSPORTer tote. Talk about the best of both worlds: store two-to-three meals, plus a laptop/books/drinks/workout clothes all in one bag. Wonderful! So to those of you out there looking for an all-around bag, I highly recommend taking a look at Fitmark&amp;rsquo;s products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;notebook-workout-log&#34;&gt;Notebook/Workout Log&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow I find myself listening to a podcast or reading an article or two and find myself jotting notes on random sheets of paper, only to lose those notes a week later. I decided to carry around a single-subject composition book along with my workout log so that I can keep all my fitness-related thoughts together in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My workout logs have changed shape and form over the years of lifting. Most recently I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to designing my own workout log in iBooks based on my routine over a 12-week period. I include each workout, the respective exercises, sets and reps within a table, which makes it seamlessly easy to track progress and continuously work towards achieving a PR or goal. Check out my FREE &lt;a href=&#34;http://queenflex.blogspot.com/p/official-workout-log.html&#34;&gt;downloadable workout training log&lt;/a&gt; template!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lacrosse-tennis-yoga-tuneup-balls&#34;&gt;Lacrosse/Tennis/Yoga TuneUp Balls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know when you&amp;rsquo;ll have a trigger point or shooting shoulder pain. So why not be prepared with the right tools? Also since migrating to a stand-up desk, my feet and calves can use some extra love throughout the day. Plus, some days are just meant for fidgeting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-2-gallon-water-jug&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Gallon Water Jug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;http://s4.thcdn.com/productimg/600/600/11133450-2084319696682723.jpg&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;
I never leave the house without my &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; Gallon water jug. While it probably looks silly to some, I&amp;rsquo;m always thirsty (especially in the Arizona heat), so I don&amp;rsquo;t mind that it becomes a conversation-starter in most social scenarios. Receive &lt;a href=&#34;http://us.myprotein.com/protein-accessories/myprotein-1-2-gallon-hydrator/11133450.html?feature=locale-popup&amp;amp;referringSite=myprotein_en_GB&amp;amp;countrySelected=Y&#34;&gt;10% off your order with the promo code &amp;ldquo;LIZ-R4T&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; gallon hydrator on myprotein.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are your daily must-haves? Do you use any of these items as religiously as me? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; Note: I do not represent Fitmark Bags in any way, shape, or form. The opinions of this article are strictly mine, and I have not been compensated to say anything written in this article about any of these staple items.&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>