<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/training/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/training/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>you don&#39;t know squat if you don&#39;t squat</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 21:10:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-2_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Article 2 of the &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series is brought to you by legs day. You don&amp;rsquo;t know squat, if you don&amp;rsquo;t squat! This article takes a step into my day, my workout, and my nutrition. Click to read more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rise-and-grind-it-s-legs-day-dec-6&#34;&gt;rise and grind, it&amp;rsquo;s legs day! - Dec 6&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, today was an early start. I woke up at about 5:10am for a 6am shift start. I arrived into the office and was able to grind out a lot of logistics for various projects I&amp;rsquo;m working on. And, it turns out I will be heading to Las Vegas in a MONTH for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ces.tech/&#34;&gt;Consumer Electronics Show (CES)&lt;/a&gt;! Tonight, I have a squat workout scheduled and as you may or may not know, I have a love-hate relationship with squats. While I think squats are key to having a solid and functional fitness foundation, form is critical to being able to move a lot of weight. I am still trying to perfect my squat form, and it&amp;rsquo;s been challenging returning to a &amp;ldquo;heavy&amp;rdquo; squat from a lower-back injury. Ever since sustaining the initial injury, my squats have taken a toll in terms of how much weight I can actually tollerate. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that 5/3/1 will help me take a few steps back, adjust my form, my breathing, and my technique, and ultimately allow me to get stronger. I thing the higher-volume nature of &amp;ldquo;Boring but Big&amp;rdquo; is just what I need to get confident and comfortable with performing the squatting movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;trying-so-hard-to-hit-those-macros&#34;&gt;trying so hard to hit those macros&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk nutrition for a little bit. I mentioned yesterday how difficult it&amp;rsquo;s been for me to hit my macros (155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats), lately. If you had asked me a year ago, I&amp;rsquo;d be able to hit those numbers at 3PM if I wasn&amp;rsquo;t careful. So I&amp;rsquo;m not really sure what&amp;rsquo;s up. My appetite has disappeared! Tracking my food has seemed to help, because no matter what I want to eat, it fits!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gluten-free diet has been really great so far in terms of how I feel and how I&amp;rsquo;ve been digesting. I haven&amp;rsquo;t noticed too many changes with my skin, but it&amp;rsquo;s only been a few days, so I&amp;rsquo;m sure it takes time. The downfall with being gluten-free is that I feel so limited with what I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; eat. It&amp;rsquo;s a choice to eat this way, and I&amp;rsquo;m doing it because I think I&amp;rsquo;ll have a greater health benefit long-term. I just think I&amp;rsquo;m going to need to find other carbohydrates that are gluten-free and low in sugar (&lt;em&gt;good luck&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some foods that are becoming staples to my diet right now are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apples&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;strawberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chex/GF cereal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almonds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Almond milk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sweet Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Potatoes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown Rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Beans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chicken&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lean ground beef (90-96% lean)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whey Protein&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corn tortillas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60% dark chocolate chips&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;50&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;50&lt;/sub&gt; salad mix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pickles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to mix it up and have a bit more variety, but I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to be limited when it comes to staying gluten-free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-and-feeling-under-the-weather-dec-7-and-8&#34;&gt;health and feeling &amp;ldquo;under the weather&amp;rdquo; - Dec 7 and 8&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last article I spoke a lot about how &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt; this routine was going to be. Unfortunately, that was before I got sick. So these past few days I&amp;rsquo;ve been battling off a headcold, therefore, I didn&amp;rsquo;t train on Wednesday or Thursday. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping that I will get back to the gym on Friday for Bench Press, but it&amp;rsquo;s going to depend on how I feel and how much food I&amp;rsquo;m eating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=Life always throws a monkey-wrench. Just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans. @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;Life always throws a monkey-wrench, and just when you think everything is going to go your way, something changes in your plans.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have to just go with it, and make the most of what you set out to do. I want to nip this cold in the bud, so I&amp;rsquo;m doing everything I can to take care of myself and make a 80-90% recovery before going back to the gym. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about being &amp;ldquo;tough&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;bro&amp;rdquo; or whatever when it comes to training while sick. I personally think that it&amp;rsquo;s dumb to train when you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling well. Your mind will be focused on how terrible you feel rather than focusing on perfecting your form. Rest up, get over the cold or illness, and the gym will be there when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to return.
The other part of training while sick is that your body is already trying to &amp;ldquo;fight&amp;rdquo; off the illness. When you throw in additional stressors, such as lack of sleep, lifting, etc., it makes it difficult for your body to get rid of it. I think this is why people end up with these &amp;ldquo;lingering&amp;rdquo; colds for weeks and months. They don&amp;rsquo;t give their bodies&amp;rsquo; the breaks they need in order to see full recovery. So, do yourself a favor and sleep!
For me, I notice the onset of an illness when I don&amp;rsquo;t get 7-8 hours of sleep consistently, and I am working 10+ hour days, and working out, and doing too much. So the illness is an alarm telling me &amp;ldquo;hey! you need to take a break!&amp;rdquo; So tonight&amp;rsquo;s chest workout is still tentative. It&amp;rsquo;s about 9:30am here, and I have many hours to figure out if I&amp;rsquo;m going to train tonight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think I&amp;rsquo;m going to cut this article off here, but thank you, if you have read this far, and I will be back with another article on Day 3 of 5/3/1, whether that is tonight or this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have a question or comment? Find me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>it shouldn&#39;t be this easy</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/article-1_5-3-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to write a series of articles on my experience with training. This is the intro article for my &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; series. Over the next 8 weeks, I will be doing 5/3/1 with the focus on body recomposition and strength gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider this like your typical fitness youtuber&amp;rsquo;s vlog without the video edits. I&amp;rsquo;m going to go into my routine, my day-to-day training progress, and some tips to help you along the way. Let&amp;rsquo;s get to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finishing-up-hypertrophy-training&#34;&gt;Finishing up Hypertrophy Training&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So these last few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on hypertrophy training with 3-4 sets of 10-15 reps: getting the volume up (&lt;em&gt;weight x reps x sets&lt;/em&gt;) while maintaining form. Each workout I try to increase the weight I did the previous time by at least 5 or 10 pounds. If I previously did sets with a weight of 50, then I&amp;rsquo;ll go to 55 or 60 lbs for the current workout. It&amp;rsquo;s time to shift gears and focus on getting stronger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-the-program-a-very-quick-5-3-1-summary&#34;&gt;Getting the program &amp;amp; a very quick 5/3/1 summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My next training plan will focus on lean strength gains. I&amp;rsquo;m picking up Jim Wendler&amp;rsquo;s 5/3/1 from Dec 4 - Jan 31. I generated my program plan using &lt;a href=&#34;http://strengthstandards.co&#34;&gt;Strength Standards&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5/3/1 is a training protocol created by Jim Wendler. One &amp;ldquo;training cycle&amp;rdquo; of this program is 4-weeks long, with four &amp;ldquo;training routines&amp;rdquo; each week. The training routines are centered around improving the &amp;ldquo;big 4&amp;rdquo; (bench, squat, deadlift, and press) plus a few accessory movements. At the start of every routine, there are three warm-up sets, followed by 3 working sets. The number of reps done is based on the training week: week 1 is 5+ reps, week 2 is 3+ reps, week 3 is 1+ rep(s). The goal is to hit a minimum of the prescribed number of reps for each set. Week 4 is a deload week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Week 5&amp;rsquo;s training numbers are determined off of week 3&amp;rsquo;s 1RM lifts:
- For squats and deadlifts, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 10lbs.
- For bench and press, take 90% of your week 3 1RM and add 5lbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continue subsequential cycles of 5/3/1 using the format outlined above for weeks 5-8. For more detailed information on 5/3/1 check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/531-how-to-build-pure-strength&#34;&gt;full program here.&lt;/a&gt;  Now let&amp;rsquo;s get into this first article of my &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; blog series!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: There are many variations of 5/3/1, but for this series, I will be completing two cycles of &amp;ldquo;Boring But Big.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;it-shouldn-t-be-this-easy&#34;&gt;it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be this easy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said above, last week, I generated my 5/3/1 program using Strength Standards and my most recent stats for each of the &amp;ldquo;big 4.&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m following the 90% of 1RM training protocol, so the numbers I&amp;rsquo;m hitting this week look and seem &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; light. I don&amp;rsquo;t suspect I will see a whole lot of difficulties until week 3. The nature of 5/3/1 is to start a few steps backwards in weight and then work up to heavier-than-normal weights (3 steps backwards and 5 steps forwards&amp;hellip; or something like that). I haven&amp;rsquo;t used this style of training before, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to seeing what strength gains occur over the next eight weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s military press routine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Warm-up:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;45 x 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60 x 5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;65 x 5+ (going for as many reps possible - I estimate that I can do about 12-15 at 65 lbs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Accessory work:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;military press:  5 x 10 at 40 lb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;chin-ups: 5 x 10 at bodyweight (going to do a &amp;ldquo;rest-pause&amp;rdquo; style on this exercise)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;nutrition-life-and-other-musings&#34;&gt;nutrition, life, and other musings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Monday, so my day started very early. I woke up at 4:15am to be at work, bright-eyed and bushy-tailed for a 5:30am start. Lately, I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as hungry, so eating all of my macros has been a huge challenge. (Since when is 2000 calories &amp;ldquo;a lot&amp;rdquo;??!) This week my macros are 155 protein, 250 carbs, 47 fats: a nice 30-50-20 split.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also decided to go &amp;ldquo;gluten-free&amp;rdquo; during these eight weeks because I have been having a lot of issues with acne. In the past, when I wasn&amp;rsquo;t eating as flexibly, and had a staple of about eight different foods (none of which were processed or contained gluten), I had the clearest skin of my life. So, these next few weeks, I am going to completely avoid eating gluten, which means I won&amp;rsquo;t be enduldging in my &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; favorite post-deadlift meal of waffles. :( I&amp;rsquo;ll keep you posted on my progress with a &lt;em&gt;gluten-free &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iifym.com&#34;&gt;iifym&lt;/a&gt; nutrition plan&lt;/em&gt;. Not sure how hypocritical that sounds, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s going to solve a lot of the skin problems I&amp;rsquo;ve been having.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toughest thing about being gluten-free and on iifym is CARBS. Seriously, how many potatoes or servings of rice or bowls of gluten-free Chex can a person eat in a day? It&amp;rsquo;s been a struggle to eat enough carbs and enough calories lately. Throw in a lack of hunger, and it&amp;rsquo;s a short recipe for disaster. While it may not seem as dramatic as I&amp;rsquo;m making it, (&lt;em&gt;it&amp;rsquo;s not&lt;/em&gt;), I am planning to start cutting in exactly four-weeks from today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why&amp;rsquo;s that such a problem?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, if I&amp;rsquo;m in a deficit now, then I will have to drop my calories even lower to be in a deficit then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/home?status=Combine a caloric deficit with the proper weight training program and consistency, and you will lose weight! @lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Weight loss is a seemingly easy thing: combine a modest 25% caloric deficit with the proper weight training program, and a lot of consistency, and you will lose weight!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difficult part about being at a slight deficit now is that my &amp;ldquo;modest 25% caloric deficit&amp;rdquo; at the start of my weight loss journey, will end up being less than 1500 calories, which is pretty darn low for me. So now is the time to get and keep my calories up. Starting today, I will do my very best to eat to my numbers! And to keep me accountable, add me on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/stronglizlifts&#34;&gt;MyFitnessPal&lt;/a&gt;. I will be tracking my foods and supplements on there daily, so if you&amp;rsquo;re looking for food options or just want to see what I&amp;rsquo;m up to, that will be the most up-to-date reference. I will also add in measurements (weight, % fat, waist, hips, chest, arms, thighs, etc.) at a minimum each week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-goals-and-aspirations-for-this-series-the-5-3-1-program-and-my-physique&#34;&gt;my goals and aspirations for this series, the 5/3/1 program, and my physique&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What better place and time to outline my purpose for this than right here and right now?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to create this online blog series &amp;ldquo;life on 5/3/1&amp;rdquo; to outline the day-to-day challenges, struggles, successes, and indifferences that come along with training for strength and body recomposition. One of the coolest parts about doing a series like this is being able to provide the &lt;em&gt;female&lt;/em&gt; perspective of the 5/3/1 program. I&amp;rsquo;m excited to compare my progress and results to previous training programs and to see if this method works well for me (and is enjoyable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;this-series&#34;&gt;this series:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;posting on each training day for a minimum of four posts per week (32 posts total)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;include pictures and media during my training, meal prep, and weigh-ins, where appropriate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;5-3-1-goals&#34;&gt;5/3/1 goals:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;achieve the prescribed 1RMs for week 3&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain the training schedule (no missed training sessions)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;perform 10 reps of chin-ups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;my-physique&#34;&gt;my physique:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;maintain body composition: ~154 lbs at ~24% bodyfat at the end of December 2016&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;body recomposition: ~145 lb at 22% bodyfat at the end of January 2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;clearer skin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;better digestion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;restful sleep: ~7 hours avg per night&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a 10-minute cool-down routine</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2016 10:54:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/ten-minute-routine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oftentimes we overlook the cool-down routine as much as our warm-up routine. I think it has something to do with wanting to get to the exciting part of the workout and both warm-ups and cool-downs are &amp;ldquo;boring.&amp;rdquo; I used to think that these routines were a waste of time, but that was before I knew just how much benefit they provide the body. This article explains a quick, ten-minute recovery routine that you can do practically anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get started, you will need the following things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stopwatch or Timer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A chair or something about 2-feet off the ground&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flat Surface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Music (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This routine is a circuit of four different exercises that are best performed post-workout or at a time when you want to &amp;ldquo;relax.&amp;rdquo; They are taken from the exercises recommended by Maraynn Berry&amp;rsquo;s article, &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/video/5-simple-exercises-to-eliminate-neck-pain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;5 Simple Exercises to Eliminate Neck Pain.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be alarmed. You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be experiencing neck pain in order to do these exercises! I find that this condensed version allows my body to &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;relax&amp;rdquo; especially after a heavy lifting session. This routine is especially beneficial for desk jockies because it promotes proper posture from the neck, through the shoulders, down to the hips and adductors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each exercise in this routine, you will hold the position for two minutes. There are five exercises total, therefore, ten-minutes of &amp;ldquo;working&amp;rdquo; time for this routine. I recommend you read through the exercise, and then give them a try! Let&amp;rsquo;s get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-1-u-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 1:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Back:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lay on the floor with your legs propped up on a chair or object 2-feet tall.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your legs should be at a 90-degree angle to your hips. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-2-u-static-scapular-extension&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 2:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Scapular Extension:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start on all fours, ensuring that your wrists are directly under your shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Walk your hands about 6-inches in front of the starting position.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shift your hips forward so that your weight and shoulders are over your wrists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep your elbows straight and allow your shoulder blades to sink down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let your head hang. Release any tension in your neck and mouth. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;It will be challenging, but try to hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br&gt; While it seems counter-intuitive to hold this position, since we spend most of our day in a slouched over position, this exercise moves the scapula into extension, promoting realignment to the shoulders.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-3-u-repeat-exercise-1-static-back&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 3:&lt;/u&gt;  Repeat Exercise 1, Static Back.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-4-u-wall-hold&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 4:&lt;/u&gt;  Wall Hold:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sit on the floor with your back and head against a wall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull your shoulder blades together and down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rest your legs straight out in front of you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flex your quads. Flex your feet towards your body. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-exercise-5-u-static-adductor-frog&#34;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Exercise 5:&lt;/u&gt;  Static Adductor (Frog):&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start in a seated position with the bottoms of your feet touching each other (a.k.a. butterfly position). Make sure that your feet are aligned with the center of your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lie back and relax every muscle in your body.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Put your arms at a 45-degree angle to your sides with your palms facing up. &lt;br&gt; &lt;em&gt;Hold this position for 2 minutes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;~&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give this routine a try after your next workout or before bed. After a week of doing this routine, it&amp;rsquo;ll become second-nature and you&amp;rsquo;ll find that it helps with recovery and &amp;ldquo;resets&amp;rdquo; your posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does your cool-down routine look like? &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/home?status=@lizmillerfit Recover with this easy, 10-minute routine www.queenflex.com/post/ten-minute-routine/&#34;&gt;Tweet @lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; with your tips and tricks for improving recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;additional-resources-for-prehab-rehab-and-recovery&#34;&gt;Additional Resources for Prehab, Rehab, and Recovery:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/au/learn/banish-pain-permanently-basic-drills-to-repair-your-posture?page=0,0&#34;&gt;Banish Pain Permanently by Maryann Berry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://uprightposturefitness.com/sitting-floor-exercise/&#34;&gt;Sitting Floor Exercise by Upright Posture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.huffingtonpost.com/news/egoscue-method/&#34;&gt;Egoscue Method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;McKenzie Method / MDT&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>my perspective on daily undulating periodization (dup)</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/daily-undulating-periodization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 18:30:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/daily-undulating-periodization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Daily Undulating Periodization (DUP) is all the rage these days. For a &amp;ldquo;program hopper&amp;rdquo; like myself, I find that DUP is a great way to feel like you&amp;rsquo;re doing something different each training session, without actually sacrificing progress, strength, or hypertrophy goals. The structure for DUP varies from person-to-person; however, since I am fairly new to this concept of training, I think it&amp;rsquo;s important to shed some light and decompose the process of setting up a DUP training program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also a few things to consider before writing your own DUP program: strength vs. hypertrophy, number of rest days, personal enjoyment exercises, etc. With that said, I have written this article to help you better assess DUP and whether or not it is the right programming style for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let me introduce you to my little friend,&amp;rdquo; DUP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I jump right into my process for DUP programming, I&amp;rsquo;d like to briefly explain the principles behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jmaxfitness.com/blog/daily-undulating-periodization/&#34;&gt;Daily Undulating Periodization.&lt;/a&gt; The concept is summarized in rather simple terms: for each training day, the routine includes exercises that are assigned a number of reps (rep scheme). The rep scheme changes each training session over the course of a training period (usually 4-6 weeks). Rep schemes are typically in one of three categories: strength (4-6 reps), hypertrophy (8-12 reps), endurance (15-20 reps). If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to become a more &amp;ldquo;balanced&amp;rdquo; athlete with your training, you may choose to have different rep schemes within the same training session (i.e. exercise 1 for 4 reps, exercise 2 for 8 reps, exercise 3 for 15 reps) or alternate rep schemes throughout a training week. In order to create a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muscleforlife.com/guide-to-muscle-hypertrophy-muscle-growth/&#34;&gt;progressive overload&lt;/a&gt; using DUP, you must increase volume your volume. Training volume can be increased a number of ways, but my two go-to methods are 1) using an as many reps as possible (AMRAP) set to determine whether or not you&amp;rsquo;re ready to increase the weight the next training week; or 2) increasing the number of sets each week within the training period (weight stays the same through the training period). Ok, so now that you have a brief understanding of DUP, I&amp;rsquo;d like to provide a simple methodology to create a DUP training program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;programming-for-daily-undulating-periodization&#34;&gt;programming for daily undulating periodization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;balance: the human body is a complex system, so training routines are meant to be simple.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-dup-routine-has-four-main-components&#34;&gt;a DUP routine has four main components:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fundamental Exercises&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rep Scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set Scheme&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Period Length/Deload Schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;fundamental-exercises&#34;&gt;fundamental exercises&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I talk about &amp;ldquo;fundamental exercises&amp;rdquo;, what I really mean are your &amp;ldquo;main lifts&amp;rdquo; or the &lt;strong&gt;compound lifts&lt;/strong&gt; you want to include in your program: squats, bench, deadlifts, presses, and variations of these lifts. What I typically do is pick three compound lifts to work in a training period. For example, my current program includes front squats, barbell bench press, and rack pulls. The goal is to pick the exercises that you need to work. Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;rep-scheme&#34;&gt;rep scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have your exercises picked, you need to decide on
your rep scheme. As I stated in the introduction, you can either train
the same rep scheme for each exercise or have a separate rep scheme for each exercise and rotate them throughout a training week. My current program does the latter and 4, 6, and 10 reps each training day, one rep scheme per exercise (i.e. front squat for 4 reps, bench press for 6 reps, and rack pull for 10 reps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-scheme&#34;&gt;set scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ok, that&amp;rsquo;s great, but how many sets should I be doing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer to that question depends on how you want to attack progressive overload. The idea is to have as few variables as possible, while still seeing a maximum result [check out this article on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.4hourlife.com/2012/11/26/the-4-hour-chef-finding-the-minimum-effectiv%20e-dose-med-of-life/&#34;&gt;Minimum Effective Dose&lt;/a&gt;]. For the sake of keeping this article concise, I will only touch on two ways to determine your set scheme: keep the number of sets constant throughout the training cycle and increase the weight used for each exercise each week or increase the number of sets each week while keeping the weight used for each exercise constant. Right now my training period is four weeks long; the first week I do 2 sets; second week 3 sets; third week is 4 sets (3 sets + 1 set AMRAP); fourth week is 2 sets or deload. You can follow this pattern as you wish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The former method calls for increasing the weight by 5-10 lbs per exercise per week as long as you have achieved all of your sets and reps for each exercise. If you fail your bench press at 225 for 7 reps when you should have gotten 10, then you probably aren&amp;rsquo;t ready to increase the weight for that exercise. The goal is to make progress on your lifts without sacrificing form, mobility, and overall quality of the movement. A good way to test whether or not you are ready to move up in weight is to do an AMRAP set on your last set of the week prior to deload (i.e. for me, on my 3rd week, my fourth set is an AMRAP set). If you beat the number of reps than prescribed for &amp;gt;85% of your training days for each exercise, respectively, then you&amp;rsquo;re ready to go up in weight on the first week of the next training cycle. Now let&amp;rsquo;s talk about training period length and deloading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;period-length-deload-schedule&#34;&gt;period length/deload schedule&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, you need to decide how long you want your training period to last. A training period can last anywhere from 4-6 or 4-8 weeks, but ultimately depends on your preference, how your body feels with training, and the overall progress you&amp;rsquo;re making. For me, I like to take a deload week on the 4th week of the training cycle by dropping back to 2 sets as I do on week 1. This allows me to recover better and reduces the likelihood that I get burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also follow a 2-days on, 1 day off schedule where the off-day alternates between either a full day of rest/yoga day or an &amp;ldquo;accessory day&amp;rdquo; where I focus on 10-12 isolation movements to help with hypertrophy. For the accessory day, I follow the same set scheme as the week and keep the rep scheme constant at 10-15 reps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.t-nation.com/workouts/double-stimulation-training&#34;&gt;interesting finding&lt;/a&gt; that says 24 hours after training a muscle group, you have greater ability to increase muscle mass by training it again during that timeframe. This is mainly why I use a 2-day on, 1 day off pattern rather than 5-day on, 2 day off training pattern. I also believe that since you&amp;rsquo;re undulating the rep scheme each day, you have the ability to recover slightly, but also stimulate the muscle enough to continue mass building. I am still playing around with how this works for me personally, but I&amp;rsquo;d be curious to know if any of you have had success with this concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-video&#34;&gt;reference video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still slightly confused? Have a look at this video for a visual demonstration of programming for DUP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;separator&#34; style=&#34;clear: both; text-align: center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe allowfullscreen=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;YOUTUBE-iframe-video&#34; data-thumbnail-src=&#34;https://i.ytimg.com/vi/maE93vRZpAU/0.jpg&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;300px&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/maE93vRZpAU?feature=player_embedded&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;200%&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: Consult with your doctor before starting a new exercise regime.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>combat office slouch</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2016 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/office-slouch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;stop-being-such-a-slouch&#34;&gt;Stop being such a slouch!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are like me and work a desk job, it is easy to turn into a slouched over mess. With all the hype out there about &amp;ldquo;sitting is the new smoking&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;prehab is rehab&amp;rdquo;, I have decided to create a list of the most realistic exercises that you can do at the office to help improve posture, mobility, and overall happiness. &lt;em&gt;And hopefully prevent you from looking like a stupid fool, rolling around on the floor next to your cubical.&lt;/em&gt; ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Disclaimer: the advice I&amp;rsquo;m providing here is based off of my personal experience with chronic low back, hip, neck, and shoulder pain, and does not substitute or replace medical advice. These tricks have worked for me based on meeting with a physical therapist for my own mobility/stability issues; however, everybody is different, and it&amp;rsquo;s best to seek an opinion from your doctor prior to trying a rehab/stretch/strength program like the one I am about to outline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to working a full-time desk job, I was a college student. When people think college, they may think parties, alcohol, weight gain, and craziness; however, the reality of my college experience was hair-pulling, weight loss, walking everywhere, and craziness. Once I found myself sitting at the same desk for hours on end with little reason to move other than to get water or use the bathroom, I realized I was becoming a slouched over mess. [Cue the mobility issues, back and hip pain.]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s this &amp;ldquo;neat&amp;rdquo; little thing about exercise: you can work out for an hour—maybe even two hours—a day, but if you are &lt;a href=&#34;http://breakingmuscle.com/health-medicine/its-not-your-metabolism-its-your-neat-thats-stopping-your-fat-loss&#34;&gt;inactive for 8-15 hours a day, then exercise less effective&lt;/a&gt;. So why is that so “neat” you may ask? Well it has to do with &lt;strong&gt;N.E.A.T or non-exercise activity thermogenesis&lt;/strong&gt;, aka “what you do when you’re not exercising, which burns calories to keep you alive.” So if you put yourself into a lethargic, slumped over position all day long, and think you will have great mobility for your squat session that evening, well good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-i-prevent-becoming-an-immobile-mess-of-a-human-being&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;How do I prevent becoming an immobile mess of a human being?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer:&lt;/u&gt; get off your butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Simple answer explained:&lt;/u&gt; Every 30-45 minutes, get up and perform a series of mobility/stability exercises to counterbalance the poor posture from sitting. Think back to eighth-grade science class where you learned about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.physicsclassroom.com/class/newtlaws/Lesson-4/Newton-s-Third-Law&#34;&gt;Newton’s Third Law&lt;/a&gt;. (For you engineers out there, forgive me, this was a very recent topic for y’all). Newton’s Third Law states that for every action force there is a reaction force equal in magnitude and opposite in direction. For example, if you’re sitting in a slouched over position, inducing flexion on your spine, it’d be wise to get up every half hour and do some back bends to induce extension. Refer to the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://teachmeanatomy.info/wp-content/uploads/Terms-of-Movement-Flexion-and-Extension-CC-1024x815.jpg&#34; width=&#34;60%&#34; height=&#34;45%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-15-minute-routine-to-combat-office-slouch&#34;&gt;A 15-minute routine to combat office slouch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This could be a reason why people who live in a constant state of flexion throw their backs out when they pick up a basket of laundry; it’s because they’re inducing extension on a spine that has been molded into the flexion world. It’s time to teach our spines, and other body parts for that matter, what neutral looks like. To do this, I have developed a short list of five exercises that I think are the most effective for resetting the body and prehab for future injuries. You only need therabands/resistance bands to perform all the exercises.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: If you live in the world of &lt;u&gt;extension&lt;/u&gt;, you would probably benefit from &lt;u&gt;flexion&lt;/u&gt; exercises instead of exercises two and three.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder W&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end keep your elbows by your sides. Contract your lats and pull the band apart forming a &amp;ldquo;w&amp;rdquo; with your arms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_G0feLqXA0E&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standing back-bends (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Position your feet slightly behind your hips. Place your hands on your low back (or table as shown in the video), and slowly bend backwards. You will feel this stretch in your lower back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HjXCgxajrY4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prone Press-ups (extension)&lt;/strong&gt;
Lie on the floor and place your hands slightly wider than shoulder-width. Contract your lats and press up with your arms. You should feel a stretch in the low back. Exhale at the top of the movement for a deeper low-back stretch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qCOt_Em11g8&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shoulder Stars&lt;/strong&gt;
Grasp a theraband on either end and hit 6 points to form the shape of a star as shown in the video. Contract your lats and make sure that your shoulders are relaxed and not shrugged up towards your ears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xTCvBqZz3Bc&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bodyweight Squats&lt;/strong&gt;
Make sure your feet are shoulder-width apart and that you contract your glutes while hinging at the hips. When you come down, try to break just below parallel and come back up. If you feel this in your lower back, you should compare your form to the example in the video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&#34;90%&#34; height=&#34;75%&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/p3g4wAsu0R4&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to perform these exercises every 30-45 minutes (set a timer!) throughout the work day to prevent poor posture and to prehab the body from potential future injuries. Hopefully, when you&amp;rsquo;re ready to hit the gym, your body is already primed for the upcoming movements and you&amp;rsquo;ll be less stiff and sore afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give these exercises a try, and let me know if they work for you!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 5 &amp; 6 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk5-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2016 13:25:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk5-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just say StrongLifts and I have a &lt;strong&gt;LOVE-HATE&lt;/strong&gt; relationship these past 2 weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen some major strength gains for bench press (up to 110# 5X5); however, I&amp;rsquo;ve had to reduce the volume of my deadlifts and barbell rows due to low back fatigue and stiffness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://1.bp.blogspot.com/-sIsl0t4PpBg/VpvVMDXm_4I/AAAAAAAAA6A/1VZUrfJ7IPA/s1600/a%2Bqueenflex.blogspot.com%2Breview.jpg&#34; width=&#34;70%&#34; height=&#34;20%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this program is very strenuous on the body and ample recovery is necessary in order to progress by at least 5 lbs each session. I also have never continuously followed a &amp;ldquo;strength building&amp;rdquo; program, where increased volume is a priority. I honestly can say that I LOVE this way of training because it forces you to give everything you&amp;rsquo;ve got and leaves you feeling extremely &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; afterwards. It&amp;rsquo;s an addictive feeling, and I&amp;rsquo;m growing to love every training session just a little more. It&amp;rsquo;s become more about ME vs. ME as opposed to  ME vs everyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pause a moment and discuss appropriate nutrition for StrongLifts 5X5. You must eat on this program. Let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST EAT ON THIS PROGRAM.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do not fuel yourself appropriately for these workouts, you will not be able to give the lifts 100% effort. You&amp;rsquo;ll pretty much feel like crap and want to writher up and die. Now that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration; however, YOU MUST EAT if you want to hit PR&amp;rsquo;s and advance your lifts. To do this, it&amp;rsquo;s very suitable to load carbohydrates around your workout. &lt;a href=&#34;http://staging.eattoperform.com/2013/06/20/eight-nutrition-tips/&#34;&gt;2:1 carbohydrates-protein ratio is fine&lt;/a&gt;. I typically have my pre-workout meal about an hour to an hour and a half prior to lifting. My post-workout meal (PWO) is directly after I cool down/stretch and consists of 2:1 fast-digesting carbs (sugars) to fast absorption whey protein isolate. I am also working to become more consistent with taking &lt;a href=&#34;https://examine.com/supplements/Creatine/&#34;&gt;5g of Creatine Monohydrate&lt;/a&gt; PWO to help with muscle recovery and carbohydrate absorption. For an example of a typical day-in-the-life of Liz, check out my MyFitnessPal diary, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.myfitnesspal.com/food/diary/stronglizlifts?date=2016-01-16&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing to consider when doing any sort of strength building program is recovery. You must allocate rest days on this program. Again, let me repeat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;YOU MUST RECOVER ON THIS PROGRAM. DO NOT CUT REST DAYS!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recovery days are CRITICAL on this program. If you never rest, you&amp;rsquo;ll never recover, and therefore, you&amp;rsquo;ll never feel &amp;ldquo;ready&amp;rdquo; to increase your lifts. You&amp;rsquo;ll be in a continual state of soreness, and trust me, it&amp;rsquo;s not fun. Give yourself extra days to recover if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling worn out. You&amp;rsquo;ll feel better and be mentally ready to give it your all in the gym. Remember, heavy, high-volume workouts are tearing your body down. You need time to allow your body to fix the tears and build new tissues and blood vessels to support muscle growth. &lt;strong&gt;Do yourself a favor and rest.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All and all, StrongLifts has given me a platform to start off my strength training and a flexible plan to meet my weight training goals. I highly recommend jumping in and giving it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 3 &amp; 4 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 22:32:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk3-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks on the StrongLifts program have been both rewarding and extremely challenging. Between Christmas, New Years, and traveling with family, as well as keeping up with my Eat To Perform numbers, I added about 20 lbs to my Squat and hit PRs on DeadLifts and Bench.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each workout is increasingly difficult and recovery and pre-workout nutrition are key to having successful sessions. It&amp;rsquo;s safe to say I finished 2015 with a bang, and certainly look forward to the remaining two-thirds of the StrongLifts [starter] program. I plan to reassess my goals and progress in early March to determine whether or not I want to continue StrongLifts for another cycle or to try something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-njamapHPYGg/Voc8zbOX2UI/AAAAAAAAA3o/1irFK5yhA9U/s1600/STRONGLIFTS%2B5X5-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;today-s-workout-day-a-squat-bench-row&#34;&gt;today&amp;rsquo;s workout - day a: squat, bench, row&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My lifts today; however, were slightly off, ringing in the new year with a less-than-perfect workout. I missed all my working sets 5X5 for Squats and Rows due to lower back instability and fuzziness. Instead I hit a PR on bench for 5X5 and proceeded to work on my posterior chain mobility and flexibility. Some of my favorite mobility workouts are from Kelly Starrett of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mobilitywod.com/&#34;&gt;mobilityWod&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi099DokYrKAhVPxGMKHfezDmAQtwIIIDAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DJBHzXF-mVjY&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaLWLA1UMVOUFEO6OzZqgok1GmKw&amp;amp;sig2=vz_aHpCAV1Y7K4uGt-dXpw&#34;&gt;This video&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwiq3O6AkorKAhVY-2MKHVVdBakQtwIIHzAB&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.youtube.com%2Fwatch%3Fv%3DzT657soclws&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHiOQ9WoMXXQvfBqAiBtEImgna-mg&amp;amp;sig2=oC2AOgiSS_Ap2C-7dvP-Dw&amp;amp;bvm=bv.110151844,d.cGc&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; are my go-to&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m having lower back instability or hip tightness. I highly recommend checking out the mobility project for improving overall mobility and health while building strength and muscle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-steps&#34;&gt;next steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving forward&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m planning to give myself the weekend off and start back up on Monday (1/4/16) with Day B. While a disappointing start to the new year, I am very happy with my overall progress on this program and have never been more excited to work out. Even though the exercises are the same, each routine feels different because it is all about trying to increase volume through an increase in weight over 5 sets of 5. I have no doubt that I will be on my way to hitting 225# squat and deadlift and 145# bench in 2016!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There it is. Short and sweet. Until the next update&amp;hellip; Lift Heavy, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stronglifts 5X5 - week 1 &amp; 2 review</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk1-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2015 13:47:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/stronglifts-wk1-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past week or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the StrongLifts 5x5 program. For those of you unfamiliar with the training plan, it&amp;rsquo;s very simple and most workouts take an hour or less to complete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview-of-stronglifts-5x5&#34;&gt;overview of stronglifts 5X5&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-npDASfZJi1s/VnWXXfQvKtI/AAAAAAAAA0Y/n-Jb0SKgxvc/s1600/SL5x5_1%25262.jpg&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
There are two types of days for this program: Day A and Day B. The 5 exercises this program includes are Squats, Bench Press, Overhead Press, Barbell Rows, and Deadlifts. Each exercise is done for 5 sets of 5 reps with the exception of Deadlifts (I&amp;rsquo;ll explain that further in a moment). See the graphic below for the exercises and routine schedule for Day A and Day B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naturally, you will want to do more on this program because it seems so simple. Do not do extra sets or reps or additional exercises! This is a 12-week + strength building program that forces progressive overload by increasing the weight by 2.5 - 5 lbs each day. You will burn yourself out if you add in additional work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;center&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-s47R91gqxX8/VnWl1J_iZ9I/AAAAAAAAA1s/Fj-epoNRI8E/s1600/5_5.png&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;50%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;alternating-workouts-days-a-and-b&#34;&gt;alternating workouts days a and b&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A typical schedule on StrongLifts 5x5 is set up alternating Days A and B. For example, the first week of the program goes A, B, A with at least 1 day of rest between each workout day. My first week was Thursday (Day A), Saturday (Day B), Monday (Day A). On the right, I have included the calendar of my workouts for the first two weeks of the program. I highly recommend using the StrongLifts App to help track your workouts and progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; hspace=&#34;10&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-wpwu3F2Juac/VnWfxuq3ctI/AAAAAAAAA1c/XgWeBZExexE/s1600/dec_calendar.png&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;progress-weeks-1-2&#34;&gt;progress weeks 1 &amp;amp; 2&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Week 1 started off pretty slow, and I was very skeptical that my body could handle squatting 3x/week, Week 2 proved to me that this program is going to be awesome! So if you&amp;rsquo;re just starting off, give it at least 5 sessions to make your initial judgement. I especially like how the StrongLifts app has a timer to keep the sets going at an appropriate pace; after each set, once you log it, the app will tell you to take 90 seconds of rest if the set was easy or 3 minutes rest if it was challenging. If you missed any reps, it will tell you to take 5 minutes rest and provide encouragement that you will make all 5 reps the next set. Pretty great if you ask me! Below is the graph generated by the StrongLifts app for all 5 of my core lifts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;15&#34; src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-FgZSU473vMI/VnWfgHoYiJI/AAAAAAAAA1Q/b6ZnN_y6qhk/s1600/FullSizeRender.jpg&#34; width=&#34;35%&#34; height=&#34;15%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overhead press is in purple; Bench is in gray; Barbell row is orange; Squats are in blue; and deadlifts are in green. Not too bad for 5 sessions. My goal is to crush 200 lbs in the 12 weeks of the StrongLifts program. I&amp;rsquo;ve been pretty static in terms of progression these last two years; however, 2016 will be my year to change it up and #MakeItCount.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-rant-about-nutrition&#34;&gt;a brief rant about nutrition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, with any strength training program, be sure you&amp;rsquo;re eating enough! Do not try to be in a caloric deficit or on a fat-burning program during StrongLifts. You will need the fuel (carbs!) to get through all your sets and progress. For someone who has always had the &amp;ldquo;diet-mind,&amp;rdquo; it will be tough to bump up the calories and eat more; however, if you want to feel good in the gym, become a better athlete, and recover at an optimal level, you must eat to perform. No this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean eat crap or junk food all day. It means making healthy choices and having a balance of all the macronutrient groups (proteins, carbs, fats). Personally, my ratios have been around 50% Carbs, 30% Protein, and 20% fats. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of food for someone who has been eating around BMR (bad idea, don&amp;rsquo;t do this); however, almost immediately after increasing my intake and upping my carbs, I&amp;rsquo;ve felt more refreshed, and more mentally focused on hitting new PR&amp;rsquo;s each session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tweet &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/lizmillerfit&#34;&gt;@lizmillerfit&lt;/a&gt; if you have any questions about my progress or my opinions about the program. Until next review&amp;hellip;Stay Fit. Stay Strong. &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:hi@queenflex.com&#34;&gt;-QFB.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>build muscle with stronglifts 5X5</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/build-muscle-stronglifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 23:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/build-muscle-stronglifts/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So typically I like to plan out my routines and schedule what, when, and why I&amp;rsquo;m training and eating a certain way. In this case; however, I decided to jump head-first into &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stronglifts.com/&#34;&gt;StrongLifts 5X5&lt;/a&gt; because, frankly, I&amp;rsquo;m tired of dancing around the bush with fitness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-2EtzjoI-4ro/VmuoW5hWaLI/AAAAAAAAAzM/04pZQJxEQFU/s1600/is%2Bit%2Bin%2Byou%253F%2523makeitcount-2.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next 12 weeks I will be training according to the StrongLifts 5X5 program and continuing to Eat To Perform. My 2016 goals include considerable strength gains, so to FINALLY meet these goals, I am going to give this 5X5 program a try. You can find my StrongLifts updates here. I will work in real-time so that you can see first-hand how good-bad-ugly this program ends up being. With that said, I am using this article to introduce the first Strategy in the #MAKEITCOUNT series.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;strategy-1-accountability-everyone-wants-to-say-they-did-it-without-actually-doing-it&#34;&gt;strategy #1 accountability: everyone wants to say they did it, without actually doing it.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be that person who commits to something and then fails to actually follow through with it. Now I understand some situations are circumstantial, but let&amp;rsquo;s face it, who likes excuses? Not me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So while I will be spending the early part of winter working on my strength with StrongLifts 5X5, what will you be doing? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s starting to workout for the first time in ten years; maybe your goal is to start flossing twice a day (dental hygiene is important); maybe you&amp;rsquo;re starting a new job and your goal is to save for retirement; whatever your 2016 goals are, you have to jump all in and go for them. Challenge yourself to do something every day to work towards your goal. 2% changes each day add up to major improvements over the course of weeks, months, and years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until Strategy #2&amp;hellip; #MAKEITCOUNT. Learn to become Accountable&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>