<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/healthy-eating/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/healthy-eating/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>healthy mini chicken pot pies</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/chicken-pot-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2015 12:00:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/chicken-pot-pies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of you craving this classic taste of Fall, and your macros don&amp;rsquo;t allow for the traditional chicken pot pie recipe, give this a try! For under 300 calories, you&amp;rsquo;ll get a tasty dose of this deliciously seasonal, healthy chicken pot pie made with fresh ingredients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuing with the Meal Prep Series, this week&amp;rsquo;s meal is Mini Chicken Pot Pies (adopted and modified from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fitnessmagazine.com/recipe/chicken/mini-chicken-pot-pies/&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; original recipe).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-byQuTHmmeKo/VgdRcPo_jzI/AAAAAAAAArY/ed78Y2tvwDo/s640/blogger-image-1255513652.jpg&#34; width=&#34;85%&#34; height=&#34;40%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;right&#34; src=&#34;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-ZUqU8qzH4Ak/VgdTQEErGHI/AAAAAAAAArs/rFrMx5S_OoA/s320/NutritionLabel.png&#34; hspace=&#34;20&#34; width=&#34;40%&#34; height=&#34;35%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;80g yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;70g celery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g baby carrots&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 cups Reduced-Sodium Chicken Broth (not all will be consumed; mainly used for cooking)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30g Bothouse Farms Italian Vinaigrette Dressing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 Grands Jr Golden Layer Buttermilk Biscuits&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 serving frozen veggies of your choice (I chose Kroger&amp;rsquo;s Recipe Secrets - Vegetable Soup, Mix)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16 oz Chicken Breast (Raw measure)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Italian Seasonings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Non-Stick, Fat-Free Cooking Spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garlic Powder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Large Pot&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 single-serve oven-safe bowls or ramekins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kitchen Scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Baking Rack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cutting board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sharp knife&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove on high and coat large pot with non-stick spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chop up onion, celery, and carrots. Mix with seasonings in the large pot. Cook until onions are browned.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce heat to medium. Add chicken broth and Italian Vinaigrette to large pot and let simmer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wash and prep chicken breast. Cut into smaller pieces and add to large pot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let simmer ~10 minutes or until the chicken is fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add frozen veggies. Cook until completely thawed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce stove to low heat. Remove chicken and add to a separate bowl. Shred if desired using a fork.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preheat oven to 400-deg F.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using the kitchen scale, find the total weight of chicken and divide by 4. This will be the serving size per mini chicken pie.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chicken and &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; of veggies to the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ~1-2 tbsp of broth to the bowls. Season with more garlic, black pepper, italian seasonings, if desired.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flatten and mold the 4 Grands Jr Biscuits to fit the top of each of the single-serve oven-safe bowls.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Coat the top of the biscuits with a small amount (~&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; tsp) of left over broth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle top of biscuits with more seasonings if desired. (I coated with some garlic powder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bake for 8-12 minutes or until the biscuits are fully cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool for 10 minutes and enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But wait …what do I do with the left over broth?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be left with ~90% of the chicken broth. Instead of throwing it out, I used it to cook the rest of my chicken as a part of my #MealPrepSunday. To do this, I added 3 raw chicken breasts and the chicken broth to a small crock pot and cooked on high for roughly 3 hours. Once the chicken was fully cooked, I removed it from the broth and shredded it down. I put 2 servings of chicken back into the crock pot with 2 servings of frozen veggies and 1 serving of tortellini to make a soup (YUM!). I let this cook for another 30-60 minutes on low heat. I packed up the remaining shredded chicken in a tupperware for use throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Have an idea for Meal of the Week? Comment below!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>healthy protein pancakes</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/protein-pancakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 22:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/protein-pancakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do you get hit with morning cravings for all the stuff you shouldn’t be eating? Try our take on a traditional McDonalds favorite, modified without the added fats, sugars, and unhealthiness. Tweet your recipes and modifications to this awesome breakfast sandwich!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup 100% Liquid Egg Whites&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 large whole Egg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50g Plain Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50g Vanilla Greek Yogurt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; cup Quaker Quick Oats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 pinch Stevia (optional)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2 pinches Ground Cinnamon (optional, but this really makes the dish tasty)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tools&#34;&gt;Tools:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Griddle/Stove Pan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nonstick cooking spray (fat free/cal free)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spatula&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ladle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;directions&#34;&gt;Directions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turn stove burner or griddle on high and coat with non-stick spray&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mix all of the dry ingredients together&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wisk &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup egg whites with the plain and vanilla Greek yogurts until the mixture is fluffy and smooth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Combine the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients. Be careful not to over-mix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a ladle to add the griddler mixture to the stove pan/griddle. Wait until bubbly and then flip to cook each side. (similar process to making pancakes)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pour remaining &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; cup of egg whites on the stove pan/griddle in a thin layer. Fry the whole egg as well. Flip once cooked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plate the griddlers and add a small layer of the egg whites/fried egg to the top&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add another griddler to the top to make a sandwich, or leave open-faced.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let cool and enjoy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;modifications&#34;&gt;Modifications:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use PB2 or peanut butter on the underside of each griddler as a condiment for the sandwich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add chopped nuts to the dry ingredients to add a crunchiness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve without the eggs as a stack of pancakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use all egg whites instead of adding in the whole egg.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Previously published on August 6, 2014 on SpotMeGirl.com&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>