<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>queenflex blog</title>
    <link>https://queenflex.github.io/tags/injury/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on queenflex blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://queenflex.github.io/tags/injury/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>turn your injury into an opportunity</title>
      <link>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 21:44:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://queenflex.github.io/post/injury-to-opportunity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; hspace=&#34;30&#34; src=&#34;http://spotmegirl.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/12/@physio_fit.png&#34; width=&#34;50%&#34; height=&#34;30%&#34;/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Injuries happen quite often in fitness and athletics in general–whether it is a minor case of the shin-splints or a broken bone, athletes are prone to getting hurt. Somehow it has become part of a vicious cycle; a known part of the game. But does it have to be this way? &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Over the past four years of my fit lifestyle I have managed to train my way through and around injuries. One of the key things I have learned is that many training-related injuries can be prevented. It all comes down to knowing your body and how it performs. There’s a difference between “cry-baby pain” and pain you should take seriously. Listening to your body is a true way to gauge this line. If your gut-instinct tells you to take a step back, then you should probably listen to it! Push through it, and you could miss more than a few reps or even steps in the long run!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay, so now you’re telling me to just stop training when the alarm sounds?&lt;/em&gt;
Actually, I’m suggesting an alternative method, selective training. If you feel shin-splints coming on and you need to perform HIIT as part of your training regime, then stop the treadmill work. Switch to HIIT on a rower or elliptical machine. Even better, use this opportunity to go outside and ride a bicycle. Be the badass on a bike performing 1 minute of hard-out pedaling and 30 seconds of leisurely, relaxed riding. Turn your injury into a chance to rest that body part. There are over 500 muscles in the human body; if one of them needs a break, then switch your attention to the other 499-plus muscles that need work. Read on for some more great tips to turning an injury into an opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;switch-to-body-weight-exercises&#34;&gt;Switch to Body-Weight Exercises&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel an injury coming on, switch to body weight exercises for a couple of days. This will reduce the stress placed on your body from lifting heavy. Plus, you will still get a great workout! Body-weight exercises allow you to concentrate on supporting your own weight through balance and endurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking for more of a challenge? Try completing 500 reps of common body-weight exercises such as planks, pullups, sit-ups, and push-ups with a 7 minute cutoff time for each. Trust me, it’s more difficult than it sounds! You could also try switching it up and do multiple rounds of tabata: 20 seconds of reps followed by 10 seconds of rest for a total of 4 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;alternative-cardio-training&#34;&gt;Alternative Cardio Training&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cardio doesn’t have to be about running, biking, or elliptical work. Use this opportunity to go for a long hike, try out rock climbing, or even pick up boxing. Challenge yourself by trying something new. Even kayaking can be a great cardio workout! Be creative and think about opportunities you can take part in rather than worry about opportunities you’re missing out on due to an injury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rehab-and-stretch&#34;&gt;Rehab and Stretch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many times athletes get injured, go to physical therapy, finish up the sessions and then stop doing the exercises. I’ll admit, I’m not as proactive when it comes to doing the stretching and prep work before a workout. If you are given exercises by a physical therapist, be sure to do them! Stretching is a great way to prepare your body for the stresses of lifting. It promotes oxygen flow to the muscles and will help loosen you up beforehand. Use this time to throw in your favorite playlist and get pumped for the workout!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;shoulder-related-injury&#34;&gt;Shoulder-related Injury?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No problem. After a few rounds of surgery to remove a bone mass between my scapula and rib cage, I’ve become more aware of alternative shoulder and upper body exercises. Typically when I’m working shoulders and chest I will modify the flat bench press to an incline press just so that my shoulders aren’t under so much stress. I still get the added benefit of a dumbbell or barbell press just without the added tension. If you have another sensitive area from previous injuries, modified exercises always help and can get you on track to where you want to be without stopping a plan entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ice-down-and-heat-up&#34;&gt;Ice Down and Heat Up!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use this recovery period as an excuse to relax with a heating pad or ice pack. Whether you like ice or heat, just relaxing after your workout with one or the other can help your muscles start to recover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I know that sometimes injuries are much more complex than a little case of the shin-splints. In complex injuries, you need to use your best judgement. Don’t push yourself to the point where you’re physically disintegrating. You’re training with a purpose. You want to become a better, more polished version of yourself. So instead of dropping all fitness entirely when an injury strikes, strike back and play smart. If upper body is injured, work legs. Go for a jog. Keep up your cardio. Do some active stretching and rehabilitation exercises. Be mindful of yourself and your goals, and take the time to turn your injury into an opportunity for future prevention and a successful recovery. Fitness is probably the greatest game composed of lifting, nutrition, and competition. Take care of yourself by doing the recommended stretches in preparation for your training routine. Your body will thank you for it afterwards!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt; &lt;em&gt;Previously published on December 3, 2014 on SpotMeGirl.com&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>